<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Language>
	<Item ID="1">
		<Name>&lt;info&gt;</Name>
		<Desc>IDs for classes (rule):

weapons = 100...299

arrows = 300...399

clothes = 400...599

scrolls = 600..799

potions = 800...899

amulets = 900...999

cloaks = 1000...1099

helmets = 1100...1299

rings = 1300...1399

ore = 1400...1499

tools = 1500...1599

modules = 1600...1699

shields = 1700...1799

ingredients = 1800...1999

gems and luxury = 2000... 2099

quest items = 2100... 2399

keys = 2400... 2499</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="100">
		<Name>ジャンビャ</Name>
		<Desc>A curved Scythian "honor" dagger. Once an oddity, the jambia became a common weapon of many street gangs, which had flourished after the fall of the Empire.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="101">
		<Name>Sefet</Name>
		<Desc>A simple, straight Kemetian dagger favored by those who care less about style than the ease with which the sefet slips between an enemy's ribs.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="102">
		<Name>Pugio</Name>
		<Desc>A traditional Imperial wide-bladed dagger. Originally a digging and back-up stabbing weapon of the legions, the pugio quickly became a popular choice among both respectable citizens and street thugs.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="103">
		<Name>Khanjar</Name>
		<Desc>A long, serpentine dagger from the Avagan Steppes. The wavy blade has a reputation for inflicting devastating wounds, but it is the length that makes the khanjar deadly.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="104">
		<Name>Yatagan</Name>
		<Desc>A single-edged, recurved Turuk long blade. The recurved design has been ignored by the Empire's swordsmen, but was welcomed by knife fighters, who adopted the Yatagan as a deadly and effective long dagger.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="110">
		<Name>Gladius</Name>
		<Desc>A double-edged short sword designed for thrusting and slashing in close quarters. Favoured by the Imperial Guard, the gladius is a common sight throughout the remnants of the Empire.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="111">
		<Name>Khopesh</Name>
		<Desc>A sickle sword of Kemetian origin. The khopesh evolved from the crescent-bladed axe, resulting in a versatile double-edged weapon that may surprise even seasoned opponents.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="112">
		<Name>Handar</Name>
		<Desc>A heavy, double-edged Bactrian broadsword with a wide, triangular blade. The handar is one of the most powerful one-handed weapons, built for slow, but devastating attacks.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="113">
		<Name>Shamshir</Name>
		<Desc>A single-edged, deeply curved sword with a slim blade. While the shamshir is more suitable for cutting and slashing attacks, it's more than capable of delivering rising, descending, and hooking thrusts.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="114">
		<Name>Scimitar</Name>
		<Desc>A two-handed, heavy Ashkaanian sword with an oversized, curved, single-edged blade designed to mow through anything that stands in front of you. The weight adds impressive power to the strike, but makes the sword more difficult to control.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="120">
		<Name>Zaghnal</Name>
		<Desc>An elaborately decorated Scythian fighting axe with a crow's beak-shaped blade designed for greater armor penetration. Innumerable skirmishes between the legions and the desert tribes ensured a steady supply of Scythian weaponry.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="121">
		<Name>Skeggox</Name>
		<Desc>A deadly bearded axe, introduced to the protectorates of the former Empire by Skanian raiders. The skeggox's unusual blade provides an ample surface for slashing, while keeping the weight low.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="122">
		<Name>Mineb</Name>
		<Desc>The unusual Kemetian one handed axe known as the mineb reflects a different school of weapon design. Over the centuries, many of these ornately decorated, gold-encrusted axes were brought from Kemet as gifts. Now they are to be found all over the Empire.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="123">
		<Name>Shadhavar</Name>
		<Desc>A two-handed Scythian axe whose design was inspired by the mythical death-bringing horned gazelle. The shadhavar is a rare, beautiful, and effective weapon with a gracefully curved cutting surface, augmented by deadly spearpoints.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="124">
		<Name>Labrys</Name>
		<Desc>A heavy two-handed Minoan axe. For the Minoans, the labrys was a religious and ceremonial symbol, but the Empire turned it to more practical applications as a devastating battlefield weapon.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="125">
		<Name>Pickaxe</Name>
		<Desc>A miner's tool that can easily double up as a weapon.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="130">
		<Name>Marculus</Name>
		<Desc>A small, one-handed smith's hammer. Typically used for shaping heated metal, it also does a fine job breaking skulls and other fragile objects.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="131">
		<Name>Mallet</Name>
		<Desc>Originally a multipurpose work hammer, this wooden hammer was adapted for warfare and reinforced with metal rings and striking surfaces. Due to its lighter weight, the mallet can be efficiently wielded in one hand.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="132">
		<Name>Spiked club</Name>
		<Desc>The club is thought by many loremasters to be the earliest weapon used by man. This evolution of the humble club features a long metal head bristling with two-inch spikes.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="133">
		<Name>War hammer</Name>
		<Desc>A brutal Skanian two-handed hammer. The Skanians designed the war hammer in response to hard lessons at the hands of the Imperial Legions, who taught the raiders to respect and fear armored opponents.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="134">
		<Name>Sledgehammer</Name>
		<Desc>A heavy, two-handed hammer with a massive head. Not a weapon for those who prefer subtlety or finesse, the sledgehammer is brutally effective for its purpose. The chiseled ram's head design points to Kemetian origin.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="135">
		<Name>Wooden Stick</Name>
		<Desc>A tree branch that can be easily used as a makeshift weapon.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="140">
		<Name>Hasta</Name>
		<Desc>A standard issue Imperial short spear with a broad triangular blade. The hasta can be carried in one hand and used with a shield.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="141">
		<Name>Dori</Name>
		<Desc>A spear favored by the hoplitai for its light weight and versatility. The leaf-shaped head can be used for thrusting or slashing. The Dori is too heavy to use single-handed.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="142">
		<Name>Romach</Name>
		<Desc>A long Thracian spear with a blade designed for use against lightly armored infantry and cavalry. The heavy shaft requires two hands to wield effectively.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="143">
		<Name>Krokspar</Name>
		<Desc>Literally "barbed spear", the Krokspar is a long-shafted weapon of Skanian design with a dagger-like head a cross piece for blocking. The Krokspar is too heavy to use single-handed.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="144">
		<Name>Trident</Name>
		<Desc>A three pronged spear with a long shaft, reminiscent of a pitchfork. The trident is scorned by most fighting men, but is a favored weapon of enraged farmers and retiarii gladiators.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="145">
		<Name>Shovel</Name>
		<Desc>A wooden shovel with an iron edge. It's a tool first and foremost, but it can still crack a skull in case of emergency.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="150">
		<Name>Short Bow</Name>
		<Desc>A simple bow fashioned from a single piece of elm wood, this weapon lacks power and range, but is quick to shoot and has a low draw weight. It's suitable for small game, animal and otherwise.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="151">
		<Name>Recurved Ordu Bow</Name>
		<Desc>A short, composite birch bow reinforced with deer horn. The ordu bow is as much a part of the nomads' culture as the horse, and since it takes almost a year to craft a single one, it is never traded, only recovered from dead riders.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="152">
		<Name>Kemetian Bow</Name>
		<Desc>A medium-draw bow used by Kemetian charioteers to deadly effect. Unlike most of its brethren, this bow is constructed entirely from horn, and bound to an acacia wood section in the center.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="153">
		<Name>Recurved Scythian Bow</Name>
		<Desc>This long and powerful Scythian bow, famous for its incurvation, is distinguished by the triangular center section and smoothly recurved tips.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="154">
		<Name>Long Bow</Name>
		<Desc>One of the most powerful bows, the longbow is fashioned from a single length of yew wood. The longbow's power is limited only by the strength of the archer, and in the right hands can punch holes through even plate armor.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="160">
		<Name>Hand Crossbow</Name>
		<Desc>A small, handheld crossbow, invented by Medean loremasters renown for their clever gadgetry. Although its reduced size also diminishes its power and accuracy, many folks who make their livings in dark alleys think it's a great conversation starter.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="161">
		<Name>Standard Crossbow</Name>
		<Desc>A standard Imperial crossbow, combining basic single-shot design and reliability. These weapons were mass produced during the final years of the War, transforming untrained peasants into a deadly force.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="162">
		<Name>Repeating Crossbow</Name>
		<Desc>A mechanical Zhin crossbow whose complicated assembly allows the user to fire several missiles in succession. Neither accurate nor powerful, the repeater is prized for its ability to fire bolts at an unbelievably high rate.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="163">
		<Name>Double Crossbow</Name>
		<Desc>A rare example of the double-shot crossbow, an unusual design featuring two vertical bows. The bows have separate triggers, allowing the wielder to shoot twice before reloading.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="164">
		<Name>Heavy Crossbow</Name>
		<Desc>Used mainly as a siege weapon in the Great War, this weapon has a reinforced metal bow, granting extra power and penetration, but takes longer to arm. This crossbow is capable of penetrating any armor.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="165">
		<Name>Scoped Standard Crossbow</Name>
		<Desc>A standard Imperial crossbow, combining basic single-shot design and reliability. These weapons were mass produced during the final years of the War, transforming untrained peasants into a deadly force.

The scope increases the range by two tiles and adds a special Snipe attack.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="166">
		<Name>Scoped Heavy Crossbow</Name>
		<Desc>Used mainly as a siege weapon in the Great War, this weapon has a reinforced metal bow, granting extra power and penetration, but takes longer to arm. This crossbow is capable of penetrating any armor.

The scope increases the range by two tiles and adds a special Snipe attack.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="170">
		<Name>Karda</Name>
		<Desc>A double-edged Scythian throwing knife forged from a single piece of metal. Carefully balanced, this knife is accurate enough for the thrower to target joints in armor and other weak spots in your enemy's defence.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="171">
		<Name>Plumbata</Name>
		<Desc>A heavy dart with a lead (plumbum) ball on the wooden shaft to increase power and penetration. The plumbata was once a standard part of the legionnaire’s arsenal, carried within the hollow of the shield.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="172">
		<Name>Chakram</Name>
		<Desc>An exotic Sindhu throwing ring with a bladed outer edge, flat bottom, and asymmetric curved top, which ensures an accurate and stable flight with a high spin rate.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="173">
		<Name>Handox</Name>
		<Desc>A Skanian throwing axe designed for speed and penetration at close range. Skanian raiders are trained to throw these axes in volleys, wreaking havoc among enemy lines.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="174">
		<Name>Pilum</Name>
		<Desc>A tip-heavy javelin carried by legionnaires, the pilum has an iron head mounted on a wooden shaft. The pilum will penetrate enemy shields with ease, and can even be effective against heavy armor.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="175">
		<Name>Net</Name>
		<Desc>A round, wide-meshed cast net with lead weights around the edges. A successful throw will entangle the opponent for 1 turn, significantly reducing his combat abilities.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="179">
		<Name>Stone</Name>
		<Desc>A small stone suitable for throwing.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="180">
		<Name>Bolas</Name>
		<Desc>A weapon consisting of two heavy balls secured to the ends of a strong rope, hurled to entangle the legs of cattle and other animals. It works even better on two legged animals and can be thrown to entangle legs or choke.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="300">
		<Name>Regular Missile</Name>
		<Desc>Standard ammunition for bows and crossbows. While it can't match the penetration power of armor-piercing bolts or brutality of barbed arrows, regular ammo is non-discriminating and will leave a mark everywhere.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="301">
		<Name>Armor Piercing Missile</Name>
		<Desc>With narrow, dagger-like heads, these bolts and arrows will punch through the heaviest armor, but won't cause significant critical damage to the target.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="302">
		<Name>Barbed Missile</Name>
		<Desc>Designed to shred flesh, the wicked barbs on these arrows and bolts cause devastating critical damage but have very poor armor penetration.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="400">
		<Name>Leather Armor</Name>
		<Desc>Light leather tunic crafted from hardened, boiled leather. It's not designed to stop heavy blows, but it won't slow you down either.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="401">
		<Name>Reinforced Leather Armor</Name>
		<Desc>Leather tunic crafted from hardened, boiled leather and reinforced with metal to improve penetration resistance. It's not designed to stop heavy blows, but it won't slow you down either.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="402">
		<Name>Leather Barbari Armor</Name>
		<Desc>Light leather armor of the southern nomadic tribes, featuring near complete range of motion for the wearer. The term "Barbari" refers to any sort of primitive hailing from "Barbaricum", meaning anywhere outside the Empire.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="403">
		<Name>Studded Barbari Armor</Name>
		<Desc>A minor improvement on the plain leather armor of the southern nomadic tribes.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="404">
		<Name>Silk Ordu Armor</Name>
		<Desc>A light male tunic consisting of several layers of densely-woven Zhin silk. This armor offers some protection from glancing blows and arrows, and will plug wounds and protect flesh from tearing.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="405">
		<Name>Silk Ordu Armor</Name>
		<Desc>A light female tunic consisting of several layers of densely-woven Zhin silk. This armor offers some protection from glancing blows and arrows, and will plug wounds and protect flesh from tearing.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="406">
		<Name>Leather Numeri Armor</Name>
		<Desc>Light leather armor once worn by the Numeri, irregular peasant troops recruited en masse during the War. The Numeri were drawn from ill-equipped provincial militia and impoverished immigrants hoping to buy citizenship with their blood.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="407">
		<Name>Studded Numeri Armor</Name>
		<Desc>The leather armor of the Numeri augmented with metal studs by someone willing to part with a few silver coins.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="408">
		<Name>Manica</Name>
		<Desc>A segmented metal armguard lined with calfskin. Introduced by slow, fully-armored crupellarii, the manica became popular with fighters who preferred mobility and speed, wearing heavy protection on the weapon arm only.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="409">
		<Name>Auxiliary Armor</Name>
		<Desc>Light leather armor with a metal shoulder guard. During the War, lightly armored auxiliary troops provided support to the Imperial Legions. When the Empire fell, surviving units formed mercenary companies whose only master was gold.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="410">
		<Name>Phrygian Armor</Name>
		<Desc>High quality leather armor crafted from overlapping upwards rows of lacquered pieces of hardened leather, laced together with silk thread.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="411">
		<Name>Leather Ordu Armor</Name>
		<Desc>Leather armor of the Ordu warriors, worn with a silk undershirt. While the Empire emphasized brute force and heavy defence, the Ordu favored swiftness, and discovered new ways to reinforce leather without losing mobility.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="412">
		<Name>Studded Ordu Armor</Name>
		<Desc>Leather Ordu armor, reinforced with studs and worn with a silk undershirt. While the Empire emphasized brute force and heavy defence, the Ordu favored swiftness, and discovered new ways to reinforce leather without losing mobility.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="413">
		<Name>Lorica Segmentata</Name>
		<Desc>Segmented armor comprised of overlapping metal strips fastened to leather straps. Simple and inexpensive, this standard armor of the Legions was an unofficial symbol of the Empire, recognized and feared everywhere.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="414">
		<Name>Lorica Musculata</Name>
		<Desc>A stylized cuirass in the form of a muscled human torso, this was the preferred armor among officers and senators of the Empire.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="415">
		<Name>Praetorian Armor</Name>
		<Desc>Heavy, elaborately decorated metal armor of the Praetorian Guard. At the height of the Empire, the Praetorians were the hand-picked protectors of the Emperor and his generals. The Praetorians have since shifted their loyalty to the Noble Houses.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="416">
		<Name>Lamellar Ordu Armor</Name>
		<Desc>Heavy Ordu armor made from parallel rows of metal lamellae laced together with silk threads. Ordu lamellar armor is significantly superior to chain mail, yet it's much lighter and less restrictive.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="417">
		<Name>Imperial Armor</Name>
		<Desc>Heavy armor of the elite Legio XIII Ferrata, meaning Ironclad. This armor provides superior protection, but greatly limited mobility, a potentially fatal drawback for solo fighters.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="420">
		<Name>Daratan Lorica Segmentata</Name>
		<Desc>Segmented armor comprised of overlapping metal strips fastened to leather straps. Simple and inexpensive, this standard armor of the Legions was an unofficial symbol of the Empire, recognized and feared everywhere.

This particular armor bears the sign of the Noble House Daratan.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="421">
		<Name>Daratan Praetorian Armor</Name>
		<Desc>Heavy, elaborately decorated metal armor of the Praetorian Guard. At the height of the Empire, the Praetorians were the hand-picked protectors of the Emperor and his generals. The Praetorians have since shifted their loyalty to the Noble Houses.

This particular armor bears the sign of the Noble House Daratan.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="422">
		<Name>Raider Armor</Name>
		<Desc>Light leather armor with a metal shoulder guard. During the War, lightly armored auxiliary troops provided support to the Imperial Legions. When the Empire fell, surviving units formed mercenary companies whose only master was gold.

This particular armor belonged to some raider.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="423">
		<Name>Imperial Guards Lorica Segmentata</Name>
		<Desc>Segmented armor comprised of overlapping metal strips fastened to leather straps. Simple and inexpensive, this standard armor of the Legions was an unofficial symbol of the Empire, recognized and feared everywhere. 

This particular armor bears the eagle of the Imperial Guards.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="424">
		<Name>Imperial Guards Imperial Armor</Name>
		<Desc>Heavy armor of the elite Legio XIII Ferrata, meaning Ironclad. This armor provides superior protection, but greatly limited mobility, a potentially fatal drawback for solo fighters. 

This particular armor bears the eagle of the Imperial Guards.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="500">
		<Name>Tunic</Name>
		<Desc>The tunic is a comfortable and loose fitting garment, knee-length and sleeveless. It is commonly worn by tradesmen and the middle classes.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="501">
		<Name>Light Tunic</Name>
		<Desc>A lighter version of the tunic, suitable for wearing indoors and in warm weather.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="502">
		<Name>Toga</Name>
		<Desc>A traditional wool garment of the Empire, the toga is basically a length of cloth cleverly draped about the shoulders and waist.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="503">
		<Name>Long Toga</Name>
		<Desc>A longer version of the traditional wool garment of the Empire.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="504">
		<Name>Slave Garb</Name>
		<Desc>The garb of slaves and indentured laborers, consisting of a skirt and shoulder strap. This minimal covering prevents the wearer from concealing weapons or contraband stolen from mines and warehouses.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="505">
		<Name>Expensive Long Robe</Name>
		<Desc>A long, cloth-of-gold trimmed outer garment, worn by those who wish to impress.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="506">
		<Name>Expensive Robe</Name>
		<Desc>A cloth-of-gold trimmed outer garment, for those of more discerning tastes.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="507">
		<Name>Long Robe</Name>
		<Desc>A loose-fitting, short-sleeved garment, usually worn over underclothes.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="508">
		<Name>Short Robe</Name>
		<Desc>A loose-fitting outer garment.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="509">
		<Name>Noble Clothes</Name>
		<Desc>The collar and epaulettes of this richly decorated attire reveal the wearer to be a lord of the realm, allowing the less fortunate to instantly recognize his importance and power.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="510">
		<Name>Noble Dress</Name>
		<Desc>The fine cloth and masterful tailoring of this garment leaves the hapless peon no doubt of the lady wearer's noble birth. Flaunt your wealth and prestige, but remember to accept the obeisance of your many inferiors with grace.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="511">
		<Name>Odalisque's Garb</Name>
		<Desc>The elaborately embroidered robes of the odalisque are designed to reveal rather than conceal the flesh beneath. Not for a woman looking to avoid attention.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="512">
		<Name>Desert Garments</Name>
		<Desc>The Scythian sleeveless tunic, belted and usually worn with a robe, reflects the desert nomad’s virtue of versatility in all his habits and trappings.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="513">
		<Name>Loremaster's Garments</Name>
		<Desc>The traditional Ashkaanian kaftan, worn with a sash, is designed for the desert expeditions so popular with loremasters. It shields the wearer from the sun during the day and warms him during the bitter desert nights.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="514">
		<Name>Merchant Robe</Name>
		<Desc>A long, cloth-of-gold trimmed outer garment, worn by those who wish to impress.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="515">
		<Name>Dirty Tunic</Name>
		<Desc>The tunic is a comfortable and loose fitting garment, knee-length and sleeveless. Poor people seldom wash it.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="900">
		<Name>The Eye of Thor-Agoth</Name>
		<Desc>A large, round, tri color crystal framed in gold. The center of the crystal is completely black, making it look like an eye.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="901">
		<Name>Prospector's Amulet</Name>
		<Desc>Adorned with beads and engraved with runes, it appears to be a ceremonial bowl of some sort. Strangely warped, but that isn't unusual for artefacts of the Old Empire - who knows what arcane forces had been unleashed on it? Two small, metal drums are affixed to the underside, too awkwardly angled to be supports for the bowl. Reservoirs, perhaps, containers of sacred liquid for the bowl?</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="902">
		<Name>Respirator</Name>
		<Desc>A breathing apparatus of the Old Empire. When charged with magical energies, it will allow you to breath in toxic environments. 

A valuable artefact, it's been handed down the generations from father to son. The magic powering up the device eventually ran out and the purpose was lost. All that was remembered is that it was a powerful charm protecting its wearer from unseen danger.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1000">
		<Name>Simple cape</Name>
		<Desc>A simple cape favored by people who can't afford finer things in life.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1050">
		<Name>Raider Cape</Name>
		<Desc>A long outer garment designed to protect against the weather and identify the cape's wearer as a member of a specific faction or an order, if a cape bears a clearly recognizable insignia.

This particular cape belonged to some raider.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1051">
		<Name>Imperial Guards Cape</Name>
		<Desc>A long outer garment designed to protect against the weather and identify the cape's wearer as a member of the Imperial Guards.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1100">
		<Name>Hood</Name>
		<Desc>Originally designed to protect the face during sandstorms, hoods later became popular among those wishing to conceal their identity, such as thieves and assassins.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1101">
		<Name>Leather Barbari Helmet</Name>
		<Desc>Basic leather headgear adorned with bull's horns. Among the barbarians this type of helmet is worn only by the bull killer himself.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1102">
		<Name>Heavy Barbari Helmet</Name>
		<Desc>Strike fear into primitive foes with this heavy leather helmet adorned with a bull's horns!</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1103">
		<Name>Silk Ordu Helmet</Name>
		<Desc>A common male silk hat of the Ordu, good for keeping the sun off and your hair in place.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1104">
		<Name>Silk Ordu Helmet</Name>
		<Desc>A common female silk hat of the Ordu, good for keeping the sun off and your hair in place.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1105">
		<Name>Leather Numeri Helmet</Name>
		<Desc>The Numeri were not known for the quality of their gear, but this leather helmet comes with a decorative spike on top.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1106">
		<Name>Heavy Numeri Helmet</Name>
		<Desc>A heavy leather version of the Numeri helmet, topped with a fanciful metal spike.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1107">
		<Name>Murmillo Helmet</Name>
		<Desc>A full helmet commonly used by murmillo gladiators, sporting a high angular crest and a broad curved brim. Vision is somewhat impaired by its full facial visor, penetrated by narrow gratings for the eyes.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1108">
		<Name>Auxiliary Helmet</Name>
		<Desc>A serious helmet for the fighter unconcerned with decorations and ceremonies, the Auxiliary helmet is reinforced with a metal ridge along the cranium for extra protection against overhead strikes.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1109">
		<Name>Phrygian Helmet</Name>
		<Desc>A very unusual piece of headgear, this helmet sports a high, conical peak resembling a common peasant hat, and a next-to-full facemask offering a combination of defense and relatively unimpaired vision.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1110">
		<Name>Leather Ordu Helmet</Name>
		<Desc>The distinctive male conical leather helmet of the Ordu, with neckguard. Beware, lest you be mistaken for an Ordu at a distance.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1111">
		<Name>Leather Ordu Helmet</Name>
		<Desc>The distinctive female conical leather helmet of the Ordu, with neckguard. Beware, lest you be mistaken for an Ordu at a distance.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1112">
		<Name>Studded Ordu Helmet</Name>
		<Desc>A heavier version of male leather Ordu hat.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1113">
		<Name>Studded Ordu Helmet</Name>
		<Desc>A heavier version of female leather Ordu hat.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1114">
		<Name>Legionnaire helmet</Name>
		<Desc>The standard helmet of the Imperial Legions offers basic protection and cheek guards. The face is open, allowing for maximal field of view.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1115">
		<Name>Attic Helmet</Name>
		<Desc>A full metal helmet with cheek and nose guards and a front-to-back horsehair crest.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1116">
		<Name>Centurion Helmet</Name>
		<Desc>Traditional centurion helmet with a distinctive, transverse horsehair crest -crista transversa- which allowed legionnaries to recognize centurions in the chaos of battle.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1117">
		<Name>Praetorian Helmet</Name>
		<Desc>Traditional helmet of the Praetorian guards with a distinctive reinforced fore-guard and a front-to-back decorative crest.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1119">
		<Name>Lamellar Ordu Helmet</Name>
		<Desc>A metal Ordu helmet.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1120">
		<Name>Imperial Helmet</Name>
		<Desc>The heavy helmet of the Imperial Guards, with nose and cheek guards and the unmistakable double horsehair crest.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1121">
		<Name>Open Hood</Name>
		<Desc>Originally designed to protect the face during sandstorms, hoods later became popular among those wishing to conceal their identity, such as thieves and assassins.

This version shows the face of the character (like Varro's pic).</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1200">
		<Name>Simple Turban</Name>
		<Desc>A simple linen head wrap. Originally worn by desert folk to protect against the harsh sun and constantly blowing sand, the turban’s use spread after the War, which turned many green plains into scorched and dusty wasteland.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1201">
		<Name>Simple Hood</Name>
		<Desc>An unadorned cloth covering for the head and neck worn by many women.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1202">
		<Name>Expensive Turban</Name>
		<Desc>The turban is a linen head wrap originally worn by desert folk to protect against sun and sand. This fancier version was adopted by wealthier folk, who are never content to clothe themselves in merely functional garb.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1203">
		<Name>Expensive Hood</Name>
		<Desc>A cloth covering for the head and neck. The expensive hood of a woman of means is distinguished by its softer material and cloth-of-gold lining.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1204">
		<Name>Noble's Turban</Name>
		<Desc>A long silken cloth wound around a richly decorated cap, the noble's turban is a decorated descendant of the original head wrap used by desert folk to protect against the harsh sun and constantly blowing sand.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1205">
		<Name>Odalisque Headdress</Name>
		<Desc>An elaborately decorated and veiled silk headdress.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1206">
		<Name>Loremaster's Turban</Name>
		<Desc>A simple linen head wrap originally worn by desert folk to protect against the harsh sun and constantly blowing sand. Loremasters, who are often to be found in the desert hunting for artefacts, were the first in the Empire to adopt the turban.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1207">
		<Name>Loremaster's Hood</Name>
		<Desc>A traditional headdress favored by women. For some, covering the hair is a sign of virtue or piety.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1208">
		<Name>Iskefe</Name>
		<Desc>A simple hat in the shape of a truncated cone.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1300">
		<Name>Gold Ring</Name>
		<Desc>A gold ring.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1310">
		<Name>Ruby Ring</Name>
		<Desc>A gold ring with a small ruby.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1330">
		<Name>Daratan Ring</Name>
		<Desc>A ring with the House Daratan insignia.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1350">
		<Name>Galbo's Ring</Name>
		<Desc>It's the famous magic ring of General Galbo, forged and enchanted by the Council of Magi to make the general unstoppable in battle. After the general's untimely death, the ring was thought to be lost and hasn't been seen for centuries.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1400">
		<Name>Metal</Name>
		<Desc>A mass of metal cast in a convenient form for shaping, remelting, or refining.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1401">
		<Name>Leather</Name>
		<Desc>Cured, soaked, scrabbed, and tanned animal hide.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1402">
		<Name>Lumber</Name>
		<Desc>Good quality wood, ready for use.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1403">
		<Name>Cloth</Name>
		<Desc>A fabric formed by weaving, felting, or knitting, that can be used for a number of purposes.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1600">
		<Name>Module</Name>
		<Desc>It's a small glass tube encased in elaborate metal framework. The tube is very warm to touch and contains what appears to be constantly shifting liquid fire.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1700">
		<Name>Buckler</Name>
		<Desc>The smallest shield, favored by quick fighters. It has a convex shape designed to ward off blows. Due to its small size, the buckler is useless in unskilled hands.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1701">
		<Name>Cavalry shield</Name>
		<Desc>A medium-weight oval shield mostly used by cavalry and auxiliary troops. Oval shields could be found everywhere, from Kemet to Ashkaan. They offer good defence and reasonable mobility.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1702">
		<Name>Infantry shield</Name>
		<Desc>A larger, rectangular shield with a slightly curved profile, this piece was designed for slowly advancing legionnaires who would utilize group defensive formations like the famous 'turtle'. It may be less useful to a lone fighter.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1703">
		<Name>Tower Shield</Name>
		<Desc>A heavy rectangular shield with a slightly curved profile, the tower shield provides unparalleled protection for a stationary unit, but is cumbersome and unwieldy, severely taxing its owner's mobility and response time.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2000">
		<Name>Diamond</Name>
		<Desc>A well-cut diamond.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2001">
		<Name>Emerald</Name>
		<Desc>A well-cut emerald.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2002">
		<Name>Ruby</Name>
		<Desc>A well-cut ruby.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2003">
		<Name>Sapphire</Name>
		<Desc>A well-cut sapphire.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2004">
		<Name>Topaz</Name>
		<Desc>A well-cut topaz.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2005">
		<Name>Grey stone</Name>
		<Desc>It's a large, grey stone. You've definitely seen more interesting specimens.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2006">
		<Name>Lodestone</Name>
		<Desc>It's a lodestone. A natural magnet. Interesting.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2100">
		<Name>Gracius' Map</Name>
		<Desc>It's an ancient map you acquired from Gracius, who probably doesn't need it anymore.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2105">
		<Name>Astrolabe</Name>
		<Desc>A fascinating divination device that can determine the altitude of the celestial bodies as well as latitude and longitude.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2110">
		<Name>Grooved sphere</Name>
		<Desc>A small, metal sphere with grooves running around it.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2115">
		<Name>Climbing hook</Name>
		<Desc>It's a handy tool for climbing enthusiasts.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2120">
		<Name>Rope</Name>
		<Desc>Several coils of rope.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2125">
		<Name>Rope with grappling hook</Name>
		<Desc>A grappling hook with a length of rope attached.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2130">
		<Name>Wine Amphora</Name>
		<Desc>An amphora full of wine.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2131">
		<Name>Wine Amphora (poisoned)</Name>
		<Desc>An amphora with poisoned wine.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2140">
		<Name>Imperial Guards' Writ</Name>
		<Desc>A rather pompously written 'cease and desist until further notice' document.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2145">
		<Name>Imperial Guards' Mandate</Name>
		<Desc>An official decree granting the Imperial Guards the right of free passage and ordering full cooperation from all Teron guilds and citizens.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2146">
		<Name>Imperial Guards' Mandate (fake)</Name>
		<Desc>A forgery of an official decree granting the Imperial Guards the right of free passage.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2150">
		<Name>Antique Golden Goblet</Name>
		<Desc>An antique golden goblet, decorated with gems.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2160">
		<Name>The "Jellyfish" Artefact</Name>
		<Desc>A crystal semi-sphere, encased in a metal dome. Thin metal rods of varying lengths protrude from the bottom, reminding you of a jellyfish. The crystal, despite its centuries buried under brick and stagnant water, glows with a pure, blue light.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="10501">
		<Name>Gold</Name>
		<Desc>Gold coins stamped with the visages of emperors of varying antiquity.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="10502">
		<Name>Fists</Name>
		<Desc>Fists of fury.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="801">
		<Name>Healing Salve</Name>
		<Desc>A medical ointment that's used to heal wounds. The effect is instant.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Restores hit points outside of combat, via right-clicking.
&lt;br&gt;- Stops bleeding in combat, accessible via belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="802">
		<Name>Restorative Liniment</Name>
		<Desc>A medical ointment that's used to heal bruises and swellings.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Heals damage to attributes, via right-clicking.
&lt;br&gt;- Can't be used in combat.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="803">
		<Name>Regeneration Potion</Name>
		<Desc>This potion stops all natural healing processes in your body, thus weakening it, and replaces them with an alchemical system, which attempts to close wounds the moment they are recieved. The effect is permanent and irreversible.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="804">
		<Name>Berserk Potion</Name>
		<Desc>A special draught that will fill you with rage and bloodlust. You will hit harder, but your aim will suffer. The effect lasts 3 turns.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Place in a belt slot to use in combat.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="805">
		<Name>Berserk Potion (Extended)</Name>
		<Desc>A special draught that fills you with rage and bloodlust. The rage will make you hit harder but your aim will suffer. The effect lasts longer than 3 turns.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Place in a belt slot to use in combat.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="806">
		<Name>Berserk Potion (Hemostasis)</Name>
		<Desc>A special draught that fills you with rage and bloodlust. The effect lasts 3 turns and increases your natural resistance to damage. Once the effect wears off, your wounds will reopen, resulting in some blood loss.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Place in a belt slot to use in combat.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="807">
		<Name>Neurostimulant</Name>
		<Desc>A potent elixir that will speed up your reflexes and reaction in combat for a short time.

Increases max AP for 2 turns.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Place in a belt slot to use in combat.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="808">
		<Name>Neurostimulant (Extended)</Name>
		<Desc>A potent elixir that will speed up your reflexes and reaction in combat for a time. 

Increases max AP for up to 4 turns.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Place in a belt slot to use in combat.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="809">
		<Name>Neurostimulant (Eagle Eye)</Name>
		<Desc>A potent elixir that will speed up your reflexes in combat and enhance your vision for a short time. 

Increases max AP for 2 turns and increases THC.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Place in a belt slot to use in combat.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="810">
		<Name>Poison Vial</Name>
		<Desc>Natural poison - good for coating your weapons and other nefarious purposes. 

After 20 successful strikes, the poison will be washed away by blood. Its effects last 3 turns, starting with the next turn after the attack. The damage can be reduced by the victim's Constitution.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Drag and drop on a weapon or a missiles to apply the effect.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="811">
		<Name>Antidote</Name>
		<Desc>An antidote for poison - don't leave home without one. The antidote strengthens your body's resistance to poison, reducing or even negating its effects.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Place in a belt slot to use in combat.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="812">
		<Name>Poison Vial (Potent)</Name>
		<Desc>Natural, very potent poison - good for coating your weapons and other nefarious purposes. 

After 20 successful strikes, the poison will be washed away by blood. Its effects last 5 turns, starting with the next turn after the attack. The damage can be reduced by the victim's Constitution.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Drag and drop on a weapon or a missiles to apply the effect.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="190">
		<Name>Acid Vial</Name>
		<Desc>A small flask filled with acid. When thrown, it will burn through any armor (provided the acid is strong enough), gradually reducing its damage resistance, until there is nothing left.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="191">
		<Name>Acid Vial (Strong)</Name>
		<Desc>A small flask filled with a very potent acid. When thrown, it will burn through any armor (provided the acid is strong enough), gradually reducing its damage resistance, until there is nothing left.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="192">
		<Name>Acid Vial (Splash)</Name>
		<Desc>A small flask filled with acid. When thrown, it will burn through flesh and any armor (provided the acid is strong enough), gradually reducing its damage resistance, until there is nothing left.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="200">
		<Name>Liquid Fire Vial</Name>
		<Desc>A small flask with liquid fire. When thrown, it will "fall like a fiery whirlwind on thy enemies". Why not, eh?
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="201">
		<Name>Liquid Fire Vial (Strong)</Name>
		<Desc>A small flask with extremely potent liquid fire. When thrown, it will "fall like a fiery whirlwind on thy enemies". Why not, eh?
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="202">
		<Name>Liquid Fire Vial (Burning)</Name>
		<Desc>A small flask with liquid fire. When thrown, it will "fall like a fiery whirlwind on thy enemies" and continue to burn. Why not, eh?
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="210">
		<Name>Black Powder Bomb</Name>
		<Desc>A clay pot, filled with black powder and small stones. When thrown, it explodes on impact, flinging the stones waywardly with tremendous lethality.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="211">
		<Name>Black Powder Bomb (Strong)</Name>
		<Desc>A clay pot, filled with black powder and small stones. When thrown, it explodes on impact, flinging the stones waywardly with tremendous lethality.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- The range is increased.
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="212">
		<Name>Black Powder Bomb (Frag)</Name>
		<Desc>A clay pot, filled with black powder and iron balls. When thrown, it explodes on impact, flinging the balls waywardly with tremendous lethality.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Increases chance of breaking armor.
&lt;br&gt;- Partially ignores DR.
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1800">
		<Name>Cassava Root</Name>
		<Desc>A large, thick root that can be cooked and eaten. Often the only source of food in the wasteland, the plant doesn't require much water and can grow anywhere. An oily root paste can be rubbed on wounds to prevent infection and accelerate healing.

Base reagent.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1801">
		<Name>Goldenberry</Name>
		<Desc>Small, yellow berries growing densely along the branches of Goldenberry shrubs. Highly nutritious, the berries have a reputation of a cure-all, at least when it comes to respiratory and digestive disorders. The oil extracted from the berries can fortify healing properties of other plants.

Modifier reagent.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1802">
		<Name>Amaranthus Extract</Name>
		<Desc>A rare extract of amaranthus: the unfading flower. While you've seen scrolls describing the extraction technique, the process is extremely complicated and requires arcane devices you've never heard of, so quite possibly, this is the only extract in existence.

Modifier reagent.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1803">
		<Name>Blood Mushroom</Name>
		<Desc>Deep red mushrooms covered with white wart-like protuberances have been known for their mystical properties for quite some time. They were boiled to make intoxicating drinks, dried and chewed to enter the dreamworld, but it was the Skanian priests who discovered how to brew a special draught that gives a man neither dreams nor drunkenness, but rage and bloodlust.

Base reagent.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1804">
		<Name>Emoryl Root</Name>
		<Desc>This unremarkable plant is known only for its ability to keep other alchemical compounds in the bloodstream longer, thus extending the duration of most potions and poisons.

Modifier reagent.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1805">
		<Name>Fennah Berries</Name>
		<Desc>A natural coagulant, these berries are used by healers to stop bleeding. A skilled alchemist can create a powerful extract that will greatly increase blood coagulation and reduce the blood loss in combat. Unfortunately, the effect is temporary and thus poses a potential danger – after a few minutes the wounds will open up again, causing unexpected damage.

Modifier reagent.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1806">
		<Name>Quicksilver Roots</Name>
		<Desc>While chewing Quicksilver's leaves produces a stimulating and refreshing effect, the real power of the plant is in its roots. A skilled alchemist can extract the precious oil from the roots and distill it into a potion that quickens movement and reaction time.

Base reagent.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1807">
		<Name>Dragon's Blood Extract</Name>
		<Desc>Contrary to popular belief, Dragon's Blood is a tree that owes its name to the red resin it produces. The resin has near miraculous curative and alchemical properties or so the alchemists claim. Unfortunately, the tree only grows on a small archipelago of four islands somewhere in the southern seas, which makes the Dragon's Blood's extract as rare as if it actually came from dragons.

Modifier reagent.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1808">
		<Name>Kadura Leaves</Name>
		<Desc>Like many other plants, the Kadura relies on toxins, rather than thorns, to ward of animals. Usually, the poison causes nausea and irregular heartbeat, yet when distilled properly, it can kill a man in mere minutes.

Base reagent.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1809">
		<Name>Avatera Sprouts</Name>
		<Desc>These light-green sprouts are a natural anti-venom. Every healer can cook a simple draught that can reduce the effects of snake and scorpion poison, but only a skilled alchemist can brew an elixir that can instantly counter the deadliest poison and render it harmless.

Modifier reagent.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1810">
		<Name>Sulfur</Name>
		<Desc>Abundantly available, sulphur, or the burning stone, was first used as a medicine. Later, when its military applications were discovered, it was used to produce a different kind of medicine – acid, black powder, and liquid fire.

Base/Modifier reagent.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1811">
		<Name>Salt Petrae</Name>
		<Desc>The salt of rock – a salt-like substance that encrusts cave walls. Unlike other salts, sal petrae has incendiary properties and burns with a purple flame, which makes it a popular reagent among alchemists.

Modifier reagent.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1812">
		<Name>Fools' Gold</Name>
		<Desc>A mineral called pyrite, better known as fool's gold due to its uncanny resemblance to everyone's favourite metal. It's used to make cheap jewellery, ferrous sulphate to treat iron deficiency and make inks, as well as an incredibly potent acid - oil of vitriol.

Modifier reagent.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1813">
		<Name>Rock Oil</Name>
		<Desc>A thick, flammable liquid that seeps out of fissures in the ground. It is believed that when the underworld comes close to the surface, its fiery rivers make springs ooze rock oil and gas instead of clean water. There are many who would experiment with such dark materials, and thus there are many who would risk their lives to gather it and sell at a profit.

Base reagent.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1814">
		<Name>Quicklime</Name>
		<Desc>A white, corrosive substance produced by heating limestone. It's used to make lime mortar, purify steel during smelting, and waterproof boats, but if you're looking for more practical uses, it makes liquid fire ignite faster and burn longer.

Modifier reagent.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1815">
		<Name>Black Powder</Name>
		<Desc>An explosive mixture of sulphur, charcoal, and sal petrae, ground into a powder. Discovered accidentally during a search for an elixir of immortality, the black powder failed to grant eternal life, but did a pretty good job blowing one's enemies to bloody bits, which, come to think about it, contributes greatly to one's longevity.

Base reagent.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1816">
		<Name>Iron Balls</Name>
		<Desc>Small iron balls made for unknown purpose.

Modifier "reagent".</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2010">
		<Name>Bronze Goblet</Name>
		<Desc>A bronze goblet - sturdy and affordable.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2011">
		<Name>Silver Goblet</Name>
		<Desc>A silver goblet - modest and tasteful.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2012">
		<Name>Golden Goblet</Name>
		<Desc>A golden goblet. Even the water tastes better out of this.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2013">
		<Name>Bronze Plate</Name>
		<Desc>A simple bronze plate.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2014">
		<Name>Silver Plate</Name>
		<Desc>A traditional silver plate.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2015">
		<Name>Golden Plate</Name>
		<Desc>A fine golden plate.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1052">
		<Name>House Aurelian Cape</Name>
		<Desc>A long outer garment designed to protect against the weather and identify the cape's wearer as a member of House Aurelian.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1710">
		<Name>Buckler - Imperial Guards</Name>
		<Desc>The smallest shield, favored by quick fighters. It has a convex shape designed to ward off blows. Due to its small size, the buckler is useless in unskilled hands. This particular buckler bears the sign of the Imperial Guards.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1711">
		<Name>Cavalry shield - Imperial Guards</Name>
		<Desc>A medium-weight oval shield mostly used by cavalry and auxiliary troops. Oval shields could be found everywhere, from Kemet to Ashkaan. They offer good defence and reasonable mobility. This particular shield bears the Imperial Guards insignia.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1712">
		<Name>Infantry shield - Imperial Guards</Name>
		<Desc>A larger, rectangular shield with a slightly curved profile, this piece was designed for slowly advancing legionnaires who would utilize group defensive formations like the famous 'turtle'. It may be less useful to a lone fighter. This particular shield bears the Imperial Guards insignia.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1713">
		<Name>Tower Shield - Imperial Guards</Name>
		<Desc>A heavy rectangular shield with a slightly curved profile, the tower shield provides unparalleled protection for a stationary unit, but is cumbersome and unwieldy, severely taxing its owner's mobility and response time. This particular shield bears the Imperial Guards insignia.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2165">
		<Name>Jar</Name>
		<Desc>A strange, softly glowing jar.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2170">
		<Name>The Helm of Destiny</Name>
		<Desc>The famous Helm of Destiny. Contrary to your expectations, it's an unadorned helmet made of grey metal.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2175">
		<Name>Silver Badge</Name>
		<Desc>A silver badge required to enter the East Wing of the Maadoran's palace.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2176">
		<Name>Steel badge</Name>
		<Desc>A steel badge you bought from another solicitor to enter the palace.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1335">
		<Name>Commercium Ring</Name>
		<Desc>A ring with the Commercium insignia.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1355">
		<Name>Tower Ring</Name>
		<Desc>The ring is heavier than it looks and has three rotating bands with markings on them.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2180">
		<Name>The Crimson Eye</Name>
		<Desc>A heavy, glowing red sphere, encased in a bronze reliquary.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2185">
		<Name>Demon Core</Name>
		<Desc>A heavy, glowing stone, radiating heat.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2135">
		<Name>Spies' Reports</Name>
		<Desc>The spies' reports, written in a strange code.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2177">
		<Name>Golden Badge</Name>
		<Desc>A golden badge required to enter the West Wing of the Maadoran's palace.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2190">
		<Name>Metal glove</Name>
		<Desc>A strange, metal glove of unknown purpose. It takes three 'tubes' to power it up, so whatever the glove does requires a lot of magical energy.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2195">
		<Name>Mysterious artefact</Name>
		<Desc>A delicate, golden device with a small dial and a couple of buttons. There is a symbol on the other side – a circle with a diagonal line through it. A null?</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="115">
		<Name>Lion's Claw</Name>
		<Desc>It’s a very old shamshir forged from the patterned blue steel. The blade has seen plenty of use – it’s covered with nicks and scratches, but the edge is still keen and the balance is flawless. The maker’s mark is a lion’s claw, which is what gave the sword its name.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="450">
		<Name>Stone Guardian Body</Name>
		<Desc>Dev Item</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1150">
		<Name>Stone Guardian Head</Name>
		<Desc>Dev Item</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2200">
		<Name>Senna's Letter</Name>
		<Desc>A letter given to you by Lord Senna, absolving you of all sins and wrong doings. It says that “the bearer of this letter has acted under my orders and for the good of the realm”, signed by Legatus Pavola.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="430">
		<Name>The Blue Cuirass</Name>
		<Desc>Forged by the legendary smith Nazarius, this cuirass has been passed from one worthy warrior to another, until it ended up in your hands, still covered in the blood of the previous owner. The cuirass is covered with dents and cuts, but the craftsmanship is undeniable.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="116">
		<Name>The Bringer of Storms</Name>
		<Desc>The origin of this sword is lost in antiquity. Some say that it was forged to slay the demons unleashed by the Qantari, others say that it’s a cursed blade that consumes the very souls of those it slays. The wide blade is well balanced and has a nearly flawless thick edge, free of nicks and dents despite its age.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="431">
		<Name>Darius’ Armor</Name>
		<Desc>Forged from the purest, thousand-fold blue steel, this armor was given to Darius as a tribute. Rumor has it that Darius had the armor enchanted and tempered in the blood of the last Magi. No weapon could touch him while he was wearing it, so the assassin that took his life had to wait until Darius removed it after a battle to deliver the lethal blow.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="432">
		<Name>Honor-Bound</Name>
		<Desc>A magnificent blue steel armor given to Marcus Tiberius Aerus for a personal act of valor above and beyond the call of duty. The armor is exquisitely crafted and decorated with gold inlays.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="117">
		<Name>Dreamweaver</Name>
		<Desc>Forged by Cattullus of Asmara, considered by many to be one of the greatest sword makers, this blue steel gladius has a narrower blade with parallel cutting edges and a triangular tip. Unfortunately, master Cattulus was killed during the siege of the city, which makes this sword one of a kind.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="126">
		<Name>The Pendulum of Judgement</Name>
		<Desc>It’s truly one of the finest axes you’ve ever held. Whoever’s made definitely knew how to work steel. The blade has both a primary and secondary bevel. The primary bevel is established well up the axe head to facilitate deep cuts, while the edge bevel is slightly blunter to prevent the edge from folding, chipping, or dulling quickly.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="155">
		<Name>Old Faithful</Name>
		<Desc>An old elm longbow. It’s an ugly, unfinished-looking weapon, but astonishingly stiff, large and strong, and equally capable of use for long or short shooting.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="433">
		<Name>Mangudai Ordu Armor</Name>
		<Desc>A leather armor worn by the Mangudai warriors, proven in the hunt and on the warpath. The unusually thick skin it's made from grants its wearer unparalleled protection and longevity.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1750">
		<Name>Impenetrable</Name>
		<Desc>An infantry shield of recently departed Quintus Sabellius Baro, called the Invincible. Made to his own specifications, this shield features a mix of cutting edge technology and proven design.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="118">
		<Name>The Chopper</Name>
		<Desc>A makeshift sword fashioned from an ancient metal cutter. It's too heavy to be wielded in one hand, but it does have superior armor penetration.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="167">
		<Name>The Bolter</Name>
		<Desc>A makeshift gun fashioned from an ancient device used to shoot nails into walls and other objects. It’s not very accurate, but the gun only needs a moment to get ready for the next shot.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1001">
		<Name>Centurion's cape</Name>
		<Desc>A cape issued to centurions to distinguish them from the rank and file.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1002">
		<Name>Traveler's cape</Name>
		<Desc>An affordable protection from cold and wind that can double up as a fashion statement.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1003">
		<Name>Noble's cape</Name>
		<Desc>The finest garment for customers with the most discriminative taste.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1129">
		<Name>Wolf helmet</Name>
		<Desc>A wolf skin worn over a standard iron helmet to terrify your enemies. In the long forgotten days, such helmets were worn only by standard bearers. These days it's a fashion statement.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2007">
		<Name>Yellow Sapphire</Name>
		<Desc>A rare yellow sapphire cut to perfection. The center of the gem is very dark, almost making it look like an eye.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="904">
		<Name>Respirator</Name>
		<Desc>A breathing apparatus of the Old Empire. When charged with magical energies, it will allow you to breath in toxic environments.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="903">
		<Name>Strange Mask</Name>
		<Desc>A strange mask of unknown purpose.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2205">
		<Name>Mechanical Eye</Name>
		<Desc>The ball of this fancy fake eye is a cloudy blue, a gem unlike any you have seen. The back of the device has eight hinged, outward-curving grips around the circumference, which on insertion would anchor it in the empty socket permanently. The long, metal tube protruding from the back is hollow and about wide enough to fit the thick nerve that runs to the back of a living eye.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="136">
		<Name>The Perforator</Name>
		<Desc>It's a mirror-polished, steel spiked club forged by a true master of the craft. The long spikes, oil-tempered and clay-hardened, are capable of punching holes through any armor.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2201">
		<Name>Air Valve</Name>
		<Desc>A device designed to control the flow of air. Ingenious!</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2202">
		<Name>Oil Injector</Name>
		<Desc>As the name suggest, this device is responsible for injecting the right amount of fuel at the right time. Whoever’s invented it had way too much time on his hands.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2191">
		<Name>The Ghost Hand</Name>
		<Desc>It was said that some machines could never function in this world for they required different laws of physics. Thus, the Magi had built them in realms that exist elsewhere. They called them the Ghost Worlds and used devices such as this one to bridge the gap between these worlds and ours.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2192">
		<Name>The Ghost Hand (Charged)</Name>
		<Desc>It was said that some machines could never function in this world for they required different laws of physics. Thus, the Magi had built them in realms that exist elsewhere. They called them the Ghost Worlds and used devices such as this one to bridge the gap between these worlds and ours.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1610">
		<Name>Large Module</Name>
		<Desc>It's a large glass tube filled with glowing energy.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="250">
		<Name>DEV - Long Bow Monastery</Name>
		<Desc>One of the most powerful bows, the longbow is fashioned from a single length of yew wood. The longbow's power is limited only by the strength of the archer, and in the right hands can punch holes through even plate armor.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="251">
		<Name>DEV - Heavy Crossbow Monastery</Name>
		<Desc>Used mainly as a siege weapon in the Great War, this weapon has a reinforced metal bow, granting extra power and penetration, but takes longer to arm. This crossbow is capable of penetrating any armor.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2210">
		<Name>Surgical Kit</Name>
		<Desc>The case contains a folded section of parchment and what looks like a set of surgical instruments. There are both smooth and serrated blades of various sizes, hooks to part flesh, a drill with different bits, a few unpleasantly large needles, and a strange metal syringe that incorporates a dead power tube. Every item is gleaming and sharp, as if begging to be used for the first time.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="105">
		<Name>The Arbiter</Name>
		<Desc>A family heirloom, this steel jambia is clearly the work of a master smith. The grinds are flawless and the edge is exceptionally keen. Once drawn, the dagger is said to be able to solve any dispute, hence the name.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="127">
		<Name>Black Dow</Name>
		<Desc>It's a crude and unadorned weapon, made for killing and nothing else. It bears hammer marks and dents, but the edge is razor-sharp and the balance is nearly perfect.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="434">
		<Name>Zagros' Armguard</Name>
		<Desc>An exceptionally well-crafted iron armguard, allegedly belonging to a long dead arena's champion named Zagros.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="146">
		<Name>Pax Deorum</Name>
		<Desc>An unusual steel trident decorated with a metal skull and an inscription that reads Pax Deorum.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1130">
		<Name>Zagros' Helmet</Name>
		<Desc>An exceptionally well-crafted iron murmillo helmet, allegedly belonging to a long dead arena's champion named Zagros.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="905">
		<Name>Snake Pendant</Name>
		<Desc>It’s the mark of House Crassus - the great serpent Araborus whose awakening will herald the end of this world and the beginning of a new one!</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="906">
		<Name>Pebble Necklace</Name>
		<Desc>A powerful talisman infused with the magic of the Abyss.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2500">
		<Name>Imperial Power Armor</Name>
		<Desc>The finest pre-War armor, fashioned from tempered blue steel. With raw Power harnessed from other planes, it augments its wearer's natural abilities and even generates a protective shield to slow down incoming blows.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;*Right-click on the armor to interact with it*</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2510">
		<Name>Apis Helmet</Name>
		<Desc>A power armor helmet sculpted to resemble the head of a mighty-horned bull, this piece will inspire panic and fear in the weak.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2511">
		<Name>Anubis Helmet</Name>
		<Desc>A sculpted power armor helmet in the form of a jackal's head. When charged, the eyes and features of this helmet glow with arcane energy, recalling some forgotten demi-god towering over mortal men.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2512">
		<Name>Horus Helmet</Name>
		<Desc>This heavy power armor helmet takes the shape of a hawk's head, and offers unparalleled protection against attacks of all kinds. Wreak havoc, and watch your enemies tremble in fear of the arcane!</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2513">
		<Name>Ra Helmet</Name>
		<Desc>Fear no mortal enemies in this strange, pre-War power armor helmet. It was carved in the form of a falcon's head to invoke superstitious dread in worthless foes.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2505">
		<Name>Imperial Power Armor Gauntlet</Name>
		<Desc>The finest pre-War armor, fashioned from tempered blue steel. With raw Power harnessed from other planes, it augments its wearer's natural abilities and even generates a protective shield to slow down incoming blows.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2501">
		<Name>Imperial Power Armor (Charged)</Name>
		<Desc>The finest pre-War armor, fashioned from tempered blue steel. With raw Power harnessed from other planes, it augments its wearer's natural abilities and even generates a protective shield to slow down incoming blows.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;*Right-click on the armor to interact with it*</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="119">
		<Name>Qantari Sword</Name>
		<Desc>A flat wooden club with evenly spaced blue steel inserts running on both sides. You can probably use it as a sword.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="128">
		<Name>Qantari Axe</Name>
		<Desc>A flat wooden club with evenly spaced blue steel inserts running on both sides. You can probably use it as an axe.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="137">
		<Name>Qantari War Club</Name>
		<Desc>A flat wooden club with evenly spaced blue steel inserts running on both sides. You can probably use it as a hammer. It's all in the swing.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="252">
		<Name>DEV - Scolopendra Jaw</Name>
		<Desc>The Jaw of a Scolopendra</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="451">
		<Name>DEV - Scolopendra Body</Name>
		<Desc>Dev Item</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="253">
		<Name>DEV - Stone Guard Gladius</Name>
		<Desc>A double-edged short sword designed for thrusting and slashing in close quarters. Favoured by the Imperial Guard, the gladius is a common sight throughout the remnants of the Empire.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="147">
		<Name>Vindicator</Name>
		<Desc>A magnificent one-handed spear with a wide steel blade. Apparently, it was forged for a guilty as sin praetor who requested trial by combat. The praetor spent a fortune on that spear and after killing his accuser, he called it Vindicator.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="138">
		<Name>That Which Kills</Name>
		<Desc>A two-handed, fancy-looking steel sledgehammer you took from a Skanian zealot. He said it's called That Which Kills in his language, just before you killed him.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2220">
		<Name>Aegis of the Magi</Name>
		<Desc>A strange suit of armor.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="10500">
		<Name>Undefined Item</Name>
		<Desc>
	</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1500">
		<Name>Whetstone</Name>
		<Desc>A small sharpening stone. Increases damage based on your crafting level, duration set by metal.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Crafting levels: 2-4-6-8-10. Damage: 1-2-3-4-5.
&lt;br&gt;- Duration: 10-20-30-40-50 attacks, from Bronze to Sky Metal.
&lt;br&gt;- Drag and drop on a weapon or a missiles to apply the effect.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="425">
		<Name>Lorica Hamata</Name>
		<Desc>A chain-mail armor made from interlocking rings of metal. Similar to Lorica Segmentata, Lorica Hamata offers better mobility but slightly less protection.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="6900">
		<Name>DEV - Scorpion Claw</Name>
		<Desc>Dev Item</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="6901">
		<Name>DEV - Spectre Spike</Name>
		<Desc>Dev Item</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="907">
		<Name>Protection Amulet</Name>
		<Desc>A protection amulet to ward off magical constructs and evil spirits alike.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2230">
		<Name>The Divine Spear</Name>
		<Desc>If the Divine Spear is really a spear, it is the strangest weapon you've ever seen. Too thick and too heavy, it wasn't made for human hands. Only a giant would be able to hurl this thing at his enemies.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2400">
		<Name>Hellgate Key</Name>
		<Desc>A strange four-pronged key.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="6950">
		<Name>DEV - Specter Body</Name>
		<Desc>Dev Item</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="908">
		<Name>Demon's Eye charm</Name>
		<Desc>A potent charm made from a rare, magically-preserved eye of a Qantari demon. It will ward off evil and protect you from harm.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2240">
		<Name>Mysterious contraption</Name>
		<Desc>A rusted ball the size of an apple. It's covered with strange protuberances.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2250">
		<Name>Medical Canister</Name>
		<Desc>A canister with a medical compound long past its expiration date.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2410">
		<Name>Mining Outpost Key</Name>
		<Desc>An iron key. You can twirl it around your finger to impress the local yokels.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2178">
		<Name>Silver Badge</Name>
		<Desc>A silver badge you bought from another solicitor to enter the palace.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="7000">
		<Name>DEV - Elder God Hand</Name>
		<Desc>Dev Item</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="7001">
		<Name>DEV - Elder God Shield</Name>
		<Desc>Dev Item</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="7002">
		<Name>DEV - Elder God Tentacles</Name>
		<Desc>Dev Item</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="7003">
		<Name>DEV - Elder God Mind</Name>
		<Desc>Dev Item</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1404">
		<Name>Hardened Leather</Name>
		<Desc>Leather boiled in oil and beeswax.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="7004">
		<Name>DEV - Elder God Body</Name>
		<Desc>Dev Item</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="213">
		<Name>Mysterious contraption</Name>
		<Desc>An ancient explosive device, restored and hastily repaired.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;- Can be placed in a belt slot.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2155">
		<Name>An ancient scroll</Name>
		<Desc>An ancient scroll written in an unfamiliar language.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2156">
		<Name>An ancient mantra</Name>
		<Desc>It's a rare mantra dedicated to ancient flying chariots made of blessed iron and gifted with the power of the gods. The mantra contains detailed praying instructions that might persuade the air elementals to pull such a chariot as if they were horses.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2405">
		<Name>Monastery Key</Name>
		<Desc>An iron key. You can twirl it around your finger to impress the local yokels.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="2415">
		<Name>Ganezzar Tunnels Key</Name>
		<Desc>An iron key. You can twirl it around your finger to impress the local yokels.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="909">
		<Name>Charged Respirator</Name>
		<Desc>A breathing apparatus of the Old Empire. Charged with magical energies, it will allow you to breath in toxic environments.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="148">
		<Name>Kadmos' Skewer</Name>
		<Desc>A custom steel spear made for Kadmos, a former arena champion brought low by wine and women. It's longer than an average one-handed spear, which gives it a superior reach.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1751">
		<Name>Swordbreaker</Name>
		<Desc>A lightweight metal buckler with improved durability and fancy design. A must have accessory for today's fashionable warrior.</Desc>
	</Item>
	<Item ID="1132">
		<Name>Warrior's Crown</Name>
		<Desc>An exceptional blue steel helmet that provides protection without obstructing its wearer's vision. A long time ago one of the arena champions was crowned with it; since then it was passed from one champion to another until Kadmos walked away with it.</Desc>
	</Item>
</Language>