<?xml version="1.0"?>
<dlgData xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <conditions>
      <string>aod.npc_meru_alk_met</string>
    </conditions>
    <links>
      <int>8451</int>
    </links>
    <dlg_name>ALK_NPC_Meru</dlg_name>
    <def_link>8441</def_link>
    <def_speaker_name>Meru</def_speaker_name>
    <def_portrait>Meru</def_portrait>
  </header>
  <parts>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Meru is praying, his eyes closed, his lips moving silently. Faelan looks nervous, his smug smile long gone.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgRotateToChar(1, 8000);</string>
        <string>aod.npc_meru_alk_met = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Now what?”</text>
          <def_link>8442</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.alk_HC_loremasterRitual</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>8452</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8441</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Meru finishes the prayer, then opens his eyes.

“Once you find the sacred chamber, my loremaster will perform the ritual. If the Gods accept my sacrifice, they will return and the Kingdom of Men will end.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Are you really going to sacrifice yourself?”</text>
          <def_link>8443</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“The Kingdom of Men will end? What does it mean?”</text>
          <def_link>8444</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8452</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Meru finishes the prayer, then opens his eyes.

“Once you find the sacred chamber, you’ll perform the ritual. If the Gods accept my sacrifice, they will return and the Kingdom of Men will end.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Are you really going to sacrifice yourself?”</text>
          <def_link>8443</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“The Kingdom of Men will end? What does it mean?”</text>
          <def_link>8444</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8442</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Worthy is the Lamb that was slain to receive power and blessing,” quotes Meru. “There is power in sacrifice – power to change the world – and I’ll gladly die a thousand deaths for a chance to do that.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“What’s that bit about the Kingdom of Men ending?”</text>
          <def_link>8444</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8443</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“We tried, didn’t we?” says Meru softly. “For thousands of years we tried to find our way in darkness. We built great empires only to watch them fall. We multiplied only to field greater armies and fight greater wars.

“My House witnessed the rise and the fall of the greatest of empires. We rise only to fall, doomed to repeat the cycle we can’t break.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“But the Gods can?”</text>
          <def_link>8445</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8444</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“The Gods can,” nods Meru. “Did you know that in the days long gone, before the Empire claimed all the eye could see, it was common for the city-states to seek chieftains to rule them.

“Let us seek a prince who may rule over us, and judge us according to the Law,” Meru quotes again. “Well, I’m not seeking a prince. I’m seeking a God who will rule over us and put an end to the Kingdom of Men and petty bickering over nothing that it will be remembered for!”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“What made you see the light?”</text>
          <def_link>8446</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.cha &gt;= 7</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>8448</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8445</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[charisma failure]“We've wasted enough time already. Find the sacred chamber!”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>8447</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8446</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“We've wasted enough time already. Find the sacred chamber!”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgRotateToChar(1, 8000);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>8447</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8451</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>setRtsCam();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>8447</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[success]“Years ago I let Antidas drag me into a war against Gaelius. Antidas claimed that he wanted to force Gaelius to accept a triumvirate government and rule together, but I think he knew that Gaelius would never accept such terms and wanted to use me to take Maadoran. It all seems so petty and meaningless now,” says Meru, looking away.

“My House was always surrounded in rumors and Antidas was convinced that I had the Magi’s engines of war hidden away. He kept pushing until I agreed and ventured into the depths of Castle Ganezzar. My father had them sealed, but we were losing the war and I was caught up in the moment.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>8449</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.pc_usedStarChamber</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>8453</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8448</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“I found the ‘star room’ and I sat on the throne, unsure of what to expect. And then the Gods spoke to me and their voices were like thunder, tearing my mind apart.

“I woke up on the floor, bleeding from my ears, too weak to stand. It took me a long time to realize what happened - they judged me and found me worthy. They showed me the past and the future. They showed me my destiny!”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“So you withdrew from the war and renounced your title.”</text>
          <def_link>8450</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8449</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“I found the ‘star room’ and I sat on the throne, unsure of what to expect. And then the Gods spoke to me as they spoke to you, and their voices were like thunder, tearing my mind apart.

“I woke up on the floor, bleeding from my ears, too weak to stand. It took me a long time to realize what happened - they judged me and found me worthy as they found you. They showed me the past and the future. They showed me my destiny as they showed you yours!”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“So you withdrew from the war and renounced your title.”</text>
          <def_link>8450</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8453</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“After the revelations, I could do no less. I was no lord. The true Lords are up there, we’re nothing but their servants.

“In a way I owe it all to Antidas. Had he not pushed me, I would have lived in ignorance, dreaming of that triumvirate government he sold me on.

“It's time to find the sacred chamber,” says Meru gently. “I'm ready.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>8447</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8450</UID>
    </dlgPart>
  </parts>
</dlgData>