<?xml version="1.0"?>
<dlgData xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <conditions />
    <links />
    <dlg_name>ALK_HC_02</dlg_name>
    <def_link>8203</def_link>
    <def_speaker_name>None</def_speaker_name>
    <def_portrait>None</def_portrait>
  </header>
  <parts>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait>Meru</portrait>
      <speaker_name>Meru</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>Meru staggers when he steps into the chamber and his face goes white. At first you think he’s afraid, of the unnerving mix of technology and magic, the weird faces staring from the hieroglyphs.

“This is where it happened,” the self-proclaimed First Acolyte whispers in wonder. “Do you feel it? Can you *hear* it?”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_HC_FaelanChamber, 8001);</string>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_HC_LoremasterChamber, 8033);</string>
        <string>setWindowImage(alk_chamberIntro);</string>
        <string>aod.jnl_AlAkia_Meru = 2;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>8204</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8203</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait>Meru</portrait>
      <speaker_name>Meru</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>He kneels before the largest sarcophagus, and slowly, as if the huge metal cylinder were fragile as an eggshell, leans forward to touch his forehead against the rusted surface. He looks upward, tears streaming down his face.

“I offer myself to Thee – do with me as Thou wilt. Relieve me of the bondage of self, that I may better do Thy will.” You realize the words are a formal supplication, a mantra Meru has learned from gods know where. “I give myself up to Thee. My body, my mind, my soul are thine. Do with me as Thou wilt, relieve me of the bondage of self, replace my will with thine.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
        <string>setWindowImage();</string>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_HC_MeruSarc, 8000);</string>
        <string>apmsPlayMusic(custom, 9, 1);</string>
        <string>dlgCam(25, 45, 8, 8000);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>8205</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8204</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait>Meru</portrait>
      <speaker_name>Meru</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>“I am ready,” says Meru, eyes hot with fervor.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Perform the ritual.</text>
          <def_link>8206</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.alk_HC_loremasterRitual == 0</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Watch the loremaster perform the ritual.</text>
          <def_link>8228</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.alk_HC_loremasterRitual == 1</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8205</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>You help Meru into the sarcophagus where heavy metal clamps await to secure his arms and legs. You lower a bizarrely shaped helmet, fixed to a mobile armature, until it cradles his head. When you step back the two halves of the lid close of their own accord on the sounds of his mumbled prayers.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
        <string>setCharacterRendered(8000, 0);</string>
        <string>setWindowImage(alk_chamberIntro);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>8229</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8228</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The loremaster begins reciting an unknown mantra. Gradually, a previously unnoticed hum burgeons to an oppressive drone. The noise emanates from the pyramid, continuing to grow as the chamber lights up, awakening from its centuries-long slumber. Meru’s voice within the metal shell grows in volume alongside the humming racket, turning ragged and halting. He’s practically screaming his supplications now.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_ChamberControls, 8033);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>8230</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8229</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Time after time the loremaster moves his fingers over the controls. The console lights flicker in reaction, but without the desired result, and the structure around you begins to vibrate from stresses it wasn’t built to withstand. You hear other, more alarming sounds from below, of blocks shifting and mortar crumbling, and you imagine the entire complex collapsing, burying all of you in a tomb never to be uncovered again.

The loremaster tries again and the pyramid finally complies with his request. With a sharp crack, the top splits along its four seams and peels open like a flower, revealing an enormous, crimson crystal, engraved with a thousand arcane symbols.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>8231</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.lore &gt;= 5</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>8209</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8230</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Slowly, the loremaster shifts the sliding mechanism which feeds power into the crystal. The vibrations increase until your teeth rattle. It absorbs more and more energy, and still demands more. You half expect it to shatter but it moves not at all. At last the power is at maximum, the indicator the same red as the artifact. The air grows charged and humid. Every hair on your body stands, quivers, and the world itself seems to wait with you.

You are driven to the floor when the first lightning bolt strikes the apex of the crystal, and scramble backwards when it is followed by another. Black ink pools in the white clouds overhead to herald a storm vast and unnatural, overwhelming the sky above. You cover your scorched face as the lightning strikes continue, and intensify. Wind moans hollowly through pillars and fallen walls as clouds begin to swirl slowly around the pyramid.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
        <string>setWindowImage(alk_chamber_ritual_01);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>8211</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8231</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>You help Meru into the sarcophagus where heavy metal clamps await to secure his arms and legs. You lower a bizarrely shaped helmet, fixed to a mobile armature, until it cradles his head. When you step back the two halves of the lid close of their own accord on the sounds of his mumbled prayers.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>setWindowImage(alk_chamberIntro);</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_ChamberControls);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>8207</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.lore &lt; 9 &amp;&amp; aod.star_room_learned_ritual == false</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>8212</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Sabotage the ritual.</text>
          <def_link>8227</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8206</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>You take a breath and review what you know before assaulting the controls. It takes you several attempts to get the sequence right. Gradually, a previously unnoticed hum burgeons to an oppressive drone. The noise emanates from the pyramid, continuing to grow as the chamber lights up, awakening from its centuries-long slumber. Meru’s voice within the metal shell grows in volume alongside the humming racket, turning ragged and halting. He’s practically screaming his supplications now.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>8208</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8207</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The next step of the ritual proves even more frustrating. Time after time you move your fingers over the controls. The console lights flicker in reaction, but without the desired result, and the structure around you begins to vibrate from stresses it wasn’t built to withstand. You hear other, more alarming sounds from below, of blocks shifting and mortar crumbling, and you imagine the entire complex collapsing, burying the two of you in a tomb never to be uncovered again.

Though you would swear to the heavens that your latest attempt is no different, the pyramid finally complies with your request. With a sharp crack, the top splits along its four seams and peels open like a flower, revealing an enormous, crimson crystal, engraved with a thousand arcane symbols.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>8210</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.lore &gt;= 5</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>8209</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8208</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[lore success]You recall an account from ancient times of a Qantari tribute to the Emperor. The tribute was a rare crystal, pure and clear as spring water. It was described as being huge, though you hadn’t guessed it was as big as a house. As the story goes, their craftsmen worked on it for decades, until every facet hosted a mysterious symbol, each somehow related to its brother to form a network of powerful magic.

When the engravers’ work was finished, the sacrifices began. Slaves, refugees and criminals were brought in their hundreds to a hideous machine where they were suspended upside-down and their blood decanted over the artifact. Yet however much blood was spilled, the crystal absorbed it all, and over the course of weeks its color changed from pale moonlight to a rich crimson.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>8210</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8209</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Slowly, you shift the sliding mechanism which feeds power into the crystal. The vibrations increase until your teeth rattle. It absorbs more and more energy, and still demands more. You half expect it to shatter but it moves not at all. At last the power is at maximum, the indicator the same red as the artifact. The air grows charged and humid. Every hair on your body stands, quivers, and the world itself seems to wait with you.

You are driven to the floor when the first lightning bolt strikes the apex of the crystal, and scramble backwards when it is followed by another. Black ink pools in the white clouds overhead to herald a storm vast and unnatural, overwhelming the sky above. You cover your scorched face as the lightning strikes continue, and intensify. Wind moans hollowly through pillars and fallen walls as clouds begin to swirl slowly around the pyramid.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>setWindowImage(alk_chamber_ritual_01);</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>8211</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8210</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Thunder claps deafeningly close. You look up, thinking the crystal must have shattered, but no, it glows with a fierce red health that reminds you, too much, of flesh. At that very moment the crystal releases its energy, firing a ray of impossibly white light into the sky.

The beam vanishes beyond the clouds, to a place you suspect no man could see. You rise to your feet, mesmerized, as the beam begins to pulse, a thaumaturgical bridge between the worlds. When it abruptly vanishes, the engines wind down of their own accord, the deafening drone softens and ceases, and the silence which ruled for many lifetimes of men rushes jealously back to claim the chamber. You are allowed a merciful few moments to gather your thoughts. Then the doors of the sarcophagus open. A man exits the device much more assuredly than Meru went in. He is pale but still, calm.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFadeToThisPart();</string>
        <string>dlgDeleteCharacter(8000);</string>
        <string>createByCharMarker("CM_Balzaar");</string>
        <string>setWindowImage();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>8213</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8211</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>You make a few subtle adjustments until a previously unnoticed hum burgeons to an oppressive drone. The noise emanates from the pyramid, continuing to grow as the chamber lights up, awakening from its centuries-long slumber. Meru’s voice within the metal shell grows in volume alongside the humming racket, turning ragged and halting. He’s practically screaming his supplications now.

Without warning thunder claps deafeningly close and the humming noise stops. Slowly, the lights fade away, the doors of the sarcophagus open and Meru stumbles out. He looks around as if wondering how he got here and collapses.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>setCharacterRendered(8000, 1);</string>
        <string>dlgCam(25, 45, 8, 8000);</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
        <string>setWindowImage();</string>
        <string>dlgSetAnimation(anim_death_back00, 0.95, 8000);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>8222</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8227</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[lore failure]You take a breath and review what you know before assaulting the controls. It takes you several attempts to get the sequence right. Gradually, a previously unnoticed hum burgeons to an oppressive drone. The noise emanates from the pyramid, continuing to grow as the chamber lights up, awakening from its centuries-long slumber. Meru’s voice within the metal shell grows in volume alongside the humming racket, turning ragged and halting. He’s practically screaming his supplications now.

Without warning thunder claps deafeningly close and the humming noise stops. Slowly, the lights fade away, the doors of the sarcophagus open and Meru stumbles out. He looks around as if wondering how he got here and collapses.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>setCharacterRendered(8000, 1);</string>
        <string>dlgCam(25, 45, 8, 8000);</string>
        <string>dlgSetAnimation(anim_death_back00, 0.95, 8000);</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
        <string>setWindowImage();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>8222</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8212</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait>Balzaar</portrait>
      <speaker_name>Meru</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>You are looking at the form of a man, of what was Meru. Now it is no longer Meru, nor is it a man.

“Kneel,” it says, without actually looking in your direction. The words are gentle. The power behind them is the sort that does not require threats.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_HC_MeruGod_PC);</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_HC_MeruGod, 8030);</string>
        <string>dlgCam(160, 45, 8, 8030);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Kneel.</text>
          <def_link>8215</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Kill it while it’s weak.</text>
          <def_link>8214</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8213</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait>None</portrait>
      <speaker_name>None</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>Drawing your weapon, you step forward. Fake-Meru smiles disdainfully, moving with speed he didn't possess before.

Faelan looks at fake-Meru in confusion, waiting for an order. As he locks his eyes with fake-Meru's pit-black eyes, he cries out, grasping his head, then collapses, convulsing on the floor.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgSetCombatAnimation();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Fight.</text>
          <def_link>8225</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8214</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>FIGHT</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
        <string>dlgSetAttitude(8030, 1, -10);</string>
        <string>aod.fight_alkBalzaar = 1;</string>
        <string>dlgSetAnimation(anim_death_back00, 0.95, 8001);</string>
        <string>aod.jnl_HC_AlAkia = 4;</string>
        <string>schedule(100, 0, dlgStartCombat);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>8225</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait>Balzaar</portrait>
      <speaker_name>Meru</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>Fake-Meru pauses a moment to consider the sky, the sarcophagus, and finally you. Too late you sense the significance of kneeling before this being. There is a presence behind your eyes, a compulsion to obey which you might be able to overcome if you turned all your will against it. Or not.

“You have questions.” Thankfully, the pressure relents. The deity is pleased with you. What would happen were it displeased does not merit further thought.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.alk_ritual_performed = true;</string>
        <string>setAchievement("ACH_GODS_AMONG");</string>
        <string>PCmemberBalzaar();</string>
        <string>aod.jnl_HC_AlAkia = 6;</string>
        <string>rwd_quest(HC2_01);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Who are you?”</text>
          <def_link>8216</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8215</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait>Balzaar</portrait>
      <speaker_name>Balzaar</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>“Your kind named me Balzaar. Since you must have a signifier to fix this entity in the feeble hierarchy of your brain, it will suffice.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>addLore(27);</string>
        <string>Addjournalchar(balzaar);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“And Meru?”</text>
          <def_link>8217</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8216</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait>Balzaar</portrait>
      <speaker_name>Balzaar</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>“Gone,” it says simply. You reflect that Meru achieved exactly what he desired. The god is silent. You are allowed more questions.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Now what?”</text>
          <def_link>8218</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.mdn_destroyed || aod.pc_mindShield || aod.gnz_underSiege == 0</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>8226</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8217</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait>Balzaar</portrait>
      <speaker_name>Balzaar</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>“We return to Ganezzar. The siege will be dissolved and you will go to the temple of Agathoth.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Why?”</text>
          <def_link>8219</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8218</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait>Balzaar</portrait>
      <speaker_name>Balzaar</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>“We return to Ganezzar. I will finish what Meru started and you will go to the temple of Agathoth.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Why?”</text>
          <def_link>8219</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8226</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait>Balzaar</portrait>
      <speaker_name>Balzaar</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>“Agathoth is a threat. He will be destroyed.” As with all of his pronouncements, it is a fact beyond dispute.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>addLore(28);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Help me understand, master. Can Agathoth be more powerful than you?”</text>
          <def_link>8220</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8219</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait>Balzaar</portrait>
      <speaker_name>Balzaar</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>“When the Magi severed the link, Agathoth shielded his vessel of flesh somehow. He alone did not return to the void. Yet he did not manifest his presence in this world either. The vessel is most probably damaged beyond recovery, but I do not leave such details to chance.

“I begin the work of rehabilitating my own vessel, and in time will regenerate my abilities. This form is far along in its naturally short span, and weak from neglect besides, much weaker than the first vessel. It will be a lengthy process. During this time you will act as my agent.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Why did you choose this body if it is so weak?”</text>
          <def_link>8221</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8220</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait>Balzaar</portrait>
      <speaker_name>Balzaar</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>“Others recognize it, and are accustomed to its authority. It will be more efficient to begin with this one than to utilize an unfamiliar form to enslave them.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Return to Ganezzar.</text>
          <def_link>8224</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8221</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait>Faelan</portrait>
      <speaker_name>Faelan</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>Faelan kneels next to him, checking the vitals, then gets up.

“He was a man of faith to the end,” says Faelan. For the first time he isn't smiling. “I'll stay with him for a while.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_HC_MeruSarc, 8000);</string>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_HC_FaelanSarc, 8001);</string>
        <string>dlgSetAnimation(anim_death_back00, 0.95, 8000);</string>
        <string>dlgKillCharacter(8000);</string>
        <string>aod.jnl_HC_AlAkia = 3;</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>8223</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8222</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END - Meru died</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>aod.ending_gnz_MeruDiesAlAkia = 1;</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
        <string>if(aod.jnl_HD_AlAkiaFate == 7) aod.jnl_HD_AlAkiaFate = 8;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>8223</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>ENDING - Meru is god</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeLongToThisPart();</string>
        <string>aod.ending_gnz_MeruGod = true;</string>
        <string>aod.ending_GNZ_faction_HC = 1;</string>
        <string>dlgDeleteCharacter(8000);</string>
        <string>dlgDeleteCharacter(8001);</string>
        <string>dlgDeleteCharacter(8033);</string>
        <string>if(aod.jnl_HD_AlAkiaFate == 7) aod.jnl_HD_AlAkiaFate = 11;</string>
        <string>SS_start("gnz_ending", "switchMission(\"Ganezzar.mis\");");</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>8224</UID>
    </dlgPart>
  </parts>
</dlgData>