<?xml version="1.0"?>
<dlgData xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <conditions />
    <links />
    <dlg_name>Antidas_01</dlg_name>
    <def_link>1005</def_link>
    <def_speaker_name>Antidas</def_speaker_name>
    <def_portrait>Antidas</def_portrait>
  </header>
  <parts>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"Do you believe in destiny, &lt;charname&gt;?" Before you have a chance to answer, Antidas continues. "I've spent more than a decade trying to find the temple and fulfill the prophecy. I've wasted a fortune and lost more men than I'd dare to admit, and just when I've decided to give up, you show up with another map. Coincidence? I don't believe in those.

"It is said that every man is given a chance to change his fate, to ascend to greatness and immortality, to rise above the ordinary and serve a cause greater than self-interests. You didn't come here by accident. Fate guided you here and it will guide you to the temple."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"The temple? The prophecy? Another map?"</text>
          <def_link>1006</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>1005</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"My apologies," says Antidas with a faint smile. "You know, of course, that our Empire had lasted thousands of years. Through military and diplomatic victories we had conquered the known world. An era of peace and prosperity was about to begin when the accursed Qantari came.

"Taller than any human, with glowing eyes and sharp claws, they came from the depth of the underworld and attacked without warning, slaughtering men and women alike. We fought the devils tooth and nail, but when the victory was at hand, they called forth their gods. Can you imagine a living horror towering over a battlefield and sweeping it with its arms, tearing flesh and armor with its talons? Our only chance was to reach into the higher planes and summon allies who could help us even the odds.

"Eventually the call was answered and the allies came. They burned the Qantari and their gods, leaving nothing but ashes. They saved us, but it was too late. The Empire had fallen, for too much had been destroyed. Saddened, our allies, the lords of the higher planes, left us to rebuild and restore, but as you can see, we are still living in our crumbling towns, still fighting each other like savages."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>addLore(3);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>1007</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>1006</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"Three lords of the higher planes, or the High Lords, as they are most commonly referred to, have answered our call. Gla'ath-Zor the Dreamer, Bar-Hathor the Flamewalker, and Thor-Agoth the Artificer.

"The Artificer had taught our Magi much and built many wondrous machines and engines of war. According to the legends, the Magi had attended a temple built by Thor-Agoth and studied the Arcane Art there. The centuries-old accounts describe the engines of war and 'divine' weapons in great detail.

"I don't know if the weapons are still there. I don't know if the temple is still there, but I believe there is a reason why another copy of the map has found its way to me. It's fate, &lt;charname&gt;. It has to be.

"Over the years I've sent several expeditions to find the temple and bring me the weapons of the gods. They've all failed, one way or another. Looking at you, I'm beginning to think that sending large expeditions was a mistake. Large groups attract too much attention. They are slow and suffer from the all too familiar intrigues and inner squabbles. They are vulnerable to spies and saboteurs. They cost a fortune. But one &lt;man/woman&gt;... One resourceful &lt;man/woman&gt; with nothing to lose and everything to gain... Yes, I can see my mistake now."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>addLore(4);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>1008</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>1007</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"I want you to find the temple for me, &lt;charname&gt;. If you do, you will be rewarded and elevated beyond your wildest dreams. If you do, we'll reshape the world and plant a seed of a new Empire. We'll do away with petty squabbles over broken towns and domains, we will unite our people and give them goals worthy of the banners that once flew over this land.

"Go to Maadoran. Find Domitius Ulpius. He led one of the expeditions. He was convinced that the Magi towers hold the key to the map, but there is only one tower left intact – the tower of Zamedi. The tower is sealed, as are most ancient places of wonder that House Aurelian deemed too dangerous. Gaelius would rather bury the past than face it.

"Find Domitius. If there is a way in, he'll help you find it. If not, seek answers elsewhere."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"I'll do my best, my Lord."</text>
          <def_link>1009</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>1008</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"I expect nothing less from you."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>1011</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[streetwise]"I too believe in destiny, my Lord. This ring has been in my family for generations, given to my forefathers for safekeeping by General Galbo himself. It is, without a doubt, one of the most important relics of the Empire, and its reappearance is a great omen! It is yours, my Lord."</text>
          <def_link>1010</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>1009</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"The Galbo's ring? Could it be? Send for Feng, now!"

Half an hour later Feng shows up and gives the best theatrical performance you've ever seen. If you didn't know better... Well, Antidas doesn't, besides, deep down he wants to believe. He buys the whole act and puts the ring on his finger with a shaking hand, probably expecting the ghost of General Galbo to appear and bless him.

"A ring for a ring," says Antidas. He takes off a heavy sapphire ring with the Daratan insignia and gives it to you.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>1011</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>1010</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
        <string>setRtsCam();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>1011</UID>
    </dlgPart>
  </parts>
</dlgData>