<?xml version="1.0"?>
<dlgData xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <conditions />
    <links />
    <dlg_name>END_XP_Temple_God</dlg_name>
    <def_link>9693</def_link>
    <def_speaker_name>Agathoth</def_speaker_name>
    <def_portrait>God</def_portrait>
  </header>
  <parts>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The chamber at the apex of the ziggurat has been restored to the glory of ancient days. Opulent tapestries from distant lands, gilded columns thicker than two men could encircle with their arms, braziers burning incense night and day, all is arranged to please the senses and convey wealth and power. Though your eyes water to gaze upon such riches, they are nothing compared to the glory of the God, for that is what Agathoth has become.

The God's form is encased in a suit of strange armor - glowing sigils line the arms and legs, flowing and changing as you watch - and a weighty golden mask. As a practical matter, the ornate mask conceals the tentacles cascading from his head, reducing the shock of his appearance so that the unprepared may simply grovel in terror rather than lose consciousness outright.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>useCameraBookmark(god);</string>
        <string>approachTM();</string>
        <string>dlgHideWeapons();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>9694</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9693</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Agathoth beckons with a bejeweled hand and your body traipses towards him like a puppet manipulated by a lazy child. In God’s presence, your purpose is manifest, your desires fulfilled. Among all his thousands of slaves, you are most beloved and favored. For now.

“Kneel,” the God says, a gentle reminder to a child who must learn protocol if he wishes to visit court. Strings cut, your knees buckle and your body folds until your forehead rests on the cool marble floor. You cannot rise even if you wished to, but since you do not - and will not ever - wish to, your mind remains serene and untroubled in this most perfect of all worlds.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgSetAnimation(anim_sit_getready_ground_00, 0, 1);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>9695</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9694</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Rise,” the God commands benevolently, switching his attention to your companion. “Is this the chieftain to whom the local tribes swear their allegiance?” The God's tone drops in what might be disappointment, but with the mask concealing his expression you can’t be sure. Agathoth continues with his instructions.

“From this moment forward you speak with my voice and in so doing so will grow your domain far beyond your petty ambitions. Your enemies will be swept away as leaves before a wailing wind. All who dare rise against you will fall swiftly for such is my will. Many others will serve me but you and you alone shall be the tip of my spear, the scourge of my foes.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgSetAmbientAnimation(1);</string>
        <string>dlgSetAnimation(anim_sit_relax_ground_00, 0, 1);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>9698</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.end_xp_antidas</string>
            <string>aod.end_xp_gaelius</string>
            <string>aod.end_xp_paullus</string>
            <string>aod.end_xp_miltiades</string>
            <string>aod.end_xp_meru</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>9696</int>
            <int>9701</int>
            <int>9705</int>
            <int>9709</int>
            <int>9707</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9695</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“I shall make you the absolute lord of Men. You will serve me faithfully in all things, just as your men serve you. You may rule as you see fit in matters that are beneath my notice but you will obey my word in every detail and without hesitation. When my other servants reveal themselves to you, you shall obey their orders just as you obey mine.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>9699</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9698</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“The prophecy is true,” whispers Antidas, repeating the words. “House Daratan will be restored to its former glory and rise higher than ever before.”

“Your House served me well in the past and now that I’ve returned it shall serve me again,” the God says smoothly.

“I shall make you the absolute lord of Men. You will serve me faithfully in all things, just as your men serve you. You may rule as you see fit in matters that are beneath my notice but you will obey my word in every detail and without hesitation. When my other servants reveal themselves to you, you shall obey their orders just as you obey mine.”

“Lord,” Antidas breathes out, unable to believe his luck. You aren’t sure he’s heard anything past ‘the absolute lord of Men’.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.ending_agathoth = 1;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>9697</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9696</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“A puppet,” whispers Gaelius, his hopes and dreams undone in the blink of an eye.

“A great king,” Agathoth says sternly, “ruling over the greatest empire this world has ever seen. Far greater than anything you could build on your own.

“In exchange you will serve me faithfully in all things, just as your men serve you. You may rule as you see fit in matters that are beneath my notice but you will obey my word in every detail and without hesitation. When my other servants reveal themselves to you, you shall obey their orders just as you obey mine.”

“Lord,” bows Gaelius, accepting his fate and maybe even warming up to it. Fate can do a lot worse than offering one to rule the world on someone else's behalf.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.ending_agathoth = 2;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>9702</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9701</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Paullus straightens up as if a great weight has been lifted from his shoulders. That bit about the spear and the scourge definitely got his attention.

“A warrior-king,” Agathoth nods approvingly, “who'd forge the greatest empire this world has ever seen. Far greater than anything you could do on your own.

“In exchange you will serve me faithfully in all things, just as your men serve you. You may rule as you see fit in matters that are beneath my notice but you will obey my word in every detail and without hesitation. When my other servants reveal themselves to you, you shall obey their orders just as you obey mine.”

“My men and I are yours to command, Lord,” says Paullus, snapping to attention. Well, that was an easy sell. You have a feeling that Paullus would be much happier serving Agathoth than dealing with ever unreliable nobles.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.ending_agathoth = 4;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>9706</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9705</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Meru doesn't need any convincing. He spent years dreaming of this moment, so he's probably having a hard time believing it's finally happening.

“I shall make you the absolute lord of Men,” says Agathoth. “You will serve me faithfully in all things, just as your men serve you. You may rule as you see fit in matters that are beneath my notice but you will obey my word in every detail and without hesitation. When my other servants reveal themselves to you, you shall obey their orders just as you obey mine.”

“Lord,” Meru drops on his knees without any mental push from Agathoth. “I'm thy servant, Lord!”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgSetAnimation(anim_sit_getready_ground_00, 0, 9340);</string>
        <string>aod.ending_agathoth = 3;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>9708</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9707</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Your enemies are my enemies now,” Miltiades reassures him. “Just say the word, your, um, Holiness?”

Taken aback, Agathoth glances at you. Clearly, Miltiades isn't what he expected. Then again, Miltiades isn't what anyone's ever expecting. That's why the bastard made it that far.

“I shall make you the absolute lord of Men,” says Agathoth, recovering. “You will serve me faithfully in all things, just as your men serve you. You may rule as you see fit in matters that are beneath my notice but you will obey my word in every detail and without hesitation. When my other servants reveal themselves to you, you shall obey their orders just as you obey mine.”

“I know how it works, don't worry about it,” says Miltiades. “You need a front man for your operation here. That's me. The best man for the job, hands down. I've gotta be honest, I'm getting a strong partner vibe here, but I don't want to overstep any bounds...”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.ending_agathoth = 7;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>9710</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9709</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Moving with unnatural grace, two men step forward and flank you. Under normal circumstances you’d find their unblinking, vacant gaze disturbing but there’s nothing normal about these circumstances.

“My servants will take you back and see to your safety. Keep them close for they will give their lives to protect you,” commands Agathoth. “Your first task is to raise a great army...”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>flankGuards();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>It's the dawn of a new age [and the end of your adventure].</text>
          <def_link>9700</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9699</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Moving with unnatural grace, two men step forward and flank Antidas. Under normal circumstances you’d find their unblinking, vacant gaze disturbing but there’s nothing normal about these circumstances.

“My servants will take you back and see to your safety. Keep them close for they will give their lives to protect you,” commands Agathoth. “Your first task is to raise a great army...”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>flankGuards();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>It's the dawn of a new age [and the end of your adventure].</text>
          <def_link>9700</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9697</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Moving with unnatural grace, two men step forward and flank Gaelius. Under normal circumstances you’d find their unblinking, vacant gaze disturbing but there’s nothing normal about these circumstances.

“My servants will take you back and see to your safety. Keep them close for they will give their lives to protect you,” commands Agathoth. “Your first task is to raise a great army...”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>flankGuards();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>It's the dawn of a new age [and the end of your adventure].</text>
          <def_link>9700</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9702</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Moving with unnatural grace, two men step forward and flank Paullus. Under normal circumstances you’d find their unblinking, vacant gaze disturbing but there’s nothing normal about these circumstances.

“My servants will take you back and see to your safety. Keep them close for they will give their lives to protect you,” commands Agathoth. “Your first task is to raise a great army...”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>flankGuards();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>It's the dawn of a new age [and the end of your adventure].</text>
          <def_link>9700</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9706</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Moving with unnatural grace, two men step forward and flank Meru. Under normal circumstances you’d find their unblinking, vacant gaze disturbing but there’s nothing normal about these circumstances.

“My servants will take you back and see to your safety. Keep them close for they will give their lives to protect you,” commands Agathoth. “Your first task is to raise a great army...”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>flankGuards();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>It's the dawn of a new age [and the end of your adventure].</text>
          <def_link>9700</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9708</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Moving with unnatural grace, two men step forward and flank Miltiades. Under normal circumstances you’d find their unblinking, vacant gaze disturbing but there’s nothing normal about these circumstances.

“My servants will take you back and see to your safety. Keep them close for they will give their lives to protect you,” commands Agathoth. “Your first task is to raise a great army...”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>flankGuards();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>It's the dawn of a new age [and the end of your adventure].</text>
          <def_link>9700</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9710</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>ENDING</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeLongToThisPart();</string>
        <string>SS_start("temple_ending", "disconnect();");</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>9700</UID>
    </dlgPart>
  </parts>
</dlgData>