<?xml version="1.0"?>
<dlgData xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <conditions>
      <string>aod.npc_brontia_met</string>
    </conditions>
    <links>
      <int>9409</int>
    </links>
    <dlg_name>Filler_NPC_Brontia</dlg_name>
    <def_link>9389</def_link>
    <def_speaker_name>Brontia</def_speaker_name>
    <def_portrait>None</def_portrait>
  </header>
  <parts>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>A middle-aged woman in simple, well worn street clothes sits cross legged on the ground under the shade of a tree. She chews on a crust of bread, pausing occasionally to consider a small stone or speck of debris on the ground before casually brushing it away. A few people mill lazily about, clearly waiting for something.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_brontia_met = true;</string>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_DLG_Brontia);</string>
        <string>dlgCam(345, 45, 6, 601);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“What's going on?”</text>
          <def_link>9390</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>9392</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9389</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name>Bystander</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>“We're waiting to hear Brontia speak.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“What does she speak of?”</text>
          <def_link>9391</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9390</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name>Bystander</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>“Many things. She seems to be a wise woman but claims to be unwise. Either way, her words are interesting to ponder.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Approach Brontia. “You have a patient crowd. What do you do here, woman?”</text>
          <def_link>9393</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>9392</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9391</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
        <string>dlgCam(345, 45, 12);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>9392</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The small crowd watches you approach, drawing quiet and attentive. “I eat,” she says casually, finishing her last bite.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Now what do you do?”</text>
          <def_link>9394</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9393</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>She smiles and nods. “Now I seek a morsel more filling than bread. I look for wise men and women so that I may learn from them and know true wisdom. Are you a wise &lt;man/woman&gt;?”

The few people that have gathered to listen close in a little to better hear the conversation.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“I have seen much and learned much. What would you like to understand?”</text>
          <def_link>9395</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Hopefully I’m wiser than I was yesterday and will be wiser still tomorrow. That’s about all that I can claim.”</text>
          <def_link>9396</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Me? Hardly.”</text>
          <def_link>9396</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9394</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“So far, all that I truly understand is that I know very little. Yet I have found few that are even this wise. Either you have found some true understanding or you are still ignorant of your ignorance. Let me ask you, many common folk complain about the harshness of the world around them and how it is made worse by evil men. What do you think of this?”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“I agree, it is a harsh world and most folks would sooner steal from you or double cross you than allow you to have a little for your own. Evil men for dark times.”</text>
          <def_link>9397</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“It’s a harsh world but people do what they have to do to survive. It’s hard to keep your hands clean in times like these, even for the best of folks.”</text>
          <def_link>9399</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“It is what it is. At the end of the day, we’re all looking out for ourselves. I call it livin’.”</text>
          <def_link>9400</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9395</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Aha! Like me, you are wise enough to see how little you truly understand. You and I are lucky to have figured this much out. Many that would claim to be wise haven’t even gotten this far. Let me ask you, many common folk complain about the harshness of the world around them and how it is made worse by evil men. What do you think of this?”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“I agree, it is a harsh world and most folks would sooner steal from you or double cross you than allow you to have a little for your own. Evil men for dark times.”</text>
          <def_link>9397</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“It’s a harsh world but people do what they have to do to survive. It’s hard to keep your hands clean in times like these, even for the best of folks.”</text>
          <def_link>9399</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“It is what it is. At the end of the day, we’re all looking out for ourselves. I call it livin’.”</text>
          <def_link>9400</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9396</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>She stands and begins to address the group as a whole. “Earlier I overheard a man in great distress, retelling how he had been set upon by thugs and robbed of his worth. He too claimed that our world was an evil place, filled with evil men. And I have spent some thought on this notion of an evil man. I ask, is a man evil because he takes from another? Consider the wolf and hawk, how violently they take from the world around them. Yet do we call them evil?”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"No reasonable person would. They take or they die."</text>
          <def_link>9398</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"If we were a gathering of hares I'd wager this conversation would take a different direction."</text>
          <def_link>9401</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9397</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>She stands and begins to address the group as a whole. “We do what we have to do to survive. Earlier I overheard a man in great distress, retelling how he had been set upon by thugs and robbed of his worth. He too claimed that our world was an evil place, filled with evil men. He certainly was not relieved that the thugs would be eating well that evening. But I have spent some thought on this notion of an evil man. I ask, is a man evil because he takes from another? Consider the wolf and hawk, how violently they take from the world around them. Yet do we call them evil?”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"No reasonable person would. They take or they die."</text>
          <def_link>9398</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"If we were a gathering of hares I'd wager this conversation would take a different direction."</text>
          <def_link>9401</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9399</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>She stands and begins to address the group as a whole. “Maybe this is wisdom. We look out for ourselves, do what we must. Earlier I overheard a man in great distress, retelling how he had been set upon by thugs and robbed of his worth. He was not so forgiving. He too claimed that our world was an evil place, filled with evil men. And I have spent some thought on this notion of an evil man. I ask, is a man evil because he takes from another? Consider the wolf and hawk, how violently they take from the world around them. Yet do we call them evil?”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"No reasonable person would. They take or they die."</text>
          <def_link>9398</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"If we were a gathering of hares I'd wager this conversation would take a different direction."</text>
          <def_link>9401</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9400</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The group murmurs and nods its agreement. Brontia replies, “Yes! Yes! And so I wonder, are we as people so very far beyond the law of tooth and claw in this age? It has struck me that we live by our own nature as assuredly as do the wild beasts. And it is in every living being’s best interest to act in a way that most benefits itself. If the option is available to prey upon our fellows, many will take that choice in an effort to gain some boon to their own well being. This holds true from the most petty burglary to the grandest of political schemes. Is it evil? I would call it ignorant.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“But how often do the wild beasts take in excess? Or purely for pleasure? There are men and women who take from those around them far more than they need for their own survival. Be they bandits or nobles.”</text>
          <def_link>9402</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“What about acts of selflessness? Generosity? Not everyone always acts in their own self interest.”</text>
          <def_link>9403</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Why ignorant?”</text>
          <def_link>9404</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9398</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The group chuckles as Brontia considers your words. “Perhaps. But we are not hares, we are creatures of reason. And we can understand that every creature is ultimately out for its own survival. Its own well being. The law of tooth and claw. And so I wonder, are we as people so very far beyond the law of tooth and claw in this age? It has struck me that we live by our own nature as assuredly as do the wild beasts. If the option is available to prey upon our fellows, many will take that choice in an effort to gain some boon to their own well being. This holds true from the most petty burglary to the grandest of political schemes. Is it evil? I would call it ignorant.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“But how often do the wild beasts take in excess? Or purely for pleasure? There are men and women who take from those around them far more than they need for their own survival. Be they bandits or nobles.”</text>
          <def_link>9402</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“What about acts of selflessness? Generosity? Not everyone always acts in their own self interest.”</text>
          <def_link>9403</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Why ignorant?”</text>
          <def_link>9404</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9401</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>A fellow standing near you murmurs, “This is true, this is true.” Brontia merely shrugs. “Most of you take too much of everything every day. It's our desire to store up for tomorrow that drives us to greed. If anything, there is the great evil amongst you. It drives you to always want for more and live in fear of having too little. Better to live like me. I sleep wherever I’d like each day, eat wherever I’d like, love wherever I’d like. This is the path to true happiness.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Some folks would call that living like a dog. And many of them are barely living much better.”</text>
          <def_link>9405</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9402</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“And where are these selfless acts?” She grins and passes her open, upturned hand around to each of you. One man presses a humble coin into her palm which she immediately pockets. She good naturedly whips an accusatory finger around to the crowd, “I have still yet to see one! You paid for my teaching in hopes I’d return tomorrow. But even the most generous action has at its core a seed of self satisfaction. The doer of good deeds at the very least is seeking their own reward of feeling good about what they have done. They want to feel that. Or at worst, they do it so as to not have to lay down at night and feel the guilt of not helping. All deeds serve the self.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“You said earlier that taking advantage of those around us isn’t evil but ignorant. How so?”</text>
          <def_link>9404</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9403</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Because they fail to see that by preying upon those around them they are more likely to have the same done to them at some point. A wise people would understand that our nature is to self serve. But with reflection understand that if we all seek to help ourselves, even at the expense of those around us, we all stand to suffer at the hand of each other. And not wanting to suffer, we can as a whole, be more prudent in the way we live our lives. We can choose not to inflict suffering, knowing that those around us also forgo this course.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“We are not a wise people.”</text>
          <def_link>9406</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“It’s an interesting philosophy but it can never work. Requires too much mutual trust. And it only takes one asshole to break it all. It’s best to just go ahead and be the asshole.”</text>
          <def_link>9408</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9404</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“I say we should all live *more* like dogs! Look at the street mutts. They manage enough food here and there, they play, they sleep. That is their way, every day. We should all be so fortunate.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“You say that we all act for our own best interest. What about acts of selflessness? Generosity? Not everyone always acts in favor of themselves.”</text>
          <def_link>9403</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“You said earlier that taking advantage of those around us isn’t evil but ignorant. How so?”</text>
          <def_link>9404</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9405</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Brontia nods grimly. “I agree. And it may be unrealistic but I wonder if strong leadership could bring that to us. But for now, tooth and claw in a time of ignorance. May you all come to live as I do, like a dog in the street. For there is no happiness in the sorting of the wolves and hares.”

She returns to the shade of a tree and settles into a napping position.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgSetAnimation(anim_sit_ground_00_00, 0, 601);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>9392</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9406</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Brontia sighs. “You may be right. And for now, tooth and claw in a time of ignorance. May you all come to live as I do, like a dog in the street. For there is no happiness in the sorting of the wolves and hares.”

She returns to the shade of a tree and settles into a napping position.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgSetAnimation(anim_sit_ground_00_00, 0, 601);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>9392</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9408</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The woman is preoccupied with her thoughts.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_DLG_Brontia);</string>
        <string>dlgCam(345, 45, 6, 601);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>9392</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9409</UID>
    </dlgPart>
  </parts>
</dlgData>