<?xml version="1.0"?>
<dlgData xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <conditions />
    <links />
    <dlg_name>GNZ_NPC_preacher_01</dlg_name>
    <def_link>8335</def_link>
    <def_speaker_name>Preacher</def_speaker_name>
    <def_portrait>None</def_portrait>
  </header>
  <parts>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>You step into an old, crumbling temple, open to the elements and passerby, joining a crowd waiting for today’s sermon. The preacher – a bearded man with the fiery eyes of a true believer and the mannerisms of a whoremaster – appears shortly after.

He parts the crowd with a practiced ease, making his way to the podium.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>createByCharMarker("CM_Preacher");</string>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_TemplePreacher_PC);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Wait.</text>
          <def_link>8337</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>8336</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8335</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>dlgDeleteCharacter(9008);</string>
        <string>dlgFadeToThisPart();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>8336</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“It’s humbling to see so many people,” says the preacher, his voice smooth and sincere, “so let’s speak of humility today.

“I’m often asked why Brother Meru has renounced his Lordship. What is the significance of this act? Why was it even necessary when we all wholeheartedly accept Brother Meru as our shepherd?”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Keep listening.</text>
          <def_link>8338</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8337</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“It is said,” says the preacher, his voice flowing like water, “humble yourself in the sight of the Gods and they shall lift you up.

“They. Shall. Lift. You. Up,” says the preacher as if stating something profoundly obvious. “Any man who lifts himself up, any man who puts a crown on his head, any man who raises himself above others is putting himself above the Gods, for he says that he doesn’t need the Gods. He says that he knows better.

“That’s why the Gods left us to our fate. Ignorant in their pride... in their arrogance, our forefathers told the Gods that they knew better. The Gods could have chosen to smite them all, but they didn’t. Had they done it, we’d all be living in the Kingdom of the Gods now but we HAD to learn this lesson, no matter how painful it’s proven to be.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Keep listening.</text>
          <def_link>8339</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>8336</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8338</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“The path to the Gods’ Kingdom lies in submission. We must submit to the will of the Gods for this humble act is the very foundation of it.

“Brother Meru proved it when he renounced his earthly title and removed the crown made of gold, for neither was given to him by the Gods. He kneeled in front of the divine and submitted himself to the Gods’ will, begging to be judged, for no man is above the Gods. No man can rule others because the kingship can only come from the Gods.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Keep listening.</text>
          <def_link>8340</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8339</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“When the Gods return, it will be too late to beg for forgiveness and make amends. When the Gods return, we’ll be judged. The wheat will be separated from the chaff.

“The false lords and false prophets will be held accountable, but so will those who followed them, out of fear or ignorance. Discard your pride, brothers and sisters. Have faith in the Gods. Submit to their will and show them that you’re worthy of being admitted into the Gods’ Kingdom.

“Time is running out. Don’t waste even an hour that can be dedicated to earning your salvation.”

The preacher walks away before you can ask him any questions.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>rwd_reputation(GNZ_TemplePreacher_01);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>8336</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8340</UID>
    </dlgPart>
  </parts>
</dlgData>