<?xml version="1.0"?>
<dlgData xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <conditions>
      <string>aod.npc_gnz_philosopher_met</string>
    </conditions>
    <links>
      <int>8338</int>
    </links>
    <dlg_name>GNZ_NPC_philosopher_01</dlg_name>
    <def_link>8335</def_link>
    <def_speaker_name>Philosopher</def_speaker_name>
    <def_portrait>None</def_portrait>
  </header>
  <parts>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>You see a street philosopher-turned-preacher attempting to educate his flock on the subject of gods and demons. Fortunately, you missed most of the sermon.

“If the Gods were all-powerful, why did they battle the Demons for years, laying waste to cities and countryside alike?” asks the preacher, raising his voice dramatically. “Why couldn’t they destroy them outright?”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Keep listening.</text>
          <def_link>8336</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Walk away.</text>
          <def_link>8337</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8335</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Because the Gods and the Demons are two sides of the same divine coin,” says the preacher, proudly presenting his theory and triumphantly glancing around.

“The accursed Qantari had reached into the void and brought forth those who dwell in eternal darkness and their number was four. Four is a symbol of chaos, of separation, of dispersal into four directions. It’s a symbol of banishment!”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_gnz_philosopher_met = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Keep listening.</text>
          <def_link>8339</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8336</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“What chance did mankind stand against these Lords of Chaos? None! We would have been killed or enslaved, cast into eternal darkness, but the Gods would have none of it. They came to our aid and their number was three.

“Three is the holiest of numbers for it symbolizes life. Birth, life, and death. Body, mind, and spirit. Creation, destruction, and preservation. It symbolizes unity for the three Gods united were infinitely more powerful than the four Demons whose number symbolizes separation. Thus in the end each Demon stood alone and that was their downfall.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“You said that the Gods and Demons were two sides of the same coin. What did you mean by that?”</text>
          <def_link>8340</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8339</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Their origin was the same and their number was seven – the number of the universe and a symbol of completeness. There are seven days in a week, seven rays of the sun, seven pillars of wisdom, and seven musical notes.

“Seven divine beings representing the trinity of all things and the four elements.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Clearly, you know your numbers. What do you know about the Gods and Demons that isn’t common knowledge?”</text>
          <def_link>8341</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8340</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“I know a-plenty,” says the philosopher defensively, “but my knowledge isn’t for the likes of you.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“What do you know about the one called Balzaar?”</text>
          <def_link>8342</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>8337</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8341</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Baal-Zurath? According to the stories, he is the Chief of the Demons.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“What makes him the Chief if the Demons were divided and represented different directions?”</text>
          <def_link>8343</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8342</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Well, the numbers say one thing, the stories another, but the numerology is the exact science whereas stories are nothing but hearsay. So believe what you will.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“What about the Artificer?”</text>
          <def_link>8344</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>8337</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8343</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“He was the cleverest amongst the Gods. Some stories say that Baal-Zurath was the first to enter our realm and the first to rebel against the Magi, challenging the First of the Magi himself. Other stories say that it was the Artificer who rebelled against Baal-Zurath and brought his downfall.

“And then you wonder why I don’t put much stock in stories.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Alright, so what do the numbers tell you?”</text>
          <def_link>8345</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8344</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“The numbers don’t lie,” says the philosopher, excited by the prospect of educating you. “Three and four don’t make six or eight, no matter how many times the equation is repeated. They always make seven. The very fact that seven was split into three and four tells us that there was a division amongst the Gods.

“Seven can’t be split into two and five because two can’t resist five, but three and four? These are strong numbers, plenty of power in them. It was the three that split from the seven, not the other way around.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Why did they split?”</text>
          <def_link>8346</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8345</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“The numbers are silent on the motives. The stories don’t say much on this topic either. All we know is that the Three who did split served the Old Empire and were strong enough to defeat the Four.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Only to disappear after.”</text>
          <def_link>8347</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8346</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Can you imagine a coin with only one side, &lt;brother/sister&gt;? Two sides, same coin.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>8337</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8347</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>8337</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The philosopher appears to be busy.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>8337</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8338</UID>
    </dlgPart>
  </parts>
</dlgData>