<?xml version="1.0"?>
<dlgData xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <conditions>
      <string>aod.GNZ_npc_loremaster_talked</string>
    </conditions>
    <links>
      <int>7780</int>
    </links>
    <dlg_name>GNZ_NPC_loremaster_01</dlg_name>
    <def_link>7774</def_link>
    <def_speaker_name>Loremaster</def_speaker_name>
    <def_portrait>None</def_portrait>
  </header>
  <parts>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name>Young man</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>You see a young man having a heated argument with an old loremaster.

“A story I’ve heard says these gods of yours were created,” a young man says stubbornly. “The Magi made them!”

One of the patrons curses and reaches for his dagger, but the loremaster stops him with an authoritative gesture.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>7775</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>7774</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Created?” asks the loremaster with disdain. “Do you create an oak when you plant an acorn? Or do you merely pray for it to find the soil fertile enough and sprout?

“The Magi found a way to plant seeds containing the divine essence into mortal men, who were humbled by the honor! The Magi, wise as they were, created neither the Gods nor the divine essence that was used in the ritual. Banish such thoughts for they are nothing but blasphemy that will get you killed.”

He nods at the patron still clutching his dagger.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Say nothing – you’ll live longer.</text>
          <def_link>7778</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“What makes you think the essence was divine, brother?”</text>
          <def_link>7777</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Walk away.</text>
          <def_link>7776</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>7775</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>aod.GNZ_npc_loremaster_talked = true;</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
        <string>dlgDeleteCharacter(9054);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>7776</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name>None</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>The loremaster glares at you but says nothing.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>7776</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>7780</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name>Young man</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>“I didn’t mean anything,” the young man says quickly, taking a step back. “I told you what I’ve heard, that’s all.”

“That’s all?” the loremaster says gravely. “You’re spreading lies and giving offence to the good people of this city. Giving offense to the Gods. Do you know what the punishment for such crimes is?”

“Please,” says the young man pleadingly. “I’ll do anything...”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>7779</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>7778</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name>Loremaster</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>“Anything?” the loremaster says thoughtfully as if such an outcome has never occurred to him until the youth mentioned it. “In your ignorance, you spread lies and rumors. It’s only fitting if you make amends by spreading the teaching of Brother Meru and bringing light to the hearts of your fellow men.”

“I’ll do it!” the youth says quickly as if afraid that the loremaster will change his mind. “Just tell me what to say.”

Pleased, the loremaster tells the young man to follow him and walks away.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Wait for them to leave.</text>
          <def_link>7789</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>7779</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END - they leave</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>aod.GNZ_npc_loremaster_talked = true;</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
        <string>dlgDeleteCharacter(9054);</string>
        <string>dlgDeleteCharacter(9053);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>7789</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Your words take the loremaster aback. He eyes you with a contemptuous look, then says, “What other essence could it have been?”

It’s a good starting tactic – let your opponent do the talking and bury &lt;himself/herself&gt; while you poke holes in &lt;his/her&gt; arguments.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Well, there was a lot of talk about the Qantari demons...”</text>
          <def_link>7781</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“We don’t know. We don’t know what exactly the Magi brought to our plane. You said the essence was divine yet what proof do you offer?”</text>
          <def_link>7782</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>7777</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“And you’re wondering if the essence was of the demonic rather than divine nature?” says the loremaster with a scoff. “It is a well-known fact that the Qantari summoned demons, using their own rituals. A lesser mind,” he casts a glance in your direction, “might think that the essence was the same, but &lt;he/she&gt; would be very much mistaken.

“The Qantari demons were misshapen beasts, terrifying and frightening – nightmares given form. Our Gods were human in appearance, noble and inspiring. Would you claim that the Moon and the Sun are of the same nature, simply because both are celestial bodies? Then why do you claim that Gods and Demons are one and the same?

“Furthermore, even a child knows that the Gods who came to our aid defeated the Demons and cast them into the abyss. Why would they fight each other if they were on the same side?”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Men quarrel and fight among each other all the time. Why do you expect otherworldly beings to be any different? Do they not know anger, desire, ambitions?”</text>
          <def_link>7786</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Why did they come to our aid and leave so abruptly, leaving nothing but ruins behind? We’re told it’s because we turned our backs on them which tells us nothing.”</text>
          <def_link>7786</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>7781</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Thread carefully, unbeliever,” the loremaster warns you, his thick eyebrows moving closer, reflecting his growing concern.

“The Gods came to our aid, fought for us, *bled* for us, yet they couldn’t be killed by mortal weapons. Immortality is the highest proof of the divine nature of our Allies, for no mortal creature, no matter how big and ferocious, can cheat death.

“Many times our noble Allies were grievously wounded and had to be carried away from the battlefield only to return days later, their vigor renewed, their strength restored. What have you to say to that?”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“All the more reasons to be careful. Should they return, we will not be able to stop them.”</text>
          <def_link>7788</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Why did they come to our aid and leave so abruptly, leaving nothing but ruins behind? We’re told it’s because we turned our backs on them which tells us nothing.”</text>
          <def_link>7786</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>7782</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“What makes you think that your mind – limited and finite – can understand the Gods who are incomprehensible and infinite? Your arrogance must be bottomless if you presume to be capable of such a feat.

“You don’t need to understand the Sun to accept its light and warmth. You don’t need to understand the Gods to accept their love and guidance.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Are you sure that love and guidance are what they have in store for us?”</text>
          <def_link>7787</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>7786</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“What are you saying, unbeliever?” asks the loremaster, his thick eyebrows moving closer, reflecting his growing concern.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“What if these god-like beings aren’t benevolent and righteous but malevolent and evil?”</text>
          <def_link>7788</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>7787</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The loremaster stares at you for a while, his distaste written on his face.

“A thief thinks every man steals. A cunning and deceitful &lt;man/woman&gt; wonders if the Gods are cunning and deceitful. A liar thinks that the Gods can’t be trusted. Your questions reflect your nature, unbeliever. Be on your way.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>7776</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>7788</UID>
    </dlgPart>
  </parts>
</dlgData>