<?xml version="1.0"?>
<dlgData xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <conditions>
      <string>aod.npc_zealot_skulls_met</string>
    </conditions>
    <links>
      <int>8084</int>
    </links>
    <dlg_name>GNZ_NPC_Zealot_01</dlg_name>
    <def_link>8082</def_link>
    <def_speaker_name>Zealot</def_speaker_name>
    <def_portrait>None</def_portrait>
  </header>
  <parts>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Don’t suffer an unbeliever to live,” exclaims a man standing in front of the row of crosses, “for he is the enemy of the Gods! His very existence is an affront! A breath he draws is an insult for it pollutes the air in this Holy City! His wickedness –”

He notices you and stops mid-sentence.

“I haven’t seen you before,” he says slowly, as if that alone were a chargeable offense. “Where do you stand on the matters of faith,” he asks casually, trying to sound indifferent and edging forward like a predator getting ready to pounce.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_zealot_skulls_met = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“I follow the teachings of Brother Meru. I came to Ganezzar to hear him speak.”</text>
          <def_link>8086</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Take another step and I’ll cut your throat from ear to ear.”</text>
          <def_link>8083</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8082</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The man recoils in shock but quickly composes himself, switching his attention to another passerby.

“Don’t suffer an unbeliever to live,” he shouts angrily, casting a murderous look at you.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>rwd_reputation(GNZ_Zealot_02);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>8085</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8083</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“May the Gods watch over you, &lt;brother/sister&gt;,” says the man, instantly warming up toward you.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>rwd_reputation(GNZ_Zealot_01);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“What’s that? A pillar of skulls?”</text>
          <def_link>8087</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8086</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Heads of the unbelievers,” says the man proudly. “This here,” he picks up the top skull, “is Aicken. He called the words of Brother Meru ill-invented nonsense. Nonsense! Can you believe that? Then he went on and on, saying that it was stuffed with madness, nonsense, and contradictions.” The man shakes his head sadly.

“Of course he changed his mind when we nailed him to a cross. He said his circumstances were deplorable. As if it’s some kinda excuse.” The man lovingly pats the skull before putting it back.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Are there a lot of unbelievers here?”</text>
          <def_link>8088</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“How long have you been crucifying the unbelievers?”</text>
          <def_link>8089</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8087</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Not as many as there used to be,” says the man, gesturing at the crosses, “but some rot still remains. I can smell it,” he taps on his nose for emphasis.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“How long have you been crucifying the unbelievers?”</text>
          <def_link>8089</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8088</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“For quite a while,” says the man with pride. “And it all started here in Lowtown. We’ve been petitioning Brother Meru to do something about the unbelievers for a long time but to no avail. He probably thought it was too harsh a punishment or hoped that his sermons would do the trick.

“Well, one day we had enough. Some poor bastard had too much wine and started telling us that it was all horseshit. He dared the Gods to strike him down where he stood if he was making it up. Guess what, the Gods don’t need to reach out all the way down here to swat him like a fly, not when they have the righteous men like us.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“So you put him on a cross?”</text>
          <def_link>8090</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8089</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Damn right we did and guess what? Not a word from the city watch. None! So the next night we got three more of these bastards. Nailed them right to give them plenty of time to think about what they said and shout how sorry they were for the entire city to hear.

“After a couple of months you couldn’t find an unbeliever even if you look all day, but like I said, I know some rot is still there. We’ll get them, don’t you worry.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“The guards are staying out of your way then?”</text>
          <def_link>8091</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8090</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“You could say that, so maybe Brother Meru did hear our prayers after all.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“What’s he like, Brother Meru?”</text>
          <def_link>8092</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8091</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“He’s like a father to us all. Gave up his lordship because he knows we’re all equal in the Gods’ eyes and no man should lord over another. It’s not right,” the man shakes his head vigorously.

“When the Gods return, they’re gonna hold a court and ask everyone who broke their laws and raised themselves above their fellow men. Oh yes, there will be a reckoning, you’ll see.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>8085</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8092</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>8085</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The zealot is busy talking to other people.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>8085</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8084</UID>
    </dlgPart>
  </parts>
</dlgData>