<?xml version="1.0"?>
<dlgData xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <conditions>
      <string>aod.npc_gnz_clerk01_met</string>
    </conditions>
    <links>
      <int>8276</int>
    </links>
    <dlg_name>GNZ_NPC_Clerk_01</dlg_name>
    <def_link>8273</def_link>
    <def_speaker_name>Clerk</def_speaker_name>
    <def_portrait>None</def_portrait>
  </header>
  <parts>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>A bored clerk looks at you with empty eyes.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_gnz_clerk01_met = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“How’s business?”</text>
          <def_link>8274</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.npc_meru_dead</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>8281</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8273</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Slow,” says the clerk. “The zealots frown upon everything you can make money on. Moneylending is the biggest sin, apparently. Not the lending itself, obviously, but charging the interest and collecting collaterals. They want Meru to forbid anyone from engaging in usury, as they call it.

“A year ago I would have laughed at it but now?” He shrugs.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“That bad, eh?”</text>
          <def_link>8277</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8274</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Slow,” says the clerk. “The zealots frown upon everything you can make money on. Moneylending is the biggest sin, apparently. Not the lending itself, obviously, but charging the interest and collecting collaterals. They wanted Meru forbade anyone from engaging in usury, as they call it.

“A year ago I would have laughed at it but now I hope it will change after his death.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“What else is a sin?”</text>
          <def_link>8278</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8281</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>8275</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“If I keep talking to you, I'll be out of a job faster than I can blink.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>8275</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8276</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“They’re buying what Meru is selling so fast he can’t keep up with the demand.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“What else is a sin?”</text>
          <def_link>8278</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8277</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“They aren’t picky – whatever rubs them the wrong way is a sin. Just the other day, we got a shipment of grain. Before we even had a chance to unload it, one of *them* shows up and asks what the grain is for, as if it’s any of his business.

“I know better than to argue with them, so I tell him that the grain is for the good people of Ganezzar and that we’ll sell it at cost because we refuse to make money when people are hungry. Obviously, nobody knows what our costs are and we *have* to make a profit, otherwise what’s the point? Still, it’s a good line and you’d think it would buy us some goodwill, right? Wrong!

“He stares at me for a while and then says that those who sell food to the hungry are no better than vultures and rats. Can you believe this shit? He said the Gods won’t suffer it, meaning these fuckers won’t suffer it, meaning they will come at night and burn our warehouse down.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“So what did you do?”</text>
          <def_link>8279</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8278</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“I passed the message on to Athanasius. He *blinked* and told me to give away the grain in Lowtown. He thinks he can buy their goodwill, but the truth is, he can’t. He will never be one of them because he isn’t dirt-poor.

“All it does is set a bad precedent. Now they will expect us to feed and clothe them because the Gods say so.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“I thought everyone was a believer here.”</text>
          <def_link>8280</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.npc_meru_dead</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>8282</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8279</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Some people believe or want to believe. Others fake it. We’re sort of stuck between the castle where this madness is coming from and Lowtown providing the most fertile soil for it. Adapt or die, as they say.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>8275</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8280</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Some people believe or want to believe. Others fake it. We’re sort of stuck between the castle where this madness was come from and Lowtown provided the most fertile soil for it. Adapt or die, as they say.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>8275</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8282</UID>
    </dlgPart>
  </parts>
</dlgData>