<?xml version="1.0"?>
<dlgData xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <conditions>
      <string>aod.npc_gnz_annalist_met</string>
    </conditions>
    <links>
      <int>8524</int>
    </links>
    <dlg_name>GNZ_NPC_annalist_01</dlg_name>
    <def_link>8509</def_link>
    <def_speaker_name>Annalist</def_speaker_name>
    <def_portrait>None</def_portrait>
  </header>
  <parts>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name>Blind man</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>You see a blind man sitting on a bench. He appears to be oblivious to everything, simply enjoying the warm day.

“Beautiful day, isn’t it?” says the blind, turning his head in your direction when you approach. “First time in Ganezzar?”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_gnz_annalist_met = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“How can you tell?”</text>
          <def_link>8510</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8509</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name>Blind man</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>“Who else would approach a blind man to ask for directions?”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“The locals leave you alone?”</text>
          <def_link>8511</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8510</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“I’m an annalist. *Was* an annalist,” sighs the man, “before I lost my sight. Fortunately, I don’t have to earn my meals telling stories in taverns, so I just sit outside and enjoy the warm breeze. I didn’t have time for such things before, but now I have all the time in the world.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“What did you work on before you lost your sight?”</text>
          <def_link>8512</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8511</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“I tried to trace the history of House Crassus, which proved to be a daunting task. They say the Old Empire had three pillars and House Crassus was one of them. None of the other Houses can claim this honor.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Do you know the House’s origins?”</text>
          <def_link>8513</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8512</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“I know what the stories say, which is as good as it gets these days. Of course, most of these stories come from House Crassus’ archives, so make what you will of them.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“So what do these stories say?”</text>
          <def_link>8514</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8513</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“They say that House Crassus was founded by Gaius Valerius Crassus – a military tribune with consular powers and unparalleled vision. It was him who turned the Magi into a powerful Order and it was that Order that turned an upstart kingdom into a mighty empire.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“So this Crassus character created the Magi *and* the Old Empire?”</text>
          <def_link>8515</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8514</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“I told you the source of the stories,” says the blind annalist, looking annoyed. “I wouldn’t be surprised if the stories claimed that Crassus created the Sun and the Moon too. Still, the story isn’t as outrageous as you might think, but if you have better things to do...”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Alright, go on.”</text>
          <def_link>8517</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>8516</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8515</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>8516</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Of course, the Magi were there long before Lord Crassus set his gaze upon them, but akin to today’s loremasters, they worked alone, serving kings and city-states as viziers and protectors. They wielded power, of course, but it was limited, for each man hoarded his secrets and took them to his grave. With me so far?”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Yes, continue.”</text>
          <def_link>8519</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“The Magi, what were they?”</text>
          <def_link>8518</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8517</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“The stories say that the Magi were all things: engineers, astronomers, thaumaturgists, mathematicians, and practitioners of the esoteric arts. They were men of science.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Continue.”</text>
          <def_link>8519</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8518</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“One day Crassus was summoned before the King. Seeing that a man in front of him was destined for great things, as the story claims, the King gave him three legions and charged him with taking a ‘city of evildoers and temple-robbers’, which had resisted all attempts to take it for many a decade.

“Crassus marched there without delay, laid siege to the city and eventually prevailed, but not before losing an entire legion to Hellfyre conjured by the magus of the city. Unfortunately, the city was never named, because it was razed to the ground, the land salted, and its name stricken from the records.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Hellfyre?”</text>
          <def_link>8520</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“What happened next?”</text>
          <def_link>8521</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8519</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“The word’s fairly common in the stories, but it often describes completely different things. It’s possible that the hellfyre Crassus had witnessed was what we call liquid fire. Hellfyre mentioned in the Great War’s accounts appears to be something far more potent and devastating.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“So what happened next?”</text>
          <def_link>8521</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8520</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Crassus was so impressed with the Hellfyre demonstration that he had the magus captured at great cost and made a deal with him. The magus would work for him and in exchange Crassus would hand him all magi he would capture in his campaign, as well their notes and devices.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“And that’s how it all started?”</text>
          <def_link>8522</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8521</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Simple enough for me to believe it,” nods the annalist. “When it comes to things that seem simple today, it’s easy to look back and wonder why Crassus was the first who did it. Maybe he was the first and maybe he wasn’t. Maybe he prevailed where others have failed. Maybe the magus he captured first was the key to the whole thing.

“What we do know is that Crassus’ campaign lasted for seven years. He captured many cities and many magi. Not every magus was taken alive and not every magus was of value or was willing to submit to the self-proclaimed High Magus, but many magi had embraced the new Order.

“As the Order’s power grew, Crassus began to rely more on the Magi than on his own soldiers. Soon he started going after cities that offered neither valuable resources nor riches but arcane secrets.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“He could have been king.”</text>
          <def_link>8523</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8522</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Maybe,” says the annalist. “But Crassus was after a different kind of power. He served the King loyally and in exchange he was given domain over all things arcane. The Order he created was never seen as a threat but as one of the most potent weapons of the Old Empire.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“So what was the relationship between House Crassus and the Order of Magi?”</text>
          <def_link>8525</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>8516</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8523</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name>None</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>The man doesn't respond, lost in his thoughts.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>8516</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8524</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“The Order was Crassus’ responsibility. Since it was too much for one man to oversee, a new House bearing his name was established and entrusted with continuing the work Crassus started. In a sense, House Crassus was built around the Order of Magi, both to protect the Order from its enemies and the Empire from the Order.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Someone had to hold the other end of the leash?”</text>
          <def_link>8526</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8525</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Quite so,” says the annalist. “And now if you’ll excuse me, I have other matters to contemplate on.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>8516</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8526</UID>
    </dlgPart>
  </parts>
</dlgData>