<?xml version="1.0"?>
<dlgData xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <conditions />
    <links />
    <dlg_name>GNZ_Archive_Scrolls_01</dlg_name>
    <def_link>0</def_link>
    <def_speaker_name>None</def_speaker_name>
    <def_portrait>None</def_portrait>
  </header>
  <parts>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The library is filled with scrolls – a desperate but ultimately misguided effort to preserve pre-war knowledge. Most documents are embellished retellings of second- or third-hand accounts: nothing but fanciful stories with little value.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_Scrolls_1);</string>
        <string>dlgCam(225, 45, 8, 1);</string>
        <string>dlgHideWeapons();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Browse through scrolls.</text>
          <def_link>1</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.lore_permissionGranted == 0</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>2</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>0</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>One particular story catches your eye: it speaks of a war between the Magi but doesn’t provide any specifics, focusing on the emotional aspects instead. It speaks of the great schism and greater anguish, of brothers fighting brothers, and of the last great battle that ended the Order and scattered the Magi.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_Scrolls_2);</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
        <string>dlgCam(125, 45, 8, 1);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Keep browsing.</text>
          <def_link>3</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>1</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>An entire section is dedicated to the last First of the Magi: his biography, various attempts to understand and decipher his work, stories of his exploits written more than a century after his death, and three different accounts of his last battle.

In the most fanciful account the First of the Magi faced demons who took on human form, pretending to be his brothers, but the great and wise magus saw through their lies. Unleashing a fiery sword of heaven, he battled them for many days and nights that were as bright as day, until he was engulfed in heavenly fire that burned him and the shapeshifting demons alike.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_Scrolls_3);</string>
        <string>dlgFadeToThisPart();</string>
        <string>dlgCam(250, 45, 8, 1);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Keep browsing.</text>
          <def_link>4</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>3</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Finally, something interesting. It’s an interpretation of a document written from the words of a blind magus. The document itself is missing, but it seems the magus attempted to explain how the ‘shadowy gates’ worked to a scribe assigned to him in his last days. The scribe dutifully wrote everything down and passed to his superiors for evaluation. The document gathered dust for almost two hundred years until it was discovered by an eager but overly verbose loremaster who attempted to ‘make sense of the arcane’.

The interpretation leaves much to be desired but the cited passages speak of a honeycomb network and a complex system that governed it. Once activated, a gate stayed connected to the entire network but in order to transmute matter – the scribe noted that the magus said what sounded like ‘transmit’ – it required a special permission, granted or revoked by the First of the Magi’s Officium.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.lore_permissionGranted = true;</string>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_Scrolls_4);</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
        <string>dlgCam(45, 45, 8, 1);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Take notes about these special permissions and leave.</text>
          <def_link>2</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>4</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
        <string>dlgCam(45, 45, 12, 1);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>2</UID>
    </dlgPart>
  </parts>
</dlgData>