<?xml version="1.0"?>
<dlgData xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <conditions />
    <links />
    <dlg_name>HGR_ShipLog_01</dlg_name>
    <def_link>0</def_link>
    <def_speaker_name>None</def_speaker_name>
    <def_portrait>None</def_portrait>
  </header>
  <parts>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"... we commenced to launch Heavy Fyre at the Enemy from all our Ballistae, with both Regular Speare and Hellfyre, the latter of which proved greatly Effective, so that in less than fifteen minutes from the Time we engaged Our Enemy, their Ship was very much Injured, heaving and yawing in Plain Distress. At this time damage taken by the Pax Imperium was minor ...

"... and gave us an opportunity of pouring in upon their Vessel several Hellfyres, which made Great Havoc amongst the Enemy Crewe and wreaked Grievous Injury to her Hull and Engines ..."

It seems that these crumbling pages are what's left of the captain's log.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Keep reading.</text>
          <def_link>2</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>1</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>0</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>1</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"Enclosed I have the Honour to forward you a list of Killed and Wounded of the Pax Imperium and also the list of Casualties aboard the Enemy Vessel, as well as the List of surviving Crewe and a copy of her Quarter Bill, and Finally a report of our own Damage Received during the Action...

"... and found aboard her the most unquestionable Evidence ... obliged therefore to Investigate the matter, I have set the Engines to Full Speed ... Upon Sighting our Quarry, I made a decision to land Pax Imperium in the midst of the Enemy’s forces and Project Shields, allowing our Troops to disembark and Engage the Enemy Infantry..."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Keep reading.</text>
          <def_link>3</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>1</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"I wish to convey to you the bravery of the Officers and the Crewe under my command during the Recent Action. I assure you that so well directed and so Relentless was the Fyre of Pax Imperium, that in less than three hours the Accursed One sustained Grave Injuries, compelling the remainder of the Qantari Force to Disengage and Flee. You will no doubt hear from many Quarters of the Bravery and Exemplary Conduct of those engaged in this Conflict, and I must again state that these Accounts are in no way Exaggerated ...

"... to haul off and Repair our Damages and return again to the Action, not knowing whether the Enemy had survived or not..."

The rest is indecipherable.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>1</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>3</UID>
    </dlgPart>
  </parts>
</dlgData>