<?xml version="1.0"?>
<dlgData xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <conditions />
    <links />
    <dlg_name>HGT_console_01</dlg_name>
    <def_link>90</def_link>
    <def_speaker_name>None</def_speaker_name>
    <def_portrait>None</def_portrait>
  </header>
  <parts>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>As far as you can tell, the semi-sphere is carved from a single crystal and polished to perfection. It's framed in a large metal band covered with dimly glowing symbols. You touch one of the symbols and the crystal's surface changes almost instantly, tiny fracture lines appear, rearrange themselves, and disappear as quickly as they come.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[intelligence][lore]Try to figure out how to use it.</text>
          <def_link>163</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.inf_towerConsole_learned == 0 &amp;&amp; aod.lore_knowledge_databanks == 0</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.int &lt; 8</string>
            <string>aod.lore == 10</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>162</int>
            <int>160</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Access the databanks.</text>
          <def_link>140</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.inf_towerConsole_learned || aod.lore_knowledge_databanks</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>138</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>90</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[intelligence failure]You have no idea.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>138</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>162</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[intelligence success][lore failure]You almost figured it out. If you put your hands this way and then... Never mind.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>138</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>163</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>138</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[success]You rest your hands on the cool surface of the semi-sphere and try to clear your thoughts. Slowly, images from the databanks rise to the surface of the display like colorful fish rising from black depths. As you grow accustomed to the experience, the disconnected scenes begin to rush forth all at once, until you gradually figure out how to sort and slow them.

Seek out information on:</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>The portal network.</text>
          <def_link>141</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Look for any recordings.</text>
          <def_link>147</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>160</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>You rest your hands on the cool surface of the semi-sphere and try to clear your thoughts. Slowly, images from the databanks rise to the surface of the display like colorful fish rising from black depths. As you grow accustomed to the experience, the disconnected scenes begin to rush forth all at once, until you gradually figure out how to sort and slow them.

Seek out information on:</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>The portal network.</text>
          <def_link>141</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Look for any recordings.</text>
          <def_link>147</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>140</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>A glowing honeycomb of portals surfaces on the crystal semi-sphere. There is a flash at the very center, and tiny stars radiate outwards on the network. When the stars reach a junction, they split into two or three new stars and continue to the end nodes.

Upon reaching their destinations, the lights blink three times, then disappear as the portals fail to respond. One by one the stars and the portals vanish. With the sequence ended, only three remain. One is represented by a ziggurat, the other a tower, and the last one a facility high in the mountains.

The image flashes red and disappears before you can do anything.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Look for any recordings.</text>
          <def_link>147</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>141</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>A tall, eagle-faced man stands very still; only his eyes move over the broad crystal screen before him. “Are the Sentinels ready to be activated?”

“Almost, Commander,” says a younger man, his hands moving feverishly over the controls. In response, a blur of confused images appear and disappear over the console.

“We received new orders this morning,” says the commander. “We have twenty-four hours to evacuate the base.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>158</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>147</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“What about the lake?” asks the man at the console.

The base commander makes an unfamiliar gesture. “We’ll blame it on the Qantari.”

The other man gives a low whistle. “And the ziggurat, do we give that up too?”

“The ziggurat they want intact,” says the commander with a shrug.

“Then why are we pulling the plug?” asks the Centurion.

“That kind of intelligence is above my station,” the Commander says bitterly, “or so I've been told. Someone at the top decided the base has to go dead, so that's what we're doing. The ziggurat is a different sort of animal. That we will preserve for the worst case scenario.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>159</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>158</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The subordinate thinks about this for a moment, then asks, “Have you ever met Him?”

“I did, once,” nods the commander, his jaw working silently while he chooses his words. “He's supposed to be on our side, but what does something inhuman care for what we want? We just happen to be on his side. For now.”

“What do you mean?” The man's hands are in his lap now, the console forgotten.

“He’s fighting his own war and we’re helping him to win it, not the other way around,” says the commander.

“And when the war’s over?”

“My guess is that’s why they’re pulling the plug now, so we don’t have to find out the hard way,” says the commander.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>138</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>159</UID>
    </dlgPart>
  </parts>
</dlgData>