<?xml version="1.0"?>
<dlgData xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <conditions>
      <string>aod.npc_azra_met</string>
    </conditions>
    <links>
      <int>6023</int>
    </links>
    <dlg_name>INF_NPC_Azra_01</dlg_name>
    <def_link>6024</def_link>
    <def_speaker_name>Azra</def_speaker_name>
    <def_portrait>Azra</def_portrait>
  </header>
  <parts>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait>None</portrait>
      <speaker_name>None</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>One of the villagers assumes the role of a guide and points at one of the dwellings on the outskirts of the village. The dwelling is surrounded by patches of strange plants growing out of the sand.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>setRtsCam();</string>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_OutsideAzra_01);</string>
        <string>dlgCam(335, 40, 10, 1);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Go inside.</text>
          <def_link>5981</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6024</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>You’re standing in a small room filled with various plants that leave just enough space for a bed, occupied by a dried up crone. One of the villagers respectfully taps her on the shoulder and whispers something to her ear.

The crone gestures, looking irritated, and the villagers fall back, leaving you alone with her. She slowly gets up, sighs, and comes closer to take a good look at you.

“Well, well, well,” she says in a low, raspy voice. “Look what the wind blew in.” She fixes you with a hard stare and scoffs, her withered lips twisting and moving, as if searching for the right words to express her displeasure. “So, what am I supposed to do with you?”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFadeToThisPart();</string>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_Azra_01);</string>
        <string>aod.npc_azra_met = true;</string>
        <string>dlgCam(320, 50, 8, 5805);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Why should you do anything?”</text>
          <def_link>5982</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>5981</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“What do you do when your garden sprouts weeds? You remove them without pity, even though a weed is a living thing and wants to live as much as everything else does. If you don’t, they will ruin the garden.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“You don’t have to worry about me. I’m here to ask you a few questions and then I’ll be on my way.”</text>
          <def_link>5983</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“So, this is your garden?”</text>
          <def_link>6000</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>5982</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“We shall see about that, won’t we? Why did you come here? What is it that you seek?”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“I’m looking for the temple of Thor-Agoth.”</text>
          <def_link>5984</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>5983</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“It is,” nods the crone. “I've been looking after these people for decades. I delivered most of them into this world – not many midwives around these parts. I watched them grow, kept them safe, weeded out the bad seeds.

“Speaking of which, why did you come here? What is it that you seek?”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“I’m looking for the temple of Thor-Agoth.”</text>
          <def_link>5984</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6000</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Do you see any temple around here?” she scoffs again. “Why are you looking for it?”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“The lord I serve wants me to find it.”</text>
          <def_link>5985</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“It holds answers to many questions.”</text>
          <def_link>5988</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Fame, fortune, glory – take your pick.”</text>
          <def_link>5989</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>5984</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“A servant then, are you? Serving a man for the crumbs of his table?” Another scoff.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Scoff all you want. There is no shame in working for someone to earn your pay.”</text>
          <def_link>5986</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“And what’s the alternative? This?” Nod at the room.</text>
          <def_link>5987</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>5985</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“To each his own,” says the crone, gesturing dismissively.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Do you know where the temple is?”</text>
          <def_link>5999</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>5986</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“You need more than one bed to sleep in? More than one meal to eat?” says the crone, gesturing dismissively.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Do you know where the temple is?”</text>
          <def_link>5999</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>5987</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“It holds a lot more than that.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“How do you know that?”</text>
          <def_link>5999</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>5988</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Ah, one of those... Broken as this world is, it still breeds fools faster than it kills them,” says the old woman, shaking her head.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Do you know where the temple is?”</text>
          <def_link>5990</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>5989</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The crone nods. “I visited it when I was young and curious. I walked down the ancient halls, I held in my hands the relics the gods left behind, I sat where the Magi did when they came in droves to learn the knowledge that didn’t belong in this world. I’ve even looked down at the sleeping god that lies there and wondered if the kiss of a fair maiden – don’t look at me, I wasn’t born old – would have the power to wake him.

“But even then,” the crone raises her voice suddenly, “I had the wisdom not to touch things I don’t understand and leave them alone, wisdom your kind lacks.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>addLore(21);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“So, the god is still there? Sleeping?”</text>
          <def_link>5991</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Wisdom? Or fear?”</text>
          <def_link>5997</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Tell me about the relics.”</text>
          <def_link>5998</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>5990</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“I visited it when I was young and curious. I walked down the ancient halls, I held in my hands the relics the gods left behind, I sat where the Magi did when they came in droves to learn the knowledge that didn’t belong in this world. I’ve even looked down at the sleeping god that lies there and wondered if the kiss of a fair maiden – don’t look at me, I wasn’t born old – would have the power to wake him.

“But even then,” the crone raises her voice suddenly, “I had the wisdom not to touch things I don’t understand and leave them alone, wisdom your kind lacks.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“So, the god is still there? Sleeping?”</text>
          <def_link>5991</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Wisdom? Or fear?”</text>
          <def_link>5997</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Tell me about the relics.”</text>
          <def_link>5998</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>5999</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Why wouldn’t he be? It’s not like he has anywhere else to go,” cackles the crone.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“What if the god can make things better? Can fix all this?”</text>
          <def_link>5992</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>5991</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“What if he makes things worse?” counters the crone. “That’s the difference between the town dwellers and the desert folk.

“You hope, always hope,” she spits the word ‘hope’ as if it were an insult. “You hope that the lord will be merciful, hope that guards won’t harass you, hope that the store owner will take pity on you, hope that levies won’t be raised too much this year, hope that the prices won’t go up, hope that there will be work tomorrow.

“You’re so used to hoping that someone will take care of you that you’re ready to believe in just about anything as long as it promises you new hope.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[intelligence success]“You seem to know a lot about the town life for someone who lives in the middle of nowhere.”</text>
          <def_link>5993</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.int &gt;= 7</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.cha &gt;= 7</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>5994</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“And you're so used to expecting the worst that you would reject divine help if it was offered, simply because it doesn’t fit your beliefs.”</text>
          <def_link>5995</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“What’s wrong with hope?”</text>
          <def_link>5996</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.npc_azra_talk_hope == 0</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>5992</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[charisma failure]“I wasn’t born here,” says the crone sharply.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“You mentioned hope. What's wrong with that?”</text>
          <def_link>5996</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.npc_azra_talk_hope == 0</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>6010</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.npc_azra_talk_hope</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>5993</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[charisma success]“I was born in Maadoran,” says the crone suddenly. “Before the first exodus. The city was different back then, filled to the brim with people, like an overused latrine that hasn’t been cleaned in a while. Smelled about the same too.

“That’s what I remember the most – the smell. We lived like animals, sleeping together to keep warm, eating scraps, fighting for what little we had. Not much of a life that was, yet people fought for it and died for it. “As long as it won’t get worse...,” my mother used to say, like a prayer that went unanswered. Every year things got worse and every year she said the same thing. It took me years to understand what she meant.

Anything we could survive wasn’t the worst. Anything we could survive, we could get used to and learn to live with. As long as things won’t get worse,” adds the crone smiling grimly.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_azra_asked_background = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“The first exodus?”</text>
          <def_link>6001</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>5994</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“I was born in Maadoran, before the first exodus. The city was different back then, filled to the brim with people, like an overused latrine that hasn’t been cleaned in a while. Smelled about the same too.

“That’s what I remember the most – the smell. We lived like animals, sleeping together to keep warm, eating scraps, fighting for what little we had. Not much of a life that was, yet people fought for it and died for it. “As long as it won’t get worse...,” my mother used to say, like a prayer that went unanswered. Every year things got worse and every year she said the same thing. It took me years to understand what she meant.

Anything we could survive wasn’t the worst. Anything we could survive, we could get used to and learn to live with. As long as things won’t get worse,” adds the crone smiling grimly.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“The first exodus?”</text>
          <def_link>6001</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6022</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Divine help?” scoffs the crone. “No being, mortal or divine, ever does anything without a reason. What reason would they have to help the poor old us?”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Have faith.”</text>
          <def_link>6012</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Not everyone needs a selfish reason to help someone. Being able to is the only reason they need. They’ve helped us once, they can do it again!”</text>
          <def_link>6013</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Everyone needs something. Whatever these gods want – worship, gold, virgins, temples – is a small price to pay for their help.”</text>
          <def_link>6014</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>5995</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“What’s wrong with hope?” repeats the crone, as if refusing to believe you've just asked her that.

“Hope is for fools who don’t know what they are doing. In the desert, there is no room for hope. You count on yourself, not on other people. You don’t hope to find water, you either carry enough or know where the wells or the plants that store water are. You don’t eat what you don’t know, hoping that it won’t kill you or paralyze your stomach, slowly starving you to death even if you have enough food. And you certainly don’t wake a god hoping that he has your best interests at heart, assuming he has one to begin with.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_azra_talk_hope = 1;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>And you're so used to expecting the worst that you would reject divine help if it was offered, simply because it doesn’t fit your beliefs.”</text>
          <def_link>5995</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>5996</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Fear is the beginning of wisdom,” says the crone with disdain, shaking her head at your foolishness, “for only a fool isn’t afraid. Knowing what the gods have done, knowing their power and how freely they used it, how can one not be afraid?

“Men talk a lot about overcoming fear, but fear is a natural thing. Its purpose is not to scare you, but to keep you alive. And by staying alive, by avoiding things that would kill you, you gain wisdom.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“So, the god is still there? Sleeping?”</text>
          <def_link>5991</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>5997</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“How do you describe fire to someone who’s never seen it?”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“You mentioned wisdom? Or was it fear?”</text>
          <def_link>5997</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“So, the god is still there? Sleeping?”</text>
          <def_link>5991</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>5998</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“That’s what they called it. The guards rounded up everyone the city didn’t need and sent them off to the desert. It was time for them to reclaim the land and take back what was rightfully theirs, they said. An opportunity for the right kind of people,” smiles the crone.

“My mother was devastated, but I remember it as my first real holiday. Fresh air, plenty of space, clean water that didn’t smell like a latrine. The first time I ate fresh meat, I kept looking for maggots and wondering where they were. Before that, I had never had anything, save for some rotten scraps.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Water? In the desert?”</text>
          <def_link>6002</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“How did you end up here?”</text>
          <def_link>6004</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6001</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“The desert is harsh, but not lifeless. It has enough food and water to sustain you, if you know where to look. In the cities, food and water are plentiful, but only if you can afford it. If you don’t, you better get used to scraps of rotten meat and dirty water.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“What happened to the people who left?”</text>
          <def_link>6003</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6002</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Most of them died. They begged for scraps and hoped that tomorrow would be a better day somehow instead of doing something to ensure their survival. It doesn’t surprise me anymore, seeing what I’ve seen,” she says, shaking her head slowly, her eyes distant.

“Believing in miracles, in someone coming to save you, is different than believing in your own ability to do whatever it takes to save yourself. Most people who left the city with us didn’t have that belief. I think they were waiting for the first opportunity to give up and in the desert, you don’t need to wait long.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“How did you end up here?”</text>
          <def_link>6004</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6003</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“We moved around a lot – the desert is in constant motion. To survive, you need to move too. You learn to feel the desert, the winds, the shifting sands, water in the oases, and follow them. Eventually, the desert led us here, to her holy place.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“It seems that you've adapated well to the desert.”</text>
          <def_link>6005</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“I saw a strange place in the middle of the village. What is it?”</text>
          <def_link>6006</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6004</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Kingdoms will rise and fall, but the desert will always be here. Her ways are harsh, but her children are strong and will survive where softer folks won’t.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“I saw a strange place in the middle of the village. What is it?”</text>
          <def_link>6006</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6005</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“A remnant of another age. The desert claimed it, preserved it, led us to it. The predators avoid it – animals feel things that we don’t. Shamans get stronger dreams here, so they come every now and then, bringing gifts and the sacrifice.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“The sacrifice?”</text>
          <def_link>6007</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Can I go down there?”</text>
          <def_link>6008</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6006</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The crone shrugs. “We stick to the olds ways here. To receive, you must give.” She doesn’t elaborate.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Can I go down there?”</text>
          <def_link>6008</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6007</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“I won’t stop you if you choose to do so, but you won’t be coming back. Even if you survive, you will stay down there. These people believe that this is a holy place. I can’t have them see you emerging from the underworld alive.

“You go down there, you stay there. That’s the deal I offer and there won’t be any other.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“I’ll take my chances.”</text>
          <def_link>6009</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Some other time maybe.”</text>
          <def_link>6011</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6008</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The crone studies your face, then nods.

“When you leave, the villagers will take you there.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_azra_letgo = false;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>6010</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6009</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
        <string>centercamera(215, 47, 10);</string>
        <string>aod.inf_insideAzra = true;</string>
        <string>VCO_AzraDoor.setActive(1);</string>
        <string>setCombatAllowed(1);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>6010</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The crone nods. “Be on your way then.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_azra_letgo = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>6010</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6011</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Faith? Faith is the currency of fools. It is hope’s dumb cousin. Out with you! We're done talking.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>6010</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6012</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Helped us? They destroyed half the world. Pray that they leave us alone because if they decide to help us again, there won’t be anything – or anyone – left this time.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[intelligence success]“You seem to know a lot about the town life for someone who lives in the middle of nowhere.”</text>
          <def_link>5993</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.int &gt;= 7 &amp;&amp; aod.npc_azra_asked_background == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.cha &gt;= 7</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>5994</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>6010</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6013</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“So eager to give away anything that’s not yours to improve your life, eh?” chuckles the woman. “But what if it’s more than even you are willing to pay? It’s not the kind of genie you can put back in the bottle again. Then what?”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[persuasion]“Everything belongs to the lords today. Would you shed any tears if tomorrow it belongs to a god? All I have is my life and even this isn’t much and can be taken away at any moment, so if it makes you feel any better, I’m willing to risk it too.”</text>
          <def_link>6015</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.persuasion &gt;= 6</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>6016</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[streetwise success]“Are you certain that the genie will stay in the bottle forever? The spells that bind him will fade away one day and he’ll be free. So, if it’s unavoidable, I’d rather him being in our debt.”</text>
          <def_link>6016</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.streetwise &gt;= 6 &amp;&amp; aod.int &lt; 8</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[intelligence success]“Are you certain that the genie will stay in the bottle forever? The spells that bind him will fade away one day and he’ll be free. So, if it’s unavoidable, I’d rather him being in our debt.”</text>
          <def_link>6016</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.int &gt;= 8</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6014</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[failure]“You’re too eager,” says the crone, shaking her head. “I will let you leave, but I won’t help you find the temple.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_azra_letgo = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[intelligence success]“You seem to know a lot about the town life for someone who lives in the middle of nowhere.”</text>
          <def_link>5993</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.int &gt;= 7 &amp;&amp; aod.npc_azra_asked_background == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.cha &gt;= 7</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>5994</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>6010</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6015</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Very well,” says the crone, looking at you strangely, “if you’re so eager to go there, it’s not my place to hold you back. Just keep in mind what we talked about here.

“You know where the Dead River is? It’s north of Ganezzar, far north of it. One of the locals there can show you the way. The temple is beyond the river, but the real trick is getting across alive. Those helpful gods of yours vaporized it during the war. The riverbed’s been deadly ever since. You can still see ancient ships at the bottom ... and the bones of all those who tried their luck and went down there. Luck is a poor defense against the magic of the gods. So think twice before you decide to wake one of them up.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_azra_letgo = true;</string>
        <string>revealMapLocation("Ganezzar");</string>
        <string>dlgAddTextBoxMessage("Ganezzar added to the map");</string>
        <string>rwd_civil(INF_04);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“How do I get across then?”</text>
          <def_link>6017</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6016</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“The locals can get you across. They’ve lost their ways, but I’m sure you can think of something.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“And if I don’t?”</text>
          <def_link>6018</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“How did you convince them to take you across the river?”</text>
          <def_link>6019</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.cha &gt;= 7</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>6020</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6017</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The crone shrugs.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[intelligence success]“You seem to know a lot about the town life for someone who lives in the middle of nowhere.”</text>
          <def_link>5993</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.int &gt;= 7 &amp;&amp; aod.npc_azra_asked_background == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.cha &gt;= 7</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>5994</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>6010</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6018</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[charisma failure]Something changes in the crone’s face. She looks like she’s about to say something, but waves you away instead.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>6010</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6019</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[charisma success]Something changes in the crone’s face and she straightens up, looking at you differently. For a brief moment you see a different woman standing in front of you, a woman who wouldn’t need to ask anyone for anything.

The crone sees it on your face, her mouth twitches, and she nods. “I was called the Witch in those days. I was a different woman then. A foolish one.” She shakes her head, but doesn’t elaborate.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_azra_witch = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Do tell.”</text>
          <def_link>6021</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.npc_azra_maadoran</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>6021</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6020</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“There is nothing to tell,” the crone says dismissively. “I returned to Maadoran. I was young and curious. I wanted to see the city that I only had distant memories about. It was different than I remembered it, but then again,” she smiles thinly, “I lived in places my parents wouldn’t even be allowed to approach.

“I fell in love with a man who was destined to rise. I lent him my talents and made enemies ... recklessly. I didn’t know then that those that are destined to rise are just as often destined to fall. When he did, I had to flee. I returned here – the only home I’ve ever known.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Returned to Maadoran?”</text>
          <def_link>6022</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.npc_azra_asked_background == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>6010</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6021</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“You're wasting daylight. Be on your way now.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_Azra_01);</string>
        <string>dlgCam(315, 45, 8, 5805);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>6010</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.inf_status == 5</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>6025</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6023</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END - miracle</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>6025</UID>
    </dlgPart>
  </parts>
</dlgData>