<?xml version="1.0"?>
<dlgData xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <conditions>
      <string>aod.npc_MTY_guard_01_met</string>
    </conditions>
    <links>
      <int>10</int>
    </links>
    <dlg_name>MTY_NPC_Guard_01</dlg_name>
    <def_link>0</def_link>
    <def_speaker_name>Guard</def_speaker_name>
    <def_portrait>None</def_portrait>
  </header>
  <parts>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The man before you meets your gaze and casually but deliberately dips his crossbow toward the ground. He nods and greets you plainly. "Traveler."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_MTY_guard_01_met = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"That piece for guests?"</text>
          <def_link>1</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>0</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"I hope not. We are... thankful for your help today." The strain in his voice is hard to miss.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"You don't sound very thankful."</text>
          <def_link>2</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>1</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>He looks heavily towards the ground as he sighs through his nostrils before meeting your gaze again. "I am sorry, truly. You did a great service for my people today. But no, I am not happy for you to be here, traveler. You are an ominous coincidence."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"How so?"</text>
          <def_link>3</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"I have known fifty one years amongst my people here on this mountain. Up until my fiftieth year, I could recall only... half a dozen visitors? Since we took that man in a year ago, there have been three traders and two raider bands. We had hoped any interest in us had faded away by now. And then today, another raider band *and* you. I fear it does not bode well for our future."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Clearly I'm not with the raiders though."</text>
          <def_link>4</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>9</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>3</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"That's of little solace. Perhaps it would have been better if you had been. Two separately interested parties in the same day is troubling to say the least. I am not the elder, but some of us think it unwise to bring outsiders into our home. Some think it even less wise to let them leave."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"And you are one of those. You'd see me dead?"</text>
          <def_link>5</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>4</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>He searches your eyes deeply and then with an honest and almost sad face replies, "I would. But it is not my decision. I hope you can understand the position we find ourselves in here. A single traveler has brought much evil to our doors. We cannot risk more attention. It pains me to feel this way about you after what you did for us."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"And me as well, no doubt. What guarantees do I have that you won't try to kill me right here?"</text>
          <def_link>6</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>5</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"None. But I will not. I will not act against our elder's hospitality. And again, I do not forget what you did for us today. But when you leave, I and a handful of others will petition the elder to send Maelius into the wilderness after you. To make sure you do not return to civilization. The elder will say no, as he has done before. What guarantees do I have that you will not perpetuate the lies about our village and sell its location to others?"</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"None, I suppose. But I will not. I respect your fear and concern. Perhaps I can actually help."</text>
          <def_link>7</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"I'll be waiting for him then." Leave.</text>
          <def_link>9</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"What would you do, traveler?"</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"The man that stayed with you a year ago is rumored to be dead now, so his stories have ended. Before he died, he sold his story to a healer in payment for treatment. That healer sent me to investigate his story. If I could bring an end to her curiosity, it could go some ways in stemming further investigations. Probably not all, of course. But some."</text>
          <def_link>8</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>7</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"This would be a great favor to us, traveler. I hope you would do this for us."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>9</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>9</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END - bark Man shakes his head</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>narratePhrase("The man shakes his head and looks away.");</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>10</UID>
    </dlgPart>
  </parts>
</dlgData>