<?xml version="1.0"?>
<dlgData xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <conditions>
      <string>aod.npc_mdn_farmer_01_met</string>
    </conditions>
    <links>
      <int>6561</int>
    </links>
    <dlg_name>NPC_MDN_Farmer_01</dlg_name>
    <def_link>6538</def_link>
    <def_speaker_name>Farmer</def_speaker_name>
    <def_portrait>None</def_portrait>
  </header>
  <parts>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>A deeply tanned fellow works at loosening some netting on a cart laden with sacks and baskets of produce. His thinning hair jerks about as he vigorously yanks a corner knot free and tosses the net to the front of the cart. Pausing just long enough to wipe his forehead with the back of his forearm, he grabs a basket of potatoes and turns to carry it over to the nearby stall. He moves with the strength and efficiency of one well accustomed to physical labor.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_mdn_farmer_01_met = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Got a moment?”</text>
          <def_link>6539</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6538</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Yeah. Several.” He grunts as he sets the basket down by the stall and begins walking back over to the cart. “Planning to spend them all on these baskets though.” He grabs another basket and pauses to give you a grin, “But if you can work and talk, I can talk and work.” He slides the basket off the cart and turns for the stall.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Roll up your sleeves and grab a basket of onions, “Fair enough.”</text>
          <def_link>6541</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“All work and no play makes a bore of a man by end o' the day. Ever heard that?”</text>
          <def_link>6542</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.cha &gt;= 7</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>6543</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“I much prefer carrying my food on a plate than by the basket. However, I understand the value of time.” You rub a couple coins together in an outstretched hand. “Perhaps a couple coins is worth the delay? A couple of drinks on me at the end of the day wouldn't be so bad, right?”</text>
          <def_link>6544</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>dlgGetMoney() &gt;= 2</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“I don't have time for this right now.”</text>
          <def_link>6545</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6539</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>6540</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Name's Eugenius,” he says as the two of you walk over and stoop to sit the baskets down. You head back to the cart and grab a sack of what is probably dried beans as Eugenius lifts a basket of dust radishes. “I can't help but wonder what I've got to say that would be important enough for you to lend a hand to hear it.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Looks to be a good load here. Is it not difficult raising a harvest out there?”</text>
          <def_link>6546</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6541</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[charisma failure]“Yeah, from idiots. When the farmer plays, we all go hungry. Ever heard that? Now if you don't mind... I'm busy.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>6540</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6542</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[charisma success]He stops for a second and chuckles, “There's wisdom there for sure. What can this boring old farmer do for ya?” He starts off with the basket again and you follow along.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Looks to be a good load here. Is it not difficult raising a harvest out there?”</text>
          <def_link>6546</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6543</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>He sits the basket by the stall, turns to face you and pauses for a second before grinning. “Kind of against my principles to rest before the job's done... but I reckon I'd be a damned fool to pass up an offer to buy a few of my words.” He walks over to you, pockets the coins and half jokingly gives you a conspiratorial whisper, “Let's keep it between us though, else the Commercium will want half, right?” He chuckles at himself. “Name's Eugenius. What can an old farmer do for you today?”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgChangeMoney(-2);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Looks to be a good load here. Is it not difficult raising a harvest out there?”</text>
          <def_link>6546</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6544</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Looks like we have some common ground then,” he shoots over his shoulder as he continues at his task.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>6540</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6545</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Eugenius squints his eyes inquisitively and grins, “What do you think?”

He pauses and looks up into the sky, his face turning grim. “Some years are brutal, trying to scratch a living out of the dirt. You feel like a damn fool trying to coax stubborn seeds up out of the ground into this,” he waves his hands around, “hellish world. Who can blame 'em, right?

“But then, some years, a few showers here and there... it almost feels like the gods might just still give a shit. They probably don't,” he quickly and matter-of-factly adds, “but when you go from a year where you're spitting on prickle fruit seeds every day just to get them to sprout... to a year like this one,” he points to the baskets of produce, “it's almost enough to give a man religion again.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Why do you keep doing it?”</text>
          <def_link>6547</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6546</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Well, we gotta eat, don't we?!” He laughs heartily for a few moments before trailing off and wiping his eyes. He lets out a mirthful sigh then turns serious again. “It's a noble profession, you know? Farming. I mean, I'm no house noble by a long shot but it's an honest living. Keeps my conscience clean and my neighbors fed. These are troubled times, no doubt, but at the end of the day I know I took care of myself and didn't hurt anyone while doing it. The harder I work, the more I grow. The more I grow the more money I earn *and*... the more food there is for you to buy. Sometimes what's good for one is good for another. A novel notion these days.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“So in the good years you man a stall in the market and get rich, I suppose?”</text>
          <def_link>6548</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[alchemy success]"Potatoes, onions, dust radishes, and some very healthy tomatoes. No luck with yellow gourds I'm guessing?"</text>
          <def_link>6551</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.alchemy &gt;= 2</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Do you own your land or does it belong to Gaelius?”</text>
          <def_link>6555</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"A farmer philosopher with a heart of gold. You're quite a rarity."</text>
          <def_link>6557</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"I should probably let you get back to work." Leave.</text>
          <def_link>6540</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6547</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Shoot.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“So in the good years you man a stall in the market and get rich, I suppose?”</text>
          <def_link>6548</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.npc_farmer01_asked_rich == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[alchemy success]"Potatoes, onions, dust radishes, and some very healthy tomatoes. No luck with yellow gourds I'm guessing?"</text>
          <def_link>6551</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.alchemy &gt;= 2 &amp;&amp; aod.npc_farmer01_asked_gourds == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Do you own your land or does it belong to Gaelius?”</text>
          <def_link>6555</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.npc_farmer01_asked_land == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"A farmer philosopher with a heart of gold. You're quite a rarity."</text>
          <def_link>6557</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.npc_farmer01_asked_heart == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"How much does the Commercium charge you?"</text>
          <def_link>6550</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.npc_farmer01_ask_fee &amp;&amp; aod.npc_farmer01_asked_fee == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Why not just skip the major towns? Travel around and sell to whatever settlements are out there?"</text>
          <def_link>6554</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.npc_farmer01_ask_skipTowns &amp;&amp; aod.npc_farmer01_asked_skipTowns == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"I should probably let you get back to work." Leave.</text>
          <def_link>6540</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6558</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"Ha! I'm hardly running out of holes to bury my profits in, if that's what you mean, but the good years get me by. The bad years, I grow enough to eat which is about all a simple man can really ask for, I suppose. But yeah, good years, I haul the surplus to market and make some coin for putting back. It actually pays very well when I've got it to sale.

"And this isn't my stall. When I've got this much surplus I sell in bulk to a merchant here at market. There's too much work to do back at home when the crop is coming in strong. Margin isn't as good after you consider the discount to the merchant and the Commercium fees but the time saved ensures I haven't got crop rotting in the field."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_farmer01_asked_rich = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"The Commercium always gets its cut, doesn't it? Are they difficult to work with?"</text>
          <def_link>6549</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6548</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Eugenius smiles and looks around. "You wouldn't stand in front of my house and talk shit about my onions, would you?" He raises his eyebrows as he gives you a moment for comprehension to take hold. "Look, the Commercium does what it does and I do what I do. If you wanna sell in the major towns you gotta pay the fee. So no, they're not difficult to work with as they're very efficient at processing my payments and papers. And... they keep the market square well guarded, so, good for all, right?"</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_farmer01_ask_fee = true;</string>
        <string>aod.npc_farmer01_ask_skipTowns = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Why not just skip the major towns? Travel around and sell to whatever settlements are out there?"</text>
          <def_link>6554</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"So, what's their fee?"</text>
          <def_link>6550</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6549</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"Depends on how well you're doing. Usually, it's about three-four on twenty. I think they take it a little easier on us that are dealing in crop goods. It's hard enough raising crops out there. They put too big a fee on us and it's just not worth the effort to raise surplus. And the Commercium likes to eat as well as any of us I guess."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_farmer01_asked_fee = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[trading]"I bet they'll take as little as two on twenty five if you approach them the right way. You're right, they don't want to run farmers off completely. You're a cornerstone of commerce. Tell them you need the extra money to put towards increasing your yields. It means more produce at market and more fee income for them. They should go for it."</text>
          <def_link>6559</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.trading &gt;= 4</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Another question?"</text>
          <def_link>6558</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"I should probably let you get back to work." Leave.</text>
          <def_link>6540</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6550</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Eugenius stops and eyes you quizzically, "None. They won't take. How'd you know?"</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_farmer01_asked_gourds = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"They're conspicuously absent from your otherwise impressive harvest. They don't tend to do well in areas where tomatoes grow that large. Your soil is probably acid bent. Prior to turning soil for the new season, has the winter sedge grown in thick?"</text>
          <def_link>6552</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6551</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>He smiles, "It does."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"It's possible to shift your soil's nature. If you can, acquire crushed limestone... enough to fill two of those sacks. Your best bet would likely be the salt mines to the west. Cook the limestone fiercely and then grind it fine. Spread it evenly over your gardens and you'll likely see a measurable harvest increase, including yellow gourds if you wanted. You're the farmer, but I'd leave a spot untreated for tomatoes. I'd hate to see those beauties suffer."</text>
          <def_link>6553</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6552</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"If it works, I'm indebted to you for this advice. Thank you."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Another question?"</text>
          <def_link>6558</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"I should probably let you get back to work." Leave.</text>
          <def_link>6540</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6553</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"Ha! Are you kidding me? First of all, there's only a handful of shitty settlements anywhere close out there and the risk ain't worth trying to get to all of them. Sure, I could probably avoid a Commercium fee but surviving long travels in the Waste comes with its own costs. One customer you *can* count on out there are the damned raiders. Problem with them is they're real partial to those 'steal one and get the rest for free deals'. Those assholes only buy in bulk too.

"Some merchants try to do it though. It's a rough life but the ones that make it I guess do alright. You've got to be crafty though to pull that life off. Folks that try to bypass the Commercium tend to have bad things befall them sooner or later though. Just a coincidence I'm sure."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_farmer01_asked_skipTowns = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Another question?"</text>
          <def_link>6558</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"I should probably let you get back to work." Leave.</text>
          <def_link>6540</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6554</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"I'm fortunate enough to have my own little piece of the dirt out there. Doesn't mean Gaelius can't take every potato I own and call me up to arms at a moments notice though, does it? For the good of Maadoran, the honor of House Aurelian, and defense of the Empire... or whatever we're calling it these days. But until then, yeah, beats working another man's fields for him, right?"</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_farmer01_asked_land = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"How do you think Maadoran fares these days?"</text>
          <def_link>6556</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6555</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"Better than most, which isn't saying much. Raiders are as abundant in the Wastes as gold in a Commercium's vault. The noble houses are all the same... too paranoid to trust each other, rightly so I'd wager, and hell bent on being the first to dig up whatever artifact that might secure them a clear advantage over the others. I guess Gaelius is no worse than any other.

"He likes taxing us maybe a little too much, but I hardly notice it what with the Commercium's hand always in my pocket. Let the houses play their politics I suppose. I'll worry about making sure we all eat. Last I checked, that still seemed to be important to everybody."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Another question?"</text>
          <def_link>6558</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"I should probably let you get back to work." Leave.</text>
          <def_link>6540</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6556</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"Ha, there's no deep thought here. A man like me doesn't have time for that. It's just common sense and don't be making me out for some fool of a saint. Like I said, in the end, it's what's good for me that really counts. But I rest easy knowing that what I do helps more than just myself. And it doesn't hurt that everybody that likes to eat likes a farmer. Right?! It's not everybody can do what I do out there."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_farmer01_asked_heart = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Another question?"</text>
          <def_link>6558</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"I should probably let you get back to work." Leave.</text>
          <def_link>6540</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6557</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Eugenius looks stunned. He starts to say something then stops. He chuckles and locks eyes with you, "Why would you tell me this?"</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Sometimes... what's good for one is good for another, right?"</text>
          <def_link>6560</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6559</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>He grins, "Very wise words indeed. I'll consider your suggestion. Thank you."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Another question?"</text>
          <def_link>6558</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"I should probably let you get back to work." Leave.</text>
          <def_link>6540</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6560</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END - bark Get back to work</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>sayPhrase(5280, "I have to get back to work.");</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>6561</UID>
    </dlgPart>
  </parts>
</dlgData>