<?xml version="1.0"?>
<dlgData xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <conditions />
    <links />
    <dlg_name>NPC_MDN_Storyteller_01</dlg_name>
    <def_link>0</def_link>
    <def_speaker_name>A storyteller</def_speaker_name>
    <def_portrait>None</def_portrait>
  </header>
  <parts>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>You see a grizzled old fellow haggling with the innkeeper over a dish of scraps and a cup of watered wine. When they reach an agreement the old man pulls the cup towards him for a long sip, savoring his drink, and reluctantly pours the rest into a bowl of yesterday’s rice. He works the wine into the rice which, along with half an onion, comprises his meal. After finishing, he lets his gaze linger a moment on the empty bowl before turning with a dispirited sigh to address the common room.

“A tale,” he says in a hoarse voice, before pausing to cough explosively. “Harken everyone to a most wondrous tale, a tale I offer exclusively to the most distinguished patrons of this most illustrious establishment!”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>createByCharMarker("CM_MDN_Storyteller");</string>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_Storyteller_01);</string>
        <string>dlgCam(245, 45, 8, 6125);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Stay and listen.</text>
          <def_link>2</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Walk away.</text>
          <def_link>1</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>0</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>MDN_StorytellerCrowd.hideobjects();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeToThisPart();</string>
        <string>dlgDeleteCharacter(6125);</string>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_Storyteller_02);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>1</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Look around you, my friends,” demands the old man. The patrons comply, obviously suspecting it is part of some feeble jest. “No, not at these four walls, you dolts. Look in wonder on the glorious city of Maadoran! Countless cities and towns, village, hamlets have crumbled into dust, or been submerged beneath the waves, or swallowed by the desert sands, but Maadoran survives. For ten thousand years the mighty capitol has stood and for ten thousand years he will continue to stand, watching over –”

“I heard the city was a thousand years old,” interrupts a surly looking metalworker in the crowd.

“And where did you hear that, pray tell?” The storyteller seems to grow in stature, looking down at the man with disdain. “I was born here, as was my father and my father’s father, and his father before him. So which of us knows best, my gritty friend? Now set aside for a while the cackling of geese in the market which is often mistaken for wisdom and you will learn something of this City of All Cities we are all so fortunate to call home.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Keep listening.</text>
          <def_link>3</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Walk away.</text>
          <def_link>1</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Maadoran was old and wise, already a place of philosophers and statesmen, when the Empire was nothing but an upstart kingdom. Yes, they were brawlers, full of strength and bluster, let us give violence its due. But what would have been their end without our art, our knowledge, our wisdom? The Empire had their legions, my esteemed comrades, but there is a limit to what can be accomplished through brutality. Add culture and knowledge to your strength, and you have a potent force.

“The Old Empire has fallen to dust, a heap of cracked stones where once stood mighty walls. Of ancient Aellium nothing remains but faded diagrams on a handful of mildewed scrolls. Maadoran alone stands, her glory scornful of the passing of mere men, of time and decay, her nobles and lords unfazed by...”

“I come inside to get away from the wind, not to bathe in it,” a dusty scribe declares. “Yes, get to the tale, before ye crumble away yeself,” another patron helpfully adds.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Keep listening.</text>
          <def_link>4</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Walk away.</text>
          <def_link>1</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>3</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“I’m getting to the tale,” says the old timer. He smiles still, but his eyes are tight with anger. “I know that such learned folks as yourselves must all have heard of that dismal and storied ruin, that place of terror and woe, commonly named the Abyss? Well, there are rumours, there are tales, and there is truth. I will wager a meal that no one here has heard the truth.”

“And you know this truth?” asks the scribe with a smirk.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>addLore(8);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>5</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>4</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“I certainly do,” the storyteller snaps, for an instant unable to conceal the weary and bitter man he has become. “I happened in my travels upon a loremaster walking alone at the edge of the desert. His apprentice had died on the road the week before, and *worse luck!* his mule soon after. The loremaster himself was clinging to life by the barest thread! I shared my water with him, the only wealth I had to offer for I am as you see a humble man, and in his gratitude he gifted me his finest scroll, a first-hand account of that poisoned zone which history has named the Abyss. This was ten years ago, and the scroll itself is now lost but luckily for you, my friends, I have committed it entire to the vault of my mind.” He taps a finger meaningfully on one temple. “Still, ten years is ten years, and a few of the details may be mixed up, but I promise it is worth your time, and a coin or two besides.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>6</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>5</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“It was during the final days of the Great War,” he begins with a drama running close to the ridiculous, “when earth and sky both were riven by terrible weapons, when catastrophe chased disaster. Entire cities vanished overnight, tens of thousands extinguished like candle flames swamped by the sea.

“Yet Maadoran was impregnable, for no army could breach her mantle of magic. Any who approached were destroyed without mercy, like ants treading a bed of hot coals. But her enemies were as clever as they were relentless. One night the city’s Magi tracked several new stars in the night sky, stars which moved but did not burn out and disappear as their more common brothers. They declared this a dark omen and commanded the minarets and spires to cast their nets just as these cursed beacons began to fall into the city. They were too late, however. One star escaped those nets to land in the venerable District of Wisdom. That was the time when sun dawned in darkest night, and the thunder that arose made the gods themselves tremble. With the real sun rose in the east, all could see that the District of Wisdom was no more. What is left we now call the Abyss.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>7</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“But that is not the end of my story. With that cruel dawn, a strange, misshapen man appeared at the gates. He was haggard and wan and stumbled as though wounded, yet raw power crackled the air around him. When he gestured, the steel gates, twelve feet high, crumpled as if no more than paper in his closed fist. The guards who rushed to meet him bent like reeds in a gale, but from the wind that bowed them they would never spring back. In that instant the city was doomed, for this creature wasn’t a man at all but a demon conjured in the unspeakable rituals of our enemies.

“There was, however, one who dared oppose him: Abu Hassan Ibn Hadad al-Sarabi, First of the Magi. Though the lords of the city all knew him to be doing their good work a thousand miles from Maadoran, he had somehow appeared in her direst need to stand calmly waiting in the path.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>8</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>7</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“The twisted creature sneered at the world’s greatest Magus, using the familiar form of greeting, an insult to such a powerful man, and asked if he still thirsted for knowledge man wasn’t meant to know.

“Calmly, the Magus replied that his thirst had been quenched a long time ago and that his power –and that of his seals– had grown stronger since their last meeting, as the state of the demon’s forlorn and raggedy host did attest.

“The demon had no witty reply to this, but reared up as if to strike him down. To the astonishment of everyone present, including the demon himself, his own limbs refused to obey him. His ribs cracked inwards with a sound like twigs breaking, his legs buckled beneath him, and his eyes turned white, leaving him blind. Sealed within his ruined human form, he was unable to do anything but growl and curse.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>9</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“What did they do with the demon?” inquired the scribe softly. Sometime during the story, the patrons’ taunts and grumbling had faded away, and everyone sat on the edge of his chair, fists clenched, wine forgotten.

“That detail the scroll did not reveal,” says the old man, “but I would venture the demon was locked away for eternity in the most impregnable sort of prison or vault. I mean, what else would you do with such a being?”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Did the scroll mention the name of that demon?”</text>
          <def_link>11</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“What were the Magi working on before the attack on the city?”</text>
          <def_link>15</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“The Abyss used to be called the District of Wisdom?”</text>
          <def_link>12</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Walk away.</text>
          <def_link>1</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“The scroll didn’t say. All I can tell you is that the grandest and tallest building in the city was the House of Magi, a dozen golden towers and silver arches hovering over the city. It is written that the highest pinnacle pierced the clouds, and the lowest catacomb struck dug deep under the earth, anchoring the tower in place. Can you see now what was lost?” He is practically pleading for understanding. “When will we ever rebuild such splendor? How?”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_storytellerMD_asked_magi = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Did the scroll mention the name of that demon?”</text>
          <def_link>11</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.npc_storytellerMD_asked_name == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“The Abyss used to be called the District of Wisdom?”</text>
          <def_link>12</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.npc_storytellerMD_asked_district == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“What do you know about the Gods?”</text>
          <def_link>16</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.npc_storytellerMD_asked_gods == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Walk away.</text>
          <def_link>1</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>15</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“That is correct,” he nods. “It was the heart of Maadoran, a place of temples, libraries and schools... Granted, all I saw was an old drawing but the image left me speechless and filled my heart with sorrow. Loremasters say that the answer to any question could be found in the District of Wisdom, if one knew where to look and whom to ask. Men would come from all over the land to seek out our wisdom. Now the only thing they seek here are the whores.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_storytellerMD_asked_district = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“So, it was like a vast library?”</text>
          <def_link>14</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>12</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Not wholly inaccurate,” he replies pompously, “but it was also much more than that. The ancients mined knowledge the way slaves mine ore. This city boasted the best magi, algebraists, topologists, alchemists, engineers, and astronomers. Maadoran had them all in one place. They walked these streets, breathed the same air, gazed upon the same stars. It was a time of wonder.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_storytellerMD_asked_district = true;</string>
        <string>aod.npc_storytellerMD_askAbout_gods = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Did the scroll mention the name of that demon?”</text>
          <def_link>11</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.npc_storytellerMD_asked_name == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“What were the Magi working on before the attack on the city?”</text>
          <def_link>15</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.npc_storytellerMD_asked_magi == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“What do you know about the Gods?”</text>
          <def_link>16</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.npc_storytellerMD_asked_gods == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Walk away.</text>
          <def_link>1</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>14</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Old wives’ tales,” says the old man dismissively. “Men of wisdom won the War, not Gods. Let these Gods strike me down if I lie.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_storytellerMD_asked_gods = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Did the scroll mention the name of that demon?”</text>
          <def_link>11</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.npc_storytellerMD_asked_name == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“What were the Magi working on before the attack on the city?”</text>
          <def_link>15</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.npc_storytellerMD_asked_magi == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Walk away.</text>
          <def_link>1</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>16</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“It did,” says the storyteller. He is befuddled for a moment, since you’re clearly the first person to ask him that. “Balzurath? Baalzurab? It was an evil sound, like vinegar on the tongue.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_storytellerMD_asked_name = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“What were the Magi working on before the attack on the city?”</text>
          <def_link>15</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.npc_storytellerMD_asked_magi == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“The Abyss used to be called the District of Wisdom?”</text>
          <def_link>12</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.npc_storytellerMD_asked_district == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“What do you know about the Gods?”</text>
          <def_link>16</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.npc_storytellerMD_asked_gods == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Walk away.</text>
          <def_link>1</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>11</UID>
    </dlgPart>
  </parts>
</dlgData>