<?xml version="1.0"?>
<dlgData xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <conditions>
      <string>aod.npc_CT_annalist_met</string>
    </conditions>
    <links>
      <int>11</int>
    </links>
    <dlg_name>NPC_Maximus_01</dlg_name>
    <def_link>0</def_link>
    <def_speaker_name>Maximus</def_speaker_name>
    <def_portrait>None</def_portrait>
  </header>
  <parts>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>You see a short man wearing a simple tunic. In contrast to the legionnaires stomping around everywhere, he looks soft and mild. “May I help you?” he asks, smiling awkwardly. He is plainly not used to social visits.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_CT_annalist_met = true;</string>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_DLG_Annalist_PC);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Who are you?”</text>
          <def_link>1</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>0</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“I’m Maximus Septimius Helva. I have charge of the annals, records and accounts of the Imperial Guard,” says the man with pride.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“The annals?”</text>
          <def_link>2</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>1</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Our history. Where we come from, how much we’ve endured and overcome – it’s all there.” He gestures at the tomes and scrolls around you. “To let the past lapse into dust is to lose everything, for without past there is no future.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“No mercenary has much of a future. You either end up scrambling around on all fours trying to stuff your liver back in its hole, or you live to become a broken down beggar waiting for a copper coin but half the time settling for a young woman’s spit. I know which I prefer.”</text>
          <def_link>3</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“So how did it all start?”</text>
          <def_link>4</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“As you wish.” Maximum folds his arms in his sleeves. He is clearly not the debating kind of scholar.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“So how did it all start?”</text>
          <def_link>4</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>3</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“As the sun rises from deepest night, the brightest hope may be spawned from darkness. Our earliest accounts say that the bulk of the Imperial army perished in the battle for the capital. Our history begins when the survivors made their way to Maadoran but were denied entry.

“Having seized the city by force and fearing that the army would side with House Calani, House Aurelian sealed the soldiers outside the walls. The Lord of the House cited an old law barring the army from entering the capital city and claimed Maadoran as the new capital of the Empire. He claimed that the old ways must be upheld, no matter the cost, hiding behind dusty laws and traditions.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Doesn’t your whole existence revolve around dusty laws and traditions?”</text>
          <def_link>5</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“What happened next?”</text>
          <def_link>6</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>4</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“If you are uninterested it the annals, I assure you I can find something else to occupy my time.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“What happened next?”</text>
          <def_link>6</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>5</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“When House Aurelian closed the gates, fewer than two thousand men were camped outside the walls. A few weeks later, there were more than seven thousand, and while many were wounded or dying, their numbers burgeoned every day. Although one would naturally expect two legions of armed men to sit quietly and starve to death, in this case the situation deteriorated rapidly.

“The regiment known as the Boatmen of Styx left first, all in a group. Other cohorts formed improvised companies and took to raiding. What started with theft and harassment, hitting merchants for food and supplies, quickly grew into attacks on every settlement and caravan within three days’ march.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>7</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“That’s when the Noble Houses made a deal with Legatus Caius Damianus. Some say that Damianus himself orchestrated the crisis to force House Aurelian’s hand. In the absence of documents supporting these allegations, I choose to believe this was a rare example of the Noble Houses making a wise decision. Treating with the army was the best course for everyone.

“Acting on behalf of the Imperial army, Legatus Damianus signed a charter with the seven Noble Houses officially granting the army a special status in exchange for the army recognizing the Houses’ rights and privileges, and swearing to uphold peace and security. When the dust settled, Damianus was Dux.

“The Houses also agreed to supply the newly reformed army with provisions and stores and to absorb the costs of military campaigns against threats both near and far. In essence, the Houses paid us off in order to keep us away from their domains.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“And lived happily ever after?”</text>
          <def_link>12</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>9</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>7</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"If you excuse me," says the annalist, "I have much to do, but very little time."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>9</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>9</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“If you have more questions you'd have to come back later. I really am rather busy at the moment.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>sayPhrase(8021, "If you have more questions you'd have to come back later. I really am rather busy at the moment.");</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>9</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>11</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“In a manner of speaking. Of course, some conflicts are unavoidable, but it is wise to remember that the alternative would have been an all-out war.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“So what happened to the other four Houses?”</text>
          <def_link>13</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>9</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>12</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Let’s see,” says the annalist going through the scrolls. “In the year 4271, House Tal Gazar seized the domain of House Maracas by force and put its lords to the sword. Twelve years later, Tal Gazar’s army was caught by surprise and routed by the Sydonius and Daratan forces, leaving Tal Gazar’s domain defenseless.

“House Tal Gazar appealed to the Imperial Guard for protection, starting a lengthy debate on the Charter’s provisions and amendments, during which House Sydonius razed the city to the ground and brought the last Lord of Tal Gazar to Maadoran in chains to participate in the debate. He was blinded and castrated but allowed to live the rest of his life in captivity and was well cared for, by all accounts.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“And the other two?”</text>
          <def_link>14</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>13</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“House Sydonius was decimated by the Great Plague of 4358 and lost its last remaining holdings to House Almansor, which held the biggest territory until the year of 4417 when Lord Barhalzi was assassinated and his House torn apart during the succession wars. It officially ceased to exist after the fall of Asmara a few years ago when the last living lord of that once noble House was drawn and quartered at the age of twelve.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“So what happened in Cippur?”</text>
          <def_link>8</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>14</UID>
    </dlgPart>
  </parts>
</dlgData>