<?xml version="1.0"?>
<dlgData xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <conditions />
    <links />
    <dlg_name>NPC_Balzaar_01</dlg_name>
    <def_link>8930</def_link>
    <def_speaker_name>Balzaar</def_speaker_name>
    <def_portrait>Balzaar_2</def_portrait>
  </header>
  <parts>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The body that hosts the god Balzaar looks less human with each passing day. The skin has turned glossy and hairless, stretched tight over his skull, and the eyes have become bigger, washed black and unblinking, like those of some bottom-dwelling sea creature, never meant to look on daylight.

He sits more comfortably than ever Meru did in his old seat, as if his form were boneless and melding itself to the shape of the throne. The guards are gone, unnecessary now, and the great hall filled with kneeling worshipers. Their mumbles and prayers can be heard at all hours. To listen to that idiotic drone too long could drive one mad.

Balzaar himself seems to gaze upon them with divine indifference, or perhaps he looks past them with those empty eyes, to some starry reach now lost.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Approach.</text>
          <def_link>8931</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8930</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Do not come before me empty handed again,” says Balzaar. It’s not a threat, it’s a commandment – a rule to be followed by all. The scribes behind him dip their quills in ink and set to work. So it’s written, so it shall be done.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“I won’t.”</text>
          <def_link>8932</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8931</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Balzaar nods and the praying resumes.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>8933</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8932</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>8933</UID>
    </dlgPart>
  </parts>
</dlgData>