<?xml version="1.0"?>
<dlgData xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <conditions>
      <string>aod.quest_IGTrial_fightTrialCombat</string>
    </conditions>
    <links>
      <int>22</int>
    </links>
    <dlg_name>Quest_IGTrial_01</dlg_name>
    <def_link>0</def_link>
    <def_speaker_name>Gaelius</def_speaker_name>
    <def_portrait>Gaelius</def_portrait>
  </header>
  <parts>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait>None</portrait>
      <speaker_name>None</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>You enter the main hall of the Maadoran's palace. At the far end of it, Lord Gaelius holds court, receiving daily visitors in the order of their importance. A row of guards form a barrier between the Lord of the House and the petitioners, with blank stares on their faces. Another row forms a semi-circle around Gaelius, their eyes constantly scanning the crowd.

Erastus quickly explains the situation to a legatus, while Lord Gaelius listens carefully, glancing in your direction. He asks the legatus something before gesturing for you to approach.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_DLG_Gaelius_03);</string>
        <string>useCameraBookmark(CAM_NPC_Gaelius_01);</string>
        <string>addJournalChar(gaelius);</string>
        <string>aod.npc_gaelius_trial = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Approach.</text>
          <def_link>2</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>0</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“As I’m sure you know,” says Gaelius addressing his court, “Lord Antidas has been slain in his own palace. Slain not by the outside forces seeking to bring chaos to our cities, but by the enemies within, those who were supposed to defend us from very chaos they’ve unleashed.

“The Imperial Guards,” Gaelius makes a meaningful pause, letting the crowd grasp the gravity of the situation. “One of the murderers is here today, to plead &lt;his/her&gt; innocence and try to convince us that the attack on a sovereign lord was somehow justified.” The crowd isn’t impressed with you so far. Gaelius smiles and turns his attention to you.

“Speak, villain!”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_DLG_Gaelius_01);</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“My Lord, it is the Imperial Guards who were attacked. Our only crime was to defend ourselves from an unprovoked attack.”</text>
          <def_link>3</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“A Lord who can’t protect his domain isn’t much of a lord. Teron was constantly attacked, while Antidas sat there and did nothing. We were forced to act, since nobody else did.”</text>
          <def_link>24</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“So you say, but what proof do you have?”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“There were only seven of us, my Lord. If the Imperial Guards had something sinister in mind, would they not sent more men?”</text>
          <def_link>4</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>3</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“What were the Imperial Guards doing in Lord Antidas’ palace in the first place?”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[streetwise]“Lord Antidas was planning a military operation and requested our help. Commander Carrinas sent me and my men. When we were told what Lord Antidas had in mind, I refused. At that moment, we were attacked.”</text>
          <def_link>5</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.streetwise &gt;= 4</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>6</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“We were sent to notify Lord Antidas that the Imperial Guards have invoked the Charter.”</text>
          <def_link>18</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>4</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[failure]“You expect us to believe that? That a man like Antidas would act like a spoiled child? I think we’ve heard enough – take &lt;him/her&gt; away!”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Wait! I demand a trial by combat!”</text>
          <def_link>19</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>5</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[success]You deliver the lines perfectly – a soldier reporting to an officer, describing events without any doubts or hesitation. The story raises many questions, yet you hope Gaelius would ask the right one.

He struggles for a brief moment, then asks, “What did Lord Antidas have in mind?” Perfect. It’s time for some sensationalism.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“He wanted to attack Maadoran, my Lord.”</text>
          <def_link>7</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The crowd’s reaction exceeds your wildest expectations, but Gaelius isn’t as easy to sway.

“I’ll ask you once again, what proof do you have of his intentions? It’s easy to turn dead men into villains, for they can’t speak in their own defence.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Proof? Did you think that the attack on your mine site was just a coincidence?”</text>
          <def_link>13</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.ending_outpost_attacked || aod.ending_outpost_blewUp || aod.ending_outpost_witness</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.ending_outpost_attacked</string>
            <string>aod.ending_outpost_blewUp</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>15</int>
            <int>17</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[lore success][persuasion]“How many times have Antidas fought against House Aurelian in the past? His enmity toward you is hardly a secret, my Lord.”</text>
          <def_link>8</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.lore &gt;= 3</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.persuasion &gt;= 4</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>12</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[charisma][word of honor]“How can I offer you a proof of a lord’s intentions? If such things exist, they would be out of reach of a simple soldier. All I have is my word and that’s all I can offer you.”</text>
          <def_link>8</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>dlgGetRep(honor) &lt; 1</string>
            <string>aod.cha &gt;= 7 &amp;&amp; dlgGetRep(honor) &gt;= 1</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>9</int>
            <int>10</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>7</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[success]“I guess not,” says Gaelius quietly, lost in his thoughts. “Your news is troubling, but not that surprising in the end. It underlines the need to act in order to protect what’s left...

“You’re free to go, &lt;charname&gt;,” he says suddenly. “I’m satisfied with your explanation and believe that you’ve acted without malice.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>rwd_civil(IG_Trial_01);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>11</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>12</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[success]“Very well,” says Gaelius. “I’m satisfied with your explanation and believe that you’ve acted without malice. You’re free to go.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>rwd_civil(IG_Trial_01);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>11</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>10</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[failure]“As much as I’d like to believe you, we have to err on the side of caution. Take &lt;him/her&gt; away!”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Wait! I demand a trial by combat!”</text>
          <def_link>19</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>8</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[word of honor failure]“Your word?” scoffs Gaelius. “We’ve heard enough, take &lt;him/her&gt; away!”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Wait! I demand a trial by combat!”</text>
          <def_link>19</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Gaelius gives you a sharp look. “Our site was indeed attacked and taken over by the Daratan soldiers, although some reports tell us that a &lt;man/woman&gt; matching your description was also involved.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“I assure you of my innocence, my Lord.”</text>
          <def_link>14</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>13</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“I’ll take your word for it. For now,” says Gaelius with irritation. “You're free to go.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>11</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>14</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“It was my understanding that the site was attacked by raiders,” says Gaelius, frowning.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Antidas paid them to attack the mine and then had the survivors killed.”</text>
          <def_link>16</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>15</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“It was my understanding that there was an accident at the mine site,” says Gaelius, frowning.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Antidas sent one of his men to overload the smelter.”</text>
          <def_link>16</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>17</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Did he?” says Gaelius quietly, lost in his thoughts. “Your news is troubling, but not that surprising in the end. It underlines the need to act in order to protect what’s left...

“You’re free to go, &lt;charname&gt;,” he says suddenly. “I’m satisfied with your explanation and believe that you’ve acted without malice.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>rwd_civil(IG_Trial_01);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>11</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>16</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“In other words, you were sent to tell him that you’re taking his own town from him? You provoked him and then murdered him in his own palace,” states Gaelius firmly.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“The Charter’s provisions are very clear. If Lord Antidas had issues with them, he should have sought the counsel of his peers, not attacked the men who were doing their duty.”</text>
          <def_link>24</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Surely, my Lord is not implying that the Charter – a set of laws agreed by the seven Great Houses – is nothing but an excuse to take and provoke?”</text>
          <def_link>25</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>18</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“I require no lectures on the Charter from common brigands,” states Gaelius with the natural arrogance of a noble-born.

“The Charter was written centuries ago. Its importance and influence can’t be overstated,” he glances at a group of lords who look old enough to remember the Charter being drafted, “but it was never meant to replace common sense when dealing with *today’s* problems.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[lore success][persuasion]“You have most progressive views, my Lord, but in less enlightened places we still follow the Charter – a document that gave us guidance during the dark centuries after the fall and will undoubtedly continue to guide us in the future.”</text>
          <def_link>28</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.lore &gt;= 3</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.persuasion &gt;= 4</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>29</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[persuasion][streetwise]“Another month and we’d have lost Teron to raiders. Would you consider it a better outcome? Would the interests of House Aurelian, as well as those of the lords of this city, have been served better, if raiders were allowed to turn Teron into a stronghold, from which to attack Maadoran?”</text>
          <def_link>28</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>(aod.persuasion + aod.streetwise) &gt;= 7</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>30</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[streetwise][etiquette]“Protecting Teron from the raiders was our only concern. Had Lord Antidas acted with restraint and wisdom befitting a man of his station, we could have discussed the situation in the most impartial manner and found a suitable solution. Unfortunately, he had chosen to attack the delegation, which only highlighted his inability to govern.”</text>
          <def_link>28</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>(aod.streetwise + aod.etiquette) &gt;= 7</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>30</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>25</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Who are you to take it upon yourself to judge a lord and offer opinions on what he should and shouldn’t do? We all have our own lots. Yours is to serve and obey!”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Have you confused the Imperial Guards with peasants toiling in your fields, *my Lord*? We serve only the Empire and you’d do well to remember that.”</text>
          <def_link>26</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“I didn’t judge Antidas. The Charter did. If memory serves me right, it was written by men whose blood was as noble as yours, my Lord.”</text>
          <def_link>27</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>24</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“I require no lectures on the Charter from common brigands,” states Gaelius with the natural arrogance of a noble-born.

“You claim that the Charter judged Antidas and condemned him to death, yet the Charter is nothing but a dusty old tome. It doesn’t judge. It doesn’t condemn. It doesn’t kill in the name of the greater good.

“The truth is obvious to everyone. The Imperial Guards have murdered the Lord of House Daratan and then hid behind an ancient document, thinking that it will shield them from justice!” Gaelius’ voice gains strength and volume with every word.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Hid behind?” It’s your turn to scoff. “The Charter explicitly entrusts the Imperial Guards with the task of securing the towns and stepping in, should it ever become necessary.”</text>
          <def_link>31</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[persuasion][streetwise]“Another month and we’d have lost Teron to raiders. Would you consider it a better outcome? Would the interests of House Aurelian, as well as those of the lords of this city, have been served better, if raiders were allowed to turn Teron into a stronghold, from which to attack Maadoran?”</text>
          <def_link>28</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>(aod.persuasion + aod.streetwise) &gt;= 7</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>30</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>27</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“And who determines that? The Imperial Guards? Are they the impartial judge who has the power to remove lords from power and even kill them, ‘should it ever become necessary’?”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[lore success][persuasion]“The Charter does, my Lord. That's why it was written. It states explicitly the duties and responsibilities of the Noble Houses and the Imperials Guards. Our duty is to defend all and any Imperial property if it is in direct danger of being attacked, and that's exactly what we did.”</text>
          <def_link>28</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.lore &gt;= 3</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.persuasion &gt;= 4</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>29</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[persuasion][streetwise]“Another month and we’d have lost Teron to raiders. Would you consider it a better outcome? Would the interests of House Aurelian, as well as those of the lords of this city, have been served better, if raiders were allowed to turn Teron into a stronghold, from which to attack Maadoran?”</text>
          <def_link>28</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>(aod.persuasion + aod.streetwise) &gt;= 7</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>30</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[streetwise][etiquette]“Protecting Teron from the raiders was our only concern. Had Lord Antidas acted with restraint and wisdom befitting a man of his station, we could have discussed the situation in the most impartial manner and found a suitable solution. Unfortunately, he had chosen to attack the delegation, which only highlighted his inability to govern.”</text>
          <def_link>28</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>(aod.streetwise + aod.etiquette) &gt;= 7</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>30</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>31</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“And you’d do well to remember whom you’re talking to,” snaps Gaelius. “Take &lt;him/her&gt; away!”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Wait! I demand a trial by combat!”</text>
          <def_link>19</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>26</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[failure]Your words fail to have the desired effect.

“We’ve heard enough,” says Gaelius seizing the opportunity to get rid of you. “Take &lt;him/her&gt; away!”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“Wait! I demand a trial by combat!”</text>
          <def_link>19</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>28</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[success]Gaelius cringes, but the white beards nod in agreement and murmur.

“Well, it does appear that you’ve acted in accordance with the Charter after all,” says Gaelius smoothly. “I’m satisfied with the explanation you’ve given us and believe that you’ve acted without malice.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>rwd_civil(IG_Trial_01);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>11</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>29</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[success]Judging by the reaction, the crowd doesn’t care all that much about Antidas, but raiders attacking Maadoran – that gets their attention.

“I don’t think we’ll ever get to the bottom of this,” says Gaelius, changing his tune, “but it appears that some good did come out of this. Teron is secured, which gives us time to decide what to do with it later.

“You’re free to go, &lt;charname&gt;. We thank you for your testimony.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>rwd_civil(IG_Trial_01);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>11</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>30</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeToThisPart();</string>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_Map_Gate);</string>
        <string>setRtsCam();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>11</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“Trial by combat? You must have heard too many stories about the olden days growing up,” says Gaelius with a smirk. The legatus whispers something in his ear and Gaelius smiles, nodding slightly.

“It's your lucky day, soldier. It seems that we'll be able to accomodate your request after all.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>createByCharMarker("CM_IG_Trial_Criminal_01");</string>
        <string>createByCharMarker("CM_IG_Trial_Criminal_02");</string>
        <string>createByCharMarker("CM_IG_Trial_Criminal_03");</string>
        <string>createByCharMarker("CM_IG_Trial_Criminal_04");</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Go with the legatus.</text>
          <def_link>20</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>19</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait>None</portrait>
      <speaker_name>Legatus</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>The legatus takes you to a small square planted with crosses, some empty, some occupied. Four shackled prisoners are sitting on the ground, waiting to be executed. Several guards are standing nearby.

"Change of plans, boys," says the legatus. "We're going to have a trial by combat here, like in the stories. Since the charges against the defendant are grave, &lt;he/she&gt; will have to fight this whole lot. Kill them and you're a free &lt;man/woman&gt;.

"You kill &lt;him/her&gt;," he says, addressing the prisoners, "you will be freed and expelled from the city." He gestures and the guards start distributing bronze gladii to the combatants.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>addParty(IGTrialCriminals, 0);</string>
        <string>addCharToParty(5130, IGTrialCriminals, fighter);</string>
        <string>addCharToParty(5131, IGTrialCriminals, fighter);</string>
        <string>addCharToParty(5132, IGTrialCriminals, fighter);</string>
        <string>addCharToParty(5133, IGTrialCriminals, fighter);</string>
        <string>dlgFadeToThisPart();</string>
        <string>dlgSetAnimation(anim_beg00_ambient_02, 0.25, 5130);</string>
        <string>dlgSetAnimation(anim_beg00_ambient_02, 0.25, 5131);</string>
        <string>dlgSetAnimation(anim_beg00_ambient_02, 0.25, 5132);</string>
        <string>dlgSetAnimation(anim_beg00_ambient_02, 0.25, 5133);</string>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_IGTrialByCombat_01);</string>
        <string>dlgAddItem(110, 1);</string>
        <string>dlgRemoveItem(102, 1);</string>
        <string>setRtsCam();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Are you going to give me a weapon?"</text>
          <def_link>32</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>20</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait>None</portrait>
      <speaker_name>Legatus</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>"Tell me what you need, soldier. I owe you a fair fight - within reasons, of course - and that's what you're going to get."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"A dagger."</text>
          <def_link>33</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"A sword."</text>
          <def_link>35</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"An axe."</text>
          <def_link>36</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"A hammer."</text>
          <def_link>37</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"A spear."</text>
          <def_link>38</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"A bow."</text>
          <def_link>39</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"A crossbow."</text>
          <def_link>40</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Throwing knives."</text>
          <def_link>41</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>32</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait>None</portrait>
      <speaker_name>Legatus</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>"A dagger? Are you a thief or a soldier?" He gives you a bronze pugio.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgAddItem(102, 1);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"How about a shield?"</text>
          <def_link>34</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Start the trial.</text>
          <def_link>21</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>33</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait>None</portrait>
      <speaker_name>Legatus</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>"A soldier's weapon." He gives you a bronze gladius.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgAddItem(110, 1);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"How about a shield?"</text>
          <def_link>34</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Start the trial.</text>
          <def_link>21</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>35</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait>None</portrait>
      <speaker_name>Legatus</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>"A raiders' weapon. Run with the wolves, learn how to howl?" He gives you a bronze zaghnal.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgAddItem(120, 1);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"How about a shield?"</text>
          <def_link>34</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Start the trial.</text>
          <def_link>21</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>36</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait>None</portrait>
      <speaker_name>Legatus</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>"Didn't take you for a smith." He gives you a bronze marculus.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgAddItem(130, 1);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"How about a shield?"</text>
          <def_link>34</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Start the trial.</text>
          <def_link>21</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>37</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait>None</portrait>
      <speaker_name>Legatus</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>"A spear against four men?" He gives you a bronze hasta.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgAddItem(140, 1);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"How about a shield?"</text>
          <def_link>34</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Start the trial.</text>
          <def_link>21</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>38</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait>None</portrait>
      <speaker_name>Legatus</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>"Better not miss then. When the arrows run out, you're as good as dead." He gives you a Kemetian bow and two dozen of arrows.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgAddItem(300, 25);</string>
        <string>dlgAddItem(152, 1);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Start the trial.</text>
          <def_link>21</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>39</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait>None</portrait>
      <speaker_name>Legatus</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>"Better not miss then. When the bolts run out, you're as good as dead." He gives you a standard crossbow and two dozen of bolts.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgAddItem(161, 1);</string>
        <string>dlgAddItem(300, 25);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Start the trial.</text>
          <def_link>21</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>40</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait>None</portrait>
      <speaker_name>Legatus</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>"Throwing knives? Now, that I'd like to see."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgAddItem(170, 25);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"How about a shield?"</text>
          <def_link>34</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Start the trial.</text>
          <def_link>21</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>41</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait>None</portrait>
      <speaker_name>Legatus</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>"What's next? Armor and some servants? Take this buckler and get on with it."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgAddItem(1700, 1);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Start the trial.</text>
          <def_link>21</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>34</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>FIGHT</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>aod.quest_IGTrial_fightTrialCombat = true;</string>
        <string>dlgEquipItem(110, 0, 5130);</string>
        <string>dlgEquipItem(110, 0, 5131);</string>
        <string>dlgEquipItem(110, 0, 5132);</string>
        <string>dlgEquipItem(110, 0, 5133);</string>
        <string>addEnemyToParty(1, IGTrialCriminals);</string>
        <string>dlgFadeToThisPart();</string>
        <string>aod.fight_IGTrialByCombat = true;</string>
        <string>setRtsCam();</string>
        <string>schedule(100, 0, dlgStartCombat);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>21</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait>None</portrait>
      <speaker_name>Legatus</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>"Well, what do you know?" says the legatus. "Looks like you are innocent of all charges.

"Welcome to Maadoran, &lt;son/girl&gt;."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>11</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>22</UID>
    </dlgPart>
  </parts>
</dlgData>