<?xml version="1.0"?>
<dlgData xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <conditions />
    <links />
    <dlg_name>Quest_God_ALK</dlg_name>
    <def_link>9000</def_link>
    <def_speaker_name>None</def_speaker_name>
    <def_portrait>None</def_portrait>
  </header>
  <parts>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>You walk slowly toward the seven sarcophagi, one of which waits with the lid raised on a metal hinge, like an open maw. Bennie is trembling with excitement as he assists you into the container, reminding you of an overeager priest, ushering an elderly &lt;man/woman&gt; into &lt;his/her&gt; coffin.

The interior looks uncomfortable, like the inside of a drain pipe, but as you recline the surface yields and reforms itself in the shape of your body. One might assume this feature is for the subject’s comfort, but after Bennie has secured a bizarrely shaped helmet over your head and strapped your arms and legs into place, you realize that you are unable to shift your position in the slightest. The lid descends without a whisper to enclose you completely and your mind races in preparation for what is to come.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>setWindowImage("alk_godRitual_01");</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>9001</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9000</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The chamber begins to vibrate as the machines beneath it hum to life. For a long time there is no other sound or sensation. You begin to suspect that nothing will happen, the equipment has failed. But then you become aware of a presence. You feel like a fisherman seeing an enormous shadow passing beneath your boat. It is probably harmless, a whale perhaps, but perhaps not.

The narrow tube is gone and you are floating weightless in a warm, rolling sea, the place between worlds. Your only feeling is expectation. Change is imminent, a change as inexplicable as that of a writhing larva to a flying jeweled creature.

The shadow grows. The ritual of the sarcophagus has distorted the fabric between the worlds, allowing whatever casts the shadow to move closer. The gossamer surface parts as it reaches out for you. The touch is gentle. You are cradled like a colorful bug in the hands of a child. Then the pain comes.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>9002</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9001</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>You return to the darkness of the sarcophagus, the immobility of the restraints. You hear drops of blood, your blood, spatter on the floor. Time is lost to you in the blackness. Hours or days might have passed, or merely minutes.

But the shadow is with you still, and no longer without. Slowly, the understanding dawns that something else, some alien entity, shares your mind.

A parallel series of thoughts moves alongside your own. You sense an instruction to your hands, motivated by that other will, but the wards resist the imposter. Next your mouth begins speaking weird syllables, meaningless to you. You press your lips together and it stops.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[intelligence]Take control.</text>
          <def_link>9003</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.int &gt;= 7</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>9005</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9002</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[failure]Adrenaline floods your veins and every muscle in your body tenses. You rage against the intruder, push back against the strange motivations in your mind, at once trying to understand them and reject them.

Yet the stranger resists.

Its commands grow stronger and your will is weakening, fading. A ragged scream escapes you as you lose ground, but your throat closes on a whimper. Your awareness shrinks, your anger dulls, and the struggle is over. You collapse in the restraints of the black sarcophagus that has become your tomb.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Better luck next time?</text>
          <def_link>9004</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9003</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>DEAD</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeLongToThisPart();</string>
        <string>disconnect();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>9004</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[success]Your primal instinct, the will to survive at all costs, is something the immortal entity cannot understand. With the assistance of the wards and the focus of your intelligence, you are able to push the invader back, leaving it confused and frustrated. You realize that simply defying the Other is not enough. Instead you isolate one of its directives –it is trying to find a way to communicate with Bennie, to command him to open the container– and dismiss it.

Your attack takes the entity by surprise. Vying for control of your corporeal form, it continues to hammer against the wards, but does not understand the threat coming from the primitive mind it shares.

Slowly, painfully, you gain ground, forcing it to submit to your will. All at once, the left side of your face goes numb.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[constitution]A stroke would be an unfortunate setback. Push forward.</text>
          <def_link>9006</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.con &gt;= 7</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>9007</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9005</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[failure]Too late! The stress of the struggle within you is too much. Your organs rupture one by one, your brain starts hemorrhaging, and you who would be a god die shivering, locked already in your tomb, your goal a hairsbreadth out of reach.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Betrayed by your own body...</text>
          <def_link>9004</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9006</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[success]Your rage carries the fight as you punish the weakened entity with everything you’ve got, extinguishing its directives faster than they arise. Your body has begun to break down under the stress of the struggle but, racked with pain and bleeding from your nose and ears, you consume the enemy consciousness, absorb it, make your own.

Your awareness changes and expands. You become aware of your own form as if it were laid out before an omniscient master surgeon. You note with annoyance that the heart is about to give up, and in the next instant it has been repaired, and strengthened besides. As an afterthought, you create some improvements as well.

The inefficiency of your body becomes obvious in a way you had never considered before. Why burn a torch to defeat the darkness when you can simply expand your visual range into different spectrums? And the whole system of extracting oxygen from the air and carrying it to the cells is laughable.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>9008</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9007</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>You spend some time adding redundant systems and extending an internal carapace to shield your lower organs. After so much hard work to accomplish your goals it wouldn’t do to be slain by a stray missile or energy weapon.

When you are satisfied, you reach out with your mind to manipulate a switch in the base of the sarcophagus and the lid is smoothly raised. You step out into the chamber. Bennie drops to his knees and prostrates himself before you. He will be rewarded. He is the first man to recognize your divinity, the first human to submit to your will.

But not the last.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFadeToThisPart();</string>
        <string>if(aod.gender == 1) setWindowImage("alk_godRitual_02");</string>
        <string>if(aod.gender == 0) setWindowImage("alk_godRitual_03");</string>
        <string>setAchievement("ACH_ONE_GOD");</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>The World is Yours.</text>
          <def_link>9009</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>9008</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>ENDING - god</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>SS_start("god_ending", "disconnect();");</string>
        <string>dlgFadeLongToThisPart();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>9009</UID>
    </dlgPart>
  </parts>
</dlgData>