<?xml version="1.0"?>
<dlgData xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <conditions />
    <links />
    <dlg_name>Quest_Abyss_02_Console</dlg_name>
    <def_link>4507</def_link>
    <def_speaker_name>None</def_speaker_name>
    <def_portrait>None</def_portrait>
  </header>
  <parts>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>You're standing in front of the console.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[lore]Examine the console.</text>
          <def_link>4493</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.lore &gt;= 8</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>4494</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Do not meddle in that which you do not understand. Touch nothing and leave.</text>
          <def_link>4436</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>4507</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>setRtsCam();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>4436</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[failure]You tinker around for a while but are forced to admit the machines are far beyond your understanding.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[lore]Examine the console.</text>
          <def_link>4493</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.lore &gt;= 8</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>4494</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Do not meddle in that which you do not understand. Touch nothing and leave.</text>
          <def_link>4436</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>4493</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[success]The console is beyond your understanding, so you place your faith in the mantras. Of course, the problem with mantras is that you have no way to know which one will apply. You try the Mantra of Suspending The Ordinary Functioning Of, which you thought was a safe bet until you realize that it requires you to replace one function with another. Next, you try the Mantra of Divine Guidance only to realize midway that you’re missing the famed golden arrows to which it frequently refers. With desperation hanging over you like a dark cloud, you finally decide to attempt the Mantra of Actions and Reactions. This bloated text has been enlarged by generations of philosophers eager to add their mark to history, and for this reason is ignored by more reputable loremasters.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>4495</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>4494</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Just as you are working through the last instructions of the Mantra of Actions and Reactions, the console begins to respond, confirming that you have chosen the correct text. This mantra focuses on things that act and things that react, suggesting that the right sequence can cause a chain reaction. By following the directives in the correct order, you believe you can either initiate these reactions within the three dead machines, or power down the last working machine.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Power up the three dormant machines.</text>
          <def_link>4498</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Deactivate the last working machine.</text>
          <def_link>4496</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Do not meddle in that which you do not understand. Touch nothing else and leave.</text>
          <def_link>4436</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>4495</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Reciting the words as you go along, you follow the steps until the last machine goes silent. The creature in the tank does not stir, but its breathing gets more and more shallow, until it stops. You have slain the monster.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgAddRank(49);</string>
        <string>setAchievement("ACH_GODLSAYER");</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>4497</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>4496</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>You step outside and see that the fog has lifted. The entire crater is now visible, a vast ugly hole covered in ruins and scattered with skulls and bones, more bones than you’ve ever seen in one place. Perhaps, it looked better when it was hidden by fog.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.quest_abyss_fogLifted = true;</string>
        <string>thelevelinfo.fogdensity = "0.00025";</string>
        <string>thelevelinfo.apply();</string>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_Crater_TopNoFog_01);</string>
        <string>dlgFadeLongToThisPart();</string>
        <string>theSun.brightness = 1.6;</string>
        <string>thesun.ambient = "0.34 0.34 0.30 1";</string>
        <string>theSun.apply();</string>
        <string>VCO_AbyssEntrance.setActive(false);</string>
        <string>CraterInteriorStuff.hideObjects();</string>
        <string>useCameraBookmark(CAM_topNoFog);</string>
        <string>rwd_quest(MDN_Abyss_02);</string>
        <string>aod.jnl_einar_phase3 = true;</string>
        <string>aod.ending_mdn_character_abyssGod = true;</string>
        <string>abyssThunder.stop();</string>
        <string>apmsPlayMusic(custom, 5, 1);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>4505</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>4497</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END - no fog</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_Crater_Top);</string>
        <string>setRtsCam();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>4505</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Reciting the words as you go along, you follow the steps until one of the machines rattles to life with a loud pitching noise, which eventually settles into a deep hum. As newly augmented power flows into the tank, something else starts pouring out: images, visions, memories are flooding your mind.

At one moment, you are standing on a battlefield of long ago, men around you dying by the thousands, and *you* are the one exterminating them. Though you are not physically present, you are seeing them in your mind and striking them down from far away. Next, you’re experiencing the agony of losing that vital part of you that was never yours.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Activate another machine.</text>
          <def_link>4500</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Deactivate all the machines.</text>
          <def_link>4496</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>4498</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>More power flows into the tank and more visions pour out, but you are no longer sure they *are* visions. As the chamber shakes and debris showers down from the ceiling, the agony of the creature in the tank becomes more real than ever. You fall to your knees, you are bleeding from the nose and trying to crawl away. You are crawling over piles of corpses, recently killed and still bloody. You are crawling toward something... A sarcophagus? A tank? A pyramid and a beam of light against a black sky? You no longer know where you are or what is real.

The pain is the one thing that is undoubtedly genuine. It rushes over you, each wave worse than the one before, until you are submerged. You feel like you’re being born, or reborn, made anew by someone or something that cares little about what you are feeling, or even whether you live through it.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Activate another machine.</text>
          <def_link>4501</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.con &gt;= 6</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>4502</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Deactivate all the machines.</text>
          <def_link>4496</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>4500</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[constitution failure]As the last device powers up and adds its hum to the others, the waves of agony coming from the tank become too much for you. Blood rises in your throat, pours from your ears and nose. You experience unbearable, excruciating pain as your body hemorrhages in a dozen places at once, and then you feel nothing at all.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>setAchievement("ACH_DESTROYED_MAADORAN");</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>The Abyss claims another victim.</text>
          <def_link>4499</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>4501</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>DEAD</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeLongToThisPart();</string>
        <string>disconnect();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>4499</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[constitution success]As the last device powers up and adds its hum to the others, the waves of agony coming from the tank become stronger still. Then abruptly, the pain is gone. The visions continue, but your mind has gone numb to the torment emanating from the thing in the tank.

You are looking down upon Maadoran from high above, watching the city from an invisible peak somewhere above the Abyss, and you are full of an all-consuming, inexplicable rage. The only thing you had wished for was peace, yet always it was denied to you. The city is the source of your torment, the city and its ever-growing thousands, crawling like insects through your brain, poisoning your sleep with their endless questions and thoughts and worries.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>setAchievement("ACH_DESTROYED_MAADORAN");</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>4503</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>4502</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Your rage overwhelms you and you lash out. When your fury is unleashed, it is not in the form of fist or sword or spear, but something larger, something huge, immensely powerful and beautiful. Where buildings – where entire districts – once stood, now there is dust, where men and women and children lived, bloody stains. Their screams in your mind are like music, for they are not the actual cries of the dying thousands, but better: the final tortured thoughts of the city, which has troubled your peace for the last time. You lash out again and again, until the loose bricks and mountains of rubble are perfect in their silence, and then the fog descends, slowly covering all.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>rwd_quest(MDN_Abyss_02);</string>
        <string>dlgAddRank(51);</string>
        <string>aod.pc_mindShield = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Run.</text>
          <def_link>4504</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>4503</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>ENDING - Maadoran destroyed</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeLongToThisPart();</string>
        <string>aod.ending_mdn_town_destroyed = true;</string>
        <string>aod.ending_mdn_character_abyssGod = true;</string>
        <string>aod.mdn_destroyed = true;</string>
        <string>blockMapLocation("Maadoran");</string>
        <string>removePcMember();</string>
        <string>SS_start("MDN_ending", "switchMission(\"Ganezzar.mis\");");</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>4504</UID>
    </dlgPart>
  </parts>
</dlgData>