<?xml version="1.0"?>
<dlgData xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <conditions>
      <string>aod.npc_storyteller_hadad</string>
    </conditions>
    <links>
      <int>1784</int>
    </links>
    <dlg_name>Storyteller_01</dlg_name>
    <def_link>1765</def_link>
    <def_speaker_name>Storyteller</def_speaker_name>
    <def_portrait>none</def_portrait>
  </header>
  <parts>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>You see the inn's patrons begin to gather around a strangely garbed man, who paces in circles, muttering. A murmur of expectation runs through the room and sure enough, the man stops his pacing, turns, and with a dramatic flourish cries out "A tale!" All are quiet now, but the man's rich, deep voice rolls out to fill the silence. "A tale for tonight's entertainment! And what a tale! History itself will unfold before your very eyes, a tale of mystery and wonder! Come one, come all, and listen!"</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>useCameraBookmark(NPC_Storyteller_cam_01);</string>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_Storyteller_PC_01);</string>
        <string>dlgRotateToChar(2060);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Stay and listen.</text>
          <def_link>1766</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>1780</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>1765</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"If you want to hear more stories, you'll have to come later, my friend. My throat is parched, I'm afraid."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>useCameraBookmark(NPC_Storyteller_cam_01);</string>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_Storyteller_PC_01);</string>
        <string>dlgRotateToChar(2060);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Can I ask you a few questions at least?"</text>
          <def_link>1783</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>1780</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>1784</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name>none</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>The smile drops from the storyteller's face, his brow gathers into a frown and he begins to speak in a low, sombre tone.

"The Great War raged across the Empire, the frenzied Qantari burning and looting their way across the land, our brave Legions fighting to stem the tide. But, though they could hold the Qantari themselves, even they were no match for the terrible demons the Qantari had brought with them from their homeland. Our loyal soldiers were slaughtered by the thousands. The Emperor's Magi sought to counter the terrible might of the Demons with their magics, but even though they worked feverishly to devise new spells, it was of no use; the Demons shrugged off every incantation the Magi hurled at them.

"Desperate for a solution, the Emperor summoned Abu Hassan Ibn Hadad al-Sarabi, the First of the Magi, to his side in the Holiest of Chambers, deep under the palace."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_storyteller_hadad = true;</string>
        <string>addLore(0);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>1767</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>1766</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name>none</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>"Oh Learned One, tell me," said the Emperor. "Tell me that you have found a solution, o wisest of my servants. Tell me that you have discovered some weakness in the accursed Qantari demons. Tell me how we can destroy these monsters, who feel no pain, no fear, who never tire or rest."

"And Abu Hassan Ibn Hadad did stroke his beard gravely..."

The storyteller stops to mime Ibn Hadad's gesture, folding his arms, looking thoughtful and stroking an imaginary beard to the chuckles of the audience, before continuing.

"...and said to his Emperor, "We must seek allies!"</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>1768</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>1767</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name>none</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>"The Emperor looked at Ibn Hadad in bewilderment. "Allies? What allies can we call upon? The Empire stretches from coast to coast, all men except the steppe nomads rally to fight under my banner. There are no more allies to call on!"

"Mortal allies, yes! But there are other worlds than this one, my Emperor. Higher than the eye can see and further than any man can travel, there are strange and bewildering realms, realms for which the rigid laws of our reality are merely...suggestions. If we could persuade the beings who reside in those realms to come to our aid..."

"The Emperor sat for a moment, considering. But always he returned to that inescapable truth, that the Empire was dying around him. "How many of these beings would answer our call? And would they be enough? The Demons are terrible in their power."

"I have stridden the paths of the future in my dreams and I have seen three who would come to our aid. Together, their might is a match for the Demons," answered Ibn Hadad confidently.

The Emperor cast his hands in the air, hope alight in his face for the first time. "Truly the world is wondrous! You have my blessing, Magus, go forth and call up these allies. All the resources of the Empire are at your disposal!"</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>1769</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>1768</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name>none</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>"Ibn Hadad returned to his tower and once again travelled the paths of the future. For three days and three nights he quested. When at last he emerged, he summoned a great conclave of his brothers. There, he ordered them to build a great doorway, a path into the realm that can't be reached by land or by sea. Working together, the Magi built the doorway that would have taken mortal men months in mere weeks, though many died of the exertion. When it was done, Ibn Hadad blessed the doorway himself and ordered one of the brothers through, as an emissary to the other realms. Patiently they waited for their emissary to return, and return he did a day later. But when they attempted to talk to him he seemed unable to recognize anyone, and had lost the very power of speech itself!

"Undeterred, Ibn Hadad sent forth another emissary, and then a third when the same fate befell that one, but it was no use, none could speak of what they had seen through the doorway."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>1770</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>1769</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name>none</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>"At last Ibn Hadad sent them away and returned to his tower, to travel the paths of the future one last time. When he returned to his brothers he appeared visibly aged, bent and leaning on his staff of office. But he had an answer. He had his brothers forge him a helmet of the finest crystal, weaving potent magic through and around it. Then Ibn Hadad did take the helmet and place it upon his own head, and though his brothers begged him not to, did stride through the gate himself."

The storyteller stops for a moment, surveying his audience. All eyes are on him, the audience held rapt by his story. He smiles slightly, then continues.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>1785</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>1770</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name>none</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>"For seven days and seven nights his brethren held vigil before the doorway. But on the eighth day, as most had given him up for lost, Ibn Hadad returned. When his brothers questioned him as to why he had been gone so long, he seemed shocked that so much time had passed. But thoughts of the Demons weighed heavily upon him, he brushed aside their questions and announced that he had made a deal with those who dwell in the darkness on the other side of the doorway.

"The Lords of that place had agreed to send three of their number to aid the Empire, in exchange seven times seven men would go through the doorway to honour the Lords in their realm. Seven times seven were chosen to follow Ibn Hadad back through the doorway to the otherworldly realms, and true to their word, a week later he returned with three of the Lords accompanying him. Of the other men who accompanied him, there was no sign."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>1771</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>1785</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name>none</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>The storyteller stops talking and bows, looking expectantly at the audience.

"The War!" yells one of the guests. "Tell us about the War! Tell us how the Lords of the Other Realms cast down the Qantari Demons!"

The storyteller straightens again and raises an eyebrow at the man, smiling like a benevolent uncle teaching lessons to a favoured nephew.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>1772</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>1771</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name>none</speaker_name>
      <npc_text>"A hundred tales I could tell you of the Great War and still we would have but scratched the surface! Some sages will tell you that the Old Empire was destined to fall from the day it was born, that the very moment of its ending was written in the stars themselves. That Empires and Kingdoms, like mortal men, grow tall and enjoy their time in the sun for but a brief moment before they too must pass, to make way for those that follow. Thus, sages will tell you that the Qantari kingdom was born for but a single purpose - to be the instrument of fate and bring about the destruction of the Old Empire when the time was right. That by growing stronger, so did we force the Qantari themselves to grow stronger.

For it was their destiny to bring us down, you see, and fate ensured that they were strong enough to do so. That is why the Demons came. Our Legions could hold the savage Qantari at bay but even they couldn't fight fate, couldn't fight the Demons who shrugged off blade and arrow, who slaughtered all that were sent against them, countless lives.

That is why, though Ibn Hadad and his allies came and defeated the demons, the Old Empire could not be saved. The Old Empire had already fallen, for that was always her fate, to die there that day, in blood and fire."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Do you really believe in demons? Do you believe they are the reasons the Empire fell?"</text>
          <def_link>1773</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.NPC_storytellerTeron_demons == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"What can you tell me about the Qantari? Were they really bloodthirsty savages as the stories say?"</text>
          <def_link>1774</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.NPC_storytellerTeron_qantari == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"What can you tell me about these Lords that came with Ibn Hadad?"</text>
          <def_link>1778</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.NPC_storytellerTeron_lords == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>1780</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>1772</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"I can't say no, can I? After all, it's hardly your fault that my gift for storytelling inspires such a thirst for knowledge. Ask your questions, my friend."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Do you really believe in demons? Do you believe they are the reasons the Empire fell?"</text>
          <def_link>1773</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.NPC_storytellerTeron_demons == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"What can you tell me about the Qantari? Were they really bloodthirsty savages as the stories say?"</text>
          <def_link>1774</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.NPC_storytellerTeron_qantari == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"What can you tell me about these Lords that came with Ibn Hadad?"</text>
          <def_link>1778</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.NPC_storytellerTeron_lords == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>1780</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>1783</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The storyteller smiles at your question, turning to accept a drink the innkeeper brings him. Raising the flagon in salute of his host, he throws his head back and drinks deeply. After a long moment he stops, sighs contentedly, then turns his attention back to you, wiping the foam from his mouth.

"Ah, thirsty work, this. Now, what was it you were asking? Do I believe in the demons that they say the Qantari unleashed on the Old Empire? Well, look around you, my friend!" He waves his hand in a circle, but you sense he isn't simply talking about the inn, that his gesture encompasses the entirety of the fallen Empire.

"What do you see, friend? Ruins! Destruction! The rotting carcass of the greatest Empire ever to grace this world! What mere mortal force could have brought that down? No, the stories must be true, only Demons could have done such a thing!"</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.NPC_storytellerTeron_demons = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"But surely there is more to the story? What about the Qantari themselves? Were they really bloodthirsty savages as the stories say?"</text>
          <def_link>1774</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.NPC_storytellerTeron_qantari == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"What can you tell me about these Lords that came with Ibn Hadad?"</text>
          <def_link>1778</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.NPC_storytellerTeron_lords == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>1780</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>1773</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"Well...all I can tell you is what those stories say, my friend. That they were savages from across the sea, jealous and obsessed with destroying our glorious civilization. What more could you expect from a race that worshipped Demons? Some say that they made pacts with demons to grant their warriors greater strength in battle, breeding them with the beasts of the forest to create half-men, half-animals! I shudder to imagine it!"

And shudder he does, shaking himself with an expression of horror on his face. It's convincing enough that you almost believe it wasn't rehearsed. Almost.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.NPC_storytellerTeron_qantari = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"So, these savages and animal-men, they defeated the might of the Old Empire?"</text>
          <def_link>1775</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>1774</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"Do not dismiss them, my friend! They numbered in the tens of thousands, for all their lack of sophistication, and they brought their Magi and their Demons with them!

As I said, it was their destiny to destroy the Empire, and our destiny to fall. You cannot fight your fate."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[intelligence success]"Fate usually works in subtler ways than sending a fleet of savages, magi, and demons to your shores, does it not?"</text>
          <def_link>1776</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.int &gt;= 8</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Do you really believe in demons? Do you believe they are the reasons the Empire fell?"</text>
          <def_link>1773</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.NPC_storytellerTeron_demons == false &amp;&amp; aod.int &lt; 8</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"What can you tell me about these Lords that came with Ibn Hadad?"</text>
          <def_link>1778</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.NPC_storytellerTeron_lords == false &amp;&amp; aod.int &lt; 8</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>1780</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.int &lt; 8</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>1775</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"Well...I suppose, yes, you are right. But then again, how often does fate bring to a close the story of an Empire such as ours was, unmatched in all the world!"

He raises his voice and flings out his arms at this, looking around to see if anyone appreciates the gesture. But the inn's patrons have gone back to their tables and pay him no more attention. He drops his arms, disappointed, then turns back to you.

"Look, I will give you that the story has some small flaws in it. I recall a most unusual drawing in Lord Gaelius' library, for example. It showed a town being built by slaves. The strange thing about it was, in one corner it showed our builders and architects directing them, holding plans and measuring instruments. But in the other corner...well, there appeared to be Qantari. Builders, like our own, if you can believe that!"</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_storyteller_drawing = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Are you sure it was the Qantari?"</text>
          <def_link>1781</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>1776</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"I am no expert on what the Qantari looked like, certainly, I doubt anyone still living is. But, they certainly matched the stories. Feathers, pelts, the sort of thing you would expect of savages."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"What does it mean, this drawing?"</text>
          <def_link>1782</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>1781</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"How would I know? I'm but a storyteller, my friend. Perhaps it was just some artist's flight of fancy. You know how artists can be. Still, it does make one wonder, doesn't it?"</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"What can you tell me about these Lords that came with Ibn Hadad?"</text>
          <def_link>1778</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.NPC_storytellerTeron_lords == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Do you really believe in demons? Do you believe they are the reasons the Empire fell?"</text>
          <def_link>1773</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.NPC_storytellerTeron_demons == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>1780</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>1782</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"Much has been written on the subject of the High Lords. Too much, I'd say. The accounts contradict each other, the High Lords were here, no they were there, no they did this and that. One even begins to suspect that many of the authors weren't actually present at the events they speak of with such authority! Hah!"</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.NPC_storytellerTeron_lords = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"So, how did they defeat the Qantari then, surely there must be some agreement on that? What did they do that our legions and magi couldn't?"</text>
          <def_link>1779</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>1778</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"On that, the stories are silent. They talk at length on the powers of the High Lords, that Gla'ath the Dreamer could shape reality as easily as you or I run our hands through water, that wherever Bar-Hathor the Flamewalker went, the ground itself burned in his wake and flowed like water. And that Thor-Agoth was known as the Artificer, and he constructed devices such as we can but dream of, terrible engines and alien machines beyond the understanding of mere men.

The stories are unanimous on these details, yes. But of how the High Lords actually defeated the Qantari Demons, I am afraid they are silent. Perhaps only Ibn Hadad, First of the Magi, knew that."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>addLore(1);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"What can you tell me about the Qantari? Were they really bloodthirsty savages as the stories say?"</text>
          <def_link>1774</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.NPC_storytellerTeron_qantari == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Do you really believe in demons? Do you believe they are the reasons the Empire fell?"</text>
          <def_link>1773</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.NPC_storytellerTeron_demons == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>1780</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>1779</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeToThisPart();</string>
        <string>setRtsCam();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>1780</UID>
    </dlgPart>
  </parts>
</dlgData>