<?xml version="1.0"?>
<dlgData xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <conditions>
      <string>aod.pc_background_loremaster</string>
    </conditions>
    <links>
      <int>2900</int>
    </links>
    <dlg_name>TeronThessalos</dlg_name>
    <def_link>2906</def_link>
    <def_speaker_name>Thessalos</def_speaker_name>
    <def_portrait>none</def_portrait>
  </header>
  <parts>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“What do you need here?”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgTeleportTo(160, 163, 0, W);</string>
        <string>useCameraBookmark(TeronThessalos_cam_01);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Nothing."</text>
          <def_link>2905</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2906</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“What do you... Wait, you’re Feng’s apprentice, are you not? Come in, I want to show you something.

“I’m Thessalos, a humble servant of Lord Antidas,” he adds rather arrogantly. “I’m sure you’ve heard of me.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgTeleportTo(160, 163, 0, W);</string>
        <string>useCameraBookmark(TeronThessalos_cam_01);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Follow him.</text>
          <def_link>2901</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2900</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“What do you think?” asks Thessalos gesturing toward the artefacts sitting atop the three pedestals in the middle of the hall. “I had them shipped from Maadoran. Once they decorated a house of a powerful Magi, now they decorate mine,” he says haughtily. “I can already feel the connection.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgTeleportTo(151, 161, 0, NW);</string>
        <string>dlgTeleportTo(151, 162, 0, SW, 2200);</string>
        <string>useCameraBookmark(TeronThessalos_cam_02);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Examine the artefacts.</text>
          <def_link>2902</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.lore &gt;= 4</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>2903</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2901</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>You see a strange, bronze helmet, covered with a layer of thick green corrosion. It looks like the helmets favoured by the murmillo, but lacks any decorations. Strangely, there are some old glass fragments in the visor behind the eye gratings. Whatever it was used for, it wasn’t combat.

Another artefact is a glove with strange protrusions. Like the helmet, the protrusions have rusted through and crumbled off in places, but it appears that they used to hold something.

The last item is an antique orrery – an intricate device that shows the positions and orbits of the celestial bodies. There are some markings on it, but you don’t know how to read them.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“If you’d like us to evaluate your artefacts properly –”</text>
          <def_link>2904</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2902</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[lore success]You see a strange, bronze helmet, covered with a layer of thick green corrosion. It looks like the helmets favoured by the murmillo, but lacks any decorations. Strangely, there are some old glass fragments in the visor behind the eye gratings. Whatever it was used for, it wasn’t combat.

Another artefact is a glove with strange protrusions. Like the helmet, the protrusions have rusted through and crumbled off in places, but it appears that they used to hold something. You recall a drawing of a magus in one of the manuscripts. The gloved hand of the magus was outstretched into a swirling mist. The glove was glowing and had what looked like power tubes filled with the divine breath of the gods loaded in the metal protrusions.

The last item is an antique orrery – an intricate device that shows the positions and orbits of the celestial bodies. You aren’t trained in the art of stargazing, but you know enough to understand the markings on the orrery. You move the planets according to the markings until they align in a straight line.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.quest_TeronThessalos_alignment = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>“If you’d like us to evaluate your artefacts properly –”</text>
          <def_link>2904</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2903</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>“There is no need for that, my good &lt;man/woman&gt;,” says Thessalos, interrupting you. “Their exact nature isn’t as important as their... other values. After all, they are our only connection to the past and that, my friend, is what makes them so desirable for cultured men like myself. Why, if not for our passion, these artefacts would have remained buried in the bowels of the earth, lost for mankind.”</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>2905</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2904</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
        <string>setRtsCam();</string>
        <string>dlgTeleportTo(162, 162, 0, E);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>2905</UID>
    </dlgPart>
  </parts>
</dlgData>