<?xml version="1.0"?>
<dlgData xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <conditions />
    <links />
    <dlg_name>TSQ_Preacher</dlg_name>
    <def_link>2156</def_link>
    <def_speaker_name>Preacher</def_speaker_name>
    <def_portrait>none</def_portrait>
  </header>
  <parts>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>You see a man attempting to preach to a crowd of curious onlookers. He's climbed onto a pile of rocks, the better to make himself heard. Despite that, it doesn't seem to be going well, he is having to shout over the jeering.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_preacher_met = true;</string>
        <string>useCameraBookmark(TSQ_Preacher_cam_01);</string>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_Preacher_Start);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Stay and listen.</text>
          <def_link>2191</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Walk away.</text>
          <def_link>2192</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2156</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"Look around you," he booms, face reddening with frustration. "What more do you need to realize that we're on the wrong path! For thousands of years we've tried to build a better world. For ourselves, for our children! And for thousands of years we've failed! What is left of mankind's great works, our Glorious Empire? Ruins! Rubble! Dust!" For emphasis, he kicks a stone from the pile he stands on and it clatters noisily to the cobblestones, the crowd momentarily hushed by his vehemence.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Stay and listen.</text>
          <def_link>2157</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Walk away.</text>
          <def_link>2161</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2191</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"Open your eyes, all of you! See mankind for what it is! Lost, stumbling through the darkness! A darkness that is our own foolish, wicked natures, blinding us! We have no light to guide us out of our misery, no shepherd to lead us to greener pastures!

"In our arrogance, we built monuments to glorify our own pride, gilded halls of vanity and excess! We believed that our palaces would be eternal, impervious to the tides of time and fate that sweep aside all merely mortal accomplishments. Frail as summer flowers we were, yet we believed ourselves as the mighty lion, golden and proud, the entire world ours to stalk and prey upon!

"In our pride, we forgot our Pact with Heaven! We forgot that the very first kingship came from the Gods! We forgot those same Gods, scorned their power! Worse, we believed ourselves to *be* Gods! We held our Empire to be equal to Heaven itself!

"But we are not the Gods' equals! We are but beggars before the Divine, the lowliest of the low! We must seek their forgiveness; beg them to turn not from us, as they turned away from the corruption of the Old Empire!" The man is gesturing wildly now, eyes burning with zeal. And for a moment more the spell holds, the crowd subdued in the face of his conviction. But only for a moment.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Stay and listen.</text>
          <def_link>2158</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Walk away.</text>
          <def_link>2161</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2157</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"So what would you have us do now, exactly?" someone yells, breaking the spell. "Fancy words are all well and good, but I don't see no Gods coming down to help me till my fields or feed my children!" Laughter ripples through the crowd, and the man deflates slightly. Shaking his head, expression mournful, he points at the naysayer.

"Have you not been listening?! Have you not ears on your head? It is not the Gods' place to serve us! It is up to us to show the Gods that we are willing to serve them faithfully once more!"

"Yes, but how?" Another voice, less derisive this time, the question genuine. "What will bring the Gods' favour again, priest?"</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Stay and listen.</text>
          <def_link>2159</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Walk away.</text>
          <def_link>2161</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2158</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Some in the crowd are leaning forward now, attentive. Seeing his chance, the preacher spreads his arms, chin high and chest puffed out.

"The Gods are waiting! They wait for a sign of our renewed devotion! Discard your false pride, people of Teron! Open your hearts to Heaven, turn away from your false lords and masters! For no man who is not ordained by the Gods is fit to lead, none but those chosen and blessed with the wisdom of Heaven can faithfully guide mankind back into the divine light of righteousness! Only they can deliver us from –"

"You want us to turn on Antidas!" the heckler interrupts him again. "Are you mad, old man? If the guards hear you, you'll be strung up outside the palace for the crows to feast on, and us with you!"</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Stay and listen.</text>
          <def_link>2162</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Pick up a stone and throw it at the preacher.</text>
          <def_link>2160</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Walk away.</text>
          <def_link>2161</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2159</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Your throw misses, but it spurs the crowd to action, soon others are pelting the preacher with stones, dirt, offal. Cursing, he turns to flee, but not before his eyes catch yours. By his expression you know that he won't soon forget your face or actions here.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_preacher_angry = true;</string>
        <string>rwd_reputation(TRN_Preacher_03);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Walk away.</text>
          <def_link>2161</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2160</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END - preacher leaves</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>dlgDeleteCharacter(2105);</string>
        <string>dlgFadeToThisPart();</string>
        <string>setRtsCam();</string>
        <string>aod.tsq_preacher_finished = true;</string>
        <string>PreacherNPCs.hideobjects();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>2161</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeToThisPart();</string>
        <string>setRtsCam();</string>
        <string>dlgTeleportTo(170, 127, 0, N);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>2192</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Opinion is turning on the priest, angry muttering sweeps through the assembly. "And which 'blessed' man would you have lead us? That lunatic Meru? That is your chosen one?"

"Don't mock what you don't understand, foolish one! Lord Meru has seen the light and embraced its wisdom! He is the first of the humble and devoted, guided by the great prophet Nabupolassar himself! The Prophet is the Hand of Heaven in the mortal realm, a living conduit between our world and the Gods themselves! It was the Gods who commanded Nabupolassar to travel to Ganezzar, there to reveal himself to Lord Meru and guide him toward the blessed path!"

"Bah, we've got enough prophets here in Teron, you can't throw a stone without hitting three of them!" The crowd roars its mirth as the preacher's face purples in outrage.

"Laugh then, fools! But you haven't stood in the presence of the divine, as I have! Go to Ganezzar yourselves and hear Lord Meru speak! The hands of the Gods rest upon his shoulder; all who hear him fall to their knees and weep at the joyous redemption he offers!"

"I think we've heard enough, old fool," the heckler again. He spits his contempt at the old man's feet then turns, smirking, and pushes his way out through the crowd. At this, the crowd begins to disperse, grinning and making jokes.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Talk to the preacher.</text>
          <def_link>2163</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Walk away.</text>
          <def_link>2161</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2162</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Sighing, the old man steps down from his makeshift platform, looking you over. "One &lt;man/woman&gt;?" the old man addresses his question at the sky above. "Is this all you give me?"</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFadeToThisPart();</string>
        <string>useCameraBookmark(TSQ_Preacher_cam_02);</string>
        <string>PreacherNPCs.hideobjects();</string>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_Preacher_Talk_PC);</string>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_Preacher_Talk_NPC, 2105);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"What did you expect, preacher? They've heard this story before, a dozen times a week at least."</text>
          <def_link>2164</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[intelligence success]"Discard the pride, brother. Did you not just command us all to put our faith in the Gods? Stay on the path They have set for you and followers will come, in time."</text>
          <def_link>2179</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.int &gt;= 7</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Sorry, it seems that the Gods were too busy to send anyone else."</text>
          <def_link>2175</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2163</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"This story? No, not *this* story! The lies of charlatans, yes, but I bring them the truth of the Gods! I bring them hope, mercy, a chance to rebuild our world. And what do they offer in return? Mockery!"</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Calm down, friend, I didn't mean any offense. I'm genuinely curious; tell me about these Gods of yours."</text>
          <def_link>2165</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Yes, yes, you bring the truth. You and every other doomsayer and back-alley prophet. What makes your story any different?"</text>
          <def_link>2177</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2164</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"If you would learn of the Gods, it would be wise to adopt a more humble attitude. The Gods punish those who are filled with pride and scornful of their wisdom.

"Now, ask your questions."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Who are these Gods you speak of? Where did they come from?"</text>
          <def_link>2166</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Why did the Gods leave? Why haven't we seen them again? If they wish to help us, why did they leave us to starve and struggle?"</text>
          <def_link>2167</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"You spoke of false Lords..."</text>
          <def_link>2168</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Tell me of Lord Meru."</text>
          <def_link>2169</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2165</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"Come from? Child, they were always here. It was we who forgot them. The scheming Magi, in their jealousy, turned men from worship of the true Gods to worshipping themselves. They and their puppet Emperor outlawed the worship of the Gods, blinded the masses with their magic tricks. And so the Gods were forgotten. Until we faced our certain destruction at the hands of the Qantari and their demons, then the Gods chose to show us their mercy. They came to our plane to destroy the demons and shatter the grip of the corruption of the Magi."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.come_from = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Why did the Gods leave? Why haven't we seen them again? If they wish to help us, why did they leave us to starve and struggle?"</text>
          <def_link>2167</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.man_serves_gods == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"You spoke of false Lords..."</text>
          <def_link>2168</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.false_lords == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Tell me of Lord Meru."</text>
          <def_link>2169</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.meru == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[intelligence success]"Do you not realize the consequence of your teachings, preacher? Do you not realize why the people scorn you? You would call them to war."</text>
          <def_link>2171</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.int &gt;= 8 &amp;&amp; aod.false_lords</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"I... your words have given me a lot to think about, preacher. All my life I've seen evidence that the world is hard and cruel, that the powerful get where they are by exploiting the weak. If there is another way... but I can't believe on your word alone. I need to see for myself."</text>
          <def_link>2170</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.man_serves_gods &amp;&amp; aod.false_lords</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2166</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"The Gods do not serve man, it is man who must serve the Gods. They destroyed the Qantari demons as a demonstration of their eternal mercy, but they expect us to take the next step. We must show the Gods that we are ready to serve them once again. We must cast out the false lords and parasites who still seek to turn men from their true purpose. Only once we have shown we are ready will the Gods return to us."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.man_serves_gods = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Who are these Gods you speak of? Where did they come from?"</text>
          <def_link>2166</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.come_from == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"You spoke of false Lords..."</text>
          <def_link>2168</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.false_lords == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Tell me of Lord Meru."</text>
          <def_link>2169</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.meru == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[intelligence success]"Do you not realize the consequence of your teachings, preacher? Do you not realize why the people scorn you? You would call them to war."</text>
          <def_link>2171</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.int &gt;= 8 &amp;&amp; aod.false_lords</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"I... your words have given me a lot to think about, preacher. All my life I've seen evidence that the world is hard and cruel, that the powerful get where they are by exploiting the weak. If there is another way... but I can't believe on your word alone. I need to see for myself."</text>
          <def_link>2170</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.man_serves_gods &amp;&amp; aod.false_lords</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2167</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"The Magi may be dead, but the corruption they created lives on. Greedy men, hearts closed to the wisdom of Heaven, still seek to rule us. They squabble over power and riches, and sneer at the servants of the True Gods! Their corruption is what prevents the faithful from building a new world, a paradise where all are safe, content, well-fed. Only one, Lord Meru, has seen the light, rejected the old ways, and devoted himself to the true path."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.false_lords = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Who are these Gods you speak of? Where did they come from?"</text>
          <def_link>2166</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.come_from == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Why did the Gods leave? Why haven't we seen them again? If they wish to help us, why did they leave us to starve and struggle?"</text>
          <def_link>2167</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.man_serves_gods == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Tell me of Lord Meru."</text>
          <def_link>2169</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.meru == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[intelligence success]"Do you not realize the consequence of your teachings, preacher? Do you not realize why the people scorn you? You would call them to war."</text>
          <def_link>2171</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.int &gt;= 8 &amp;&amp; aod.false_lords</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"I... your words have given me a lot to think about, preacher. All my life I've seen evidence that the world is hard and cruel, that the powerful get where they are by exploiting the weak. If there is another way... but I can't believe on your word alone. I need to see for myself."</text>
          <def_link>2170</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.man_serves_gods &amp;&amp; aod.false_lords</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2168</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"Lord Meru is the best hope for our world to be led back into the light of the Gods! Though a scion of the house responsible for nearly destroying our world through their corrupt, irresponsible magics, he overcame that legacy and found his way to true grace! He alone of those who call themselves ‘lord' heeded the wisdom of Holy Nabupolassar. He alone sees the path out of the darkness that greedy nobles and cruel warlords have led us into. He alone seeks to honour the Gods before personal power or coin. The faithful flock to his side and together we will see the Gods' wisdom and justice encompass the whole world!"

Fervour gleams in the preacher's eyes and it's clear that he is barely aware of the world around him now, lost in these visions of the future.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.meru = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Who are these Gods you speak of? Where did they come from?"</text>
          <def_link>2166</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.come_from == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Why did the Gods leave? Why haven't we seen them again? If they wish to help us, why did they leave us to starve and struggle?"</text>
          <def_link>2167</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.man_serves_gods == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"You spoke of false Lords..."</text>
          <def_link>2168</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.false_lords == false</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[intelligence success]"Do you not realize the consequence of your teachings, preacher? Do you not realize why the people scorn you? You would call them to war."</text>
          <def_link>2171</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.int &gt;= 8 &amp;&amp; aod.false_lords</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"I... your words have given me a lot to think about, preacher. All my life I've seen evidence that the world is hard and cruel, that the powerful get where they are by exploiting the weak. If there is another way... but I can't believe on your word alone. I need to see for myself."</text>
          <def_link>2170</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.man_serves_gods &amp;&amp; aod.false_lords</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2169</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"I understand, child. I too had trouble believing, until I heard the words of Holy Nabupolassar, witnessed for myself the fruits of Lord Meru's wisdom and justice.

"Travel to Ganezzar. See for yourself. I am soon to return to the holy city myself, find me there when you have the answers you seek."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_preacher_student = true;</string>
        <string>rwd_reputation(TRN_Preacher_04);</string>
        <string>aod.ending_npc_preacher_01 = true;</string>
        <string>aod.ending_sidequest = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Walk away.</text>
          <def_link>2161</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2170</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"War? Nonsense! I seek to bring them the light and peace of the Gods! Their lives are filled with suffering and toil, if they would join with Lord Meru –"</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"It would mean war. Think, preacher. Do you think Antidas or Gaelius would stand idly by while their people flock to serve House Crassus? They would see it as a threat to themselves and march to war against Lord Meru and his pet prophet. They might even form an alliance against the mutual foe."</text>
          <def_link>2172</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2171</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The preacher's mouth opens to deny your argument, but the words don't seem to come. Frowning, all he can manage is a feeble protest.

"The Gods wouldn't allow it to come to war. No, surely not, their path is the way of peace."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[persuasion]"Just as they didn't allow it to come to war when the Empire fell? Perhaps, a war is part of their plan. Perhaps, the lives of mere mortals aren't all that important to the Gods' plans."</text>
          <def_link>2173</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.persuasion &gt;= 4</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>2174</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2172</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[failure]"The Empire fell because humanity turned their backs on the Gods. It will not come to war if we truly devote ourselves to the Gods' will, they will see to it that their faithful are protected!

"You, you are seeking to draw me from the path of the righteous with your doubting words. Begone, I do not wish to speak to you anymore."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_preacher_angry = true;</string>
        <string>rwd_reputation(TRN_Preacher_03);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Walk away.</text>
          <def_link>2161</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2173</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[success]"They... I... surely not? Holy Nabupolassar teaches that the faithful will receive peace and prosperity, that the Gods wish to heal the world of its scars, not inflict new ones. Surely the Gods' would not lead us into more war, more death?

"I must think on this. Please, leave me."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_preacher_cast_doubt = true;</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Walk away.</text>
          <def_link>2161</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2174</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The man's face darkens and his mouth tightens in anger.

"If you stayed behind simply to mock me one last time, know that your day will come, when you stand before the Gods' judgement!"</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Calm down friend, I didn't mean any offense. I'm genuinely curious; tell me about these Gods of yours."</text>
          <def_link>2165</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"I don't fear the judgement of your imaginary gods, old fool."</text>
          <def_link>2176</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2175</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The preacher glares at you for a moment, before turning and walking away, rigid with fury.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_preacher_angry = true;</string>
        <string>rwd_reputation(TRN_Preacher_03);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Walk away.</text>
          <def_link>2161</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2176</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"Would a charlatan's story have convinced Lord Meru? Do you not think a Lord has a dozen cunning men whispering in his ears, day and night? Do you think such a man would be convinced by a mere trickster? And yet Lord Meru now devotes his life and his house to the Divine Wisdom revealed to him by the Prophet Nabupolassar! Is that not proof of the power of the Gods' message?"</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Well... there may be something to your story. Or perhaps Lord Meru is mad, as they say. I don't know."</text>
          <def_link>2178</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2177</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"Then ask your questions. Ask, and I shall speak of the revealed wisdom of Prophet Nabupolassar, as best I recall it. And perhaps you will find the truth you seek."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Who are these Gods you speak of? Where did they come from?"</text>
          <def_link>2166</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Why did the Gods leave? Why haven't we seen them again? If they wish to help us, why did they leave us to starve and struggle?"</text>
          <def_link>2167</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"You spoke of false Lords..."</text>
          <def_link>2168</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Tell me of Lord Meru."</text>
          <def_link>2169</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2178</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"You have the right attitude, child. Those who humble themselves before the Gods will be exalted by them, all the riches of Heaven will be theirs. Now, what is it you wish to know?"</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Who are these Gods you speak of? Where did they come from?"</text>
          <def_link>2166</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Why did the Gods leave? Why haven't we seen them again? If they wish to help us, why did they leave us to starve and struggle?"</text>
          <def_link>2167</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"You spoke of false Lords..."</text>
          <def_link>2168</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Tell me of Lord Meru."</text>
          <def_link>2169</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2182</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The preacher looks startled. Grimacing, he lifts his hands in apology.

"I... yes. You are right, of course. Forgive me, it has been a long, tiring day and I've received nothing but scorn for my efforts. I forgot myself. A momentary lapse, no more."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"And it is exactly when we are weak and times are hard, that we must be most vigilant with our thoughts. The Gods watch us, test us, always."</text>
          <def_link>2180</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2179</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The preacher's mouth is gaping now, his eyes wide with surprise. He is clearly not used to being on the receiving end of a sermon and seems at a loss as to how to respond. Eventually, he manages a question.

"Who... who are you?"</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"My name is &lt;charname&gt;. Until now, I hadn't realized that I'd been searching for something, some meaning in life. Until I heard you speaking here, about the Gods, that is. I want to learn, brother. I want to know what the Gods want me to do with my life."</text>
          <def_link>2182</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[streetwise success]"I am no one important. Just a traveller on the path, much like yourself. A more important question is: Who sent me?"</text>
          <def_link>2181</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear>aod.streetwise &gt;= 3</checkOnAppear>
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2180</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>At your words, the preacher's face spasms in fear and his body tenses. His gaze darts around wildly, as if expecting attackers to leap out around him.

"Did Antidas send you? He wants to silence my message, is that it?!?"

His tone is half terror, half accusation. By the violence of his reaction, you'd say this wouldn't be the first time he'd had a visit from authority.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"Brother! Look at yourself! The mere thought of Antidas' guards and you're reduced to a shivering wreck! Has your faith deserted you? Are your words but hollow shells?"</text>
          <def_link>2183</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2181</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Your stern words seem to reach the man, he stills and looks at you, though his eyes are still wide.

"If not Antidas, then who sent you?"</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[streetwise]"Why, the same ones who set you on your path, brother. Can you not feel their hands guiding us to this place, to this meeting? It was meant to be!"</text>
          <def_link>2184</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.streetwise &gt;= 4</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>2185</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2183</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[failure]"Bah, you think your honeyed words fool me, but you cannot fool a true servant of the Gods. I've met your kind before. You think that you're clever, but one day you will have to face the Gods in judgement. Before them your petty deceits and manipulations will mean nothing. Good day to you."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_preacher_angry = true;</string>
        <string>rwd_reputation(TRN_Preacher_03);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Walk away.</text>
          <def_link>2161</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2184</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[success]Your words take a moment to sink in, he stares at you in confusion before comprehension dawns. It is swiftly followed by a look of disbelief.

"You think the Gods sent *you* to *me*?"</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[persuasion]"You don't believe me? You, who commanded us to believe that the Gods guide our paths?"</text>
          <def_link>2186</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.persuasion &gt;= 4</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>2187</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2185</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[failure]"They do. But they also test us, place pleasing deceptions in our paths to see if we stray. I want to believe your words, but they ring false in my heart. Whatever you have planned, I wish no part in it."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Walk away.</text>
          <def_link>2161</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2186</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[success]The man licks his lips, uncertain. He is clearly struggling to keep up with the unexpected turns this conversation keeps taking.

"Yes, of course you must have faith in the Gods' wisdom. But... how do I know you were really sen –"</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[charisma]Convince him.</text>
          <def_link>2188</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.cha &gt;= 9</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>2189</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2187</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[failure]You tell the preacher that you have much to offer, that you have skills, contacts, influence. You tell him how much you can do for the Gods' cause and try to convince him that that's why they sent you to the preacher. You even tell him that you saw his face in your dreams, but it fails to move him.

"You speak of contacts and influence," says the preacher grimly. "These are the tools of those who oppress humanity, of Antidas and his ilk. The Gods care not for such earthly matters, the church has no need for your ‘skills', the truth of the Gods will take seed in righteous hearts without your ‘contacts'. Be away with you."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Walk away.</text>
          <def_link>2161</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2188</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>[success]"Brother," you interrupt him, smiling gently and putting a hand on his arm. "I can see you're still struggling with the demons of uncertainty. It is difficult, I know, even for a holy man such as yourself to put aside doubt. But you must trust that They have a plan."

The preacher straightens as you recognize his holiness, a little honey can win over even the wary heart. You continue, your voice low and soothing.

"Do you not see how perfect their plan is? That we were both guided here, to a place so desperately in need of the Gods' guidance, to work together to achieve their plans.

"Rejoice, brother, for the Gods have chosen you to play a major role in those plans. We will bring this land into the Light! Together!"

The startled look has returned to the preacher's face, but with it is a new emotion. Awe. You can see the thought worming its way into his heart, the idea that he has been Chosen for a Special Task. He is yours, now.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>aod.npc_preacher_yours = true;</string>
        <string>rwd_reputation(TRN_Preacher_01);</string>
        <string>dlgAddRank(35);</string>
        <string>aod.pc_reputation_theChosenOne = true;</string>
        <string>setAchievement("ACH_CHOSEN_ONE");</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>"We must unify the efforts of the faithful, brother. Go to Maadoran and Ganezzar. Tell them that the will of the Gods is about to be worked upon Teron. Tell them to stand ready to render assistance. The Gods have other tasks for me here, tell them I will bring word when the time is right. Go now!"</text>
          <def_link>2190</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2189</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>"Lead, &lt;brother/sister&gt;, and I'll follow. I will return to the holy city of Ganezzar without delay and prepare the faithful for your arrival."</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>rwd_reputation(TRN_Preacher_02);</string>
        <string>aod.ending_npc_preacher_02 = true;</string>
        <string>aod.ending_sidequest = true;</string>
        <string>rwd_civil(ChosenOne_01);</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Bless him and walk away.</text>
          <def_link>2161</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2190</UID>
    </dlgPart>
  </parts>
</dlgData>