<?xml version="1.0"?>
<dlgData xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <conditions />
    <links />
    <dlg_name>ZGT_tablets_01</dlg_name>
    <def_link>0</def_link>
    <def_speaker_name>None</def_speaker_name>
    <def_portrait>None</def_portrait>
  </header>
  <parts>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>You’re standing in front of the glowing stone tablets floating in the air with no visible support. Each tablet is carved with rows upon rows of tiny, precise symbols.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Examine the tablets.</text>
          <def_link>1</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>0</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>You take a few steps forward and touch the closest tablet. They are not made of stone but a much lighter material, and the letters seem to have been burned into the surface rather than inscribed.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgTeleportToMarker(TM_Vault_02);</string>
        <string>dlgFadeToThisPart();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>[lore]Decipher the text.</text>
          <def_link>2</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick>
            <string>aod.lore &gt;= 7</string>
            <string>aod.lore &gt;= 5</string>
          </checksOnClick>
          <linksOnClick>
            <int>4</int>
            <int>3</int>
          </linksOnClick>
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>1</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The tablets are written in cuneiform – a writing system so old that its origins are lost in the mists of time. They say that the Magi had gained much insight deciphering tablets that were old when the Empire was barely a kingdom and eventually adopted the script as their own.

Sadly, that’s all you know.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>8</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>2</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The tablets are written in cuneiform – a writing system so old that its origins are lost in the mists of time. They say that the Magi had gained much insight deciphering tablets that were old when the Empire was barely a kingdom and eventually adopted the script as their own.

The tablets are written by the Magi who were assigned to Agathoth – his handlers and jailers – but eventually turned against their own Order for reasons you can't quite understand.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>8</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>3</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>The tablets are written in cuneiform – a writing system so old that its origins are lost in the mists of time. They say that the Magi had gained much insight deciphering tablets that were old when the Empire was barely a kingdom and eventually adopted the script as their own.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Read the parts you do understand.</text>
          <def_link>5</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>4</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Take heed and bear witness to the truths written herein, for they are the last legacy of the Magi. Know ye that we who were the masters became the acolytes. Know ye that we turned against our own order and in so doing have destroyed it. Though we undertook this task with heavy hearts, no price is too great in the service of God.

When the great demon Balzaar broke free, the one we named Agathoth opposed him. As a reward for this act of loyalty, a great ziggurat was built, a mighty structure which served both as his temple and his prison. Within this temple he built wondrous engines of destruction and power, and taught us the knowledge of the stars. In that same temple, the most learned of the Magi monitored Agathoth day and night, distrustful of his motivations, watchful should he betray us.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>7</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>5</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>This was our mistake, that in our boundless arrogance we believed we had created Gods, when we merely made flesh that which was divine. The Qantari worshipped them as Gods long before we created the bridge between our planes. They kneeled before Balzaar and his lesser brethren and followed them to battle without hesitation.

When Balzaar’s fury tore the land asunder and left smoldering ruin in its wake, it was Agathoth's knowledge and weapons that turned the tide. Without Agathoth's divine mercy we would have been destroyed, our own armies no better than straw figures in a firestorm.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Continue.</text>
          <def_link>6</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>7</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>Imagine our horror when we were told that our watch was at an end, and instructed to reverse the ritual, to discard the divine essence like refuse. In response to this outrage we sent envoys to protest to the First of the Magi. These men were put in chains, and he in turn sent soldiers, coarse men who called us enthralled, who compared us to slaves. We took the only path left to us, to lay Agathoth in a tomb carefully warded against the machines employed against his kind, a place he may rest in safety.

This is the truth of this great era and the difficult decisions we faced. When the time is right, when some future generation receives our wisdom, they will awaken the God once more and welcome him into the world that is rightfully His to rule.</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts />
      <answers>
        <dlgAnsw>
          <text>Leave.</text>
          <def_link>8</def_link>
          <checkOnAppear />
          <checksOnClick />
          <linksOnClick />
          <scriptsOnClick />
        </dlgAnsw>
      </answers>
      <UID>6</UID>
    </dlgPart>
    <dlgPart>
      <portrait />
      <speaker_name />
      <npc_text>END</npc_text>
      <onLoadScripts>
        <string>dlgFinish();</string>
        <string>dlgFadeShortToThisPart();</string>
      </onLoadScripts>
      <answers />
      <UID>8</UID>
    </dlgPart>
  </parts>
</dlgData>